{
    "questionList": {
        "tr": [
            {
                "questionId": 0,
                "questionText": "ROM a\u00e7\u0131l\u0131m\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Read Only Memory",
                "choice2": "Random Only Memory",
                "choice3": "Reach Access Memory",
                "choice4": "Redirect Adaqute Memory",
                "rightAnswer": "Read Only Memory",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Bili\u015fim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 1,
                "questionText": "\u00dc\u00e7\u00fcnc\u00fc Ahmed d\u00f6neminde Mimar \u0130brahim Efendi'nin bulu\u015fu olan ''Tahtelbahir'' a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Yelkenli",
                "choice2": "Kad\u0131rga",
                "choice3": "Denizalt\u0131",
                "choice4": "Mavna",
                "rightAnswer": "Denizalt\u0131",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Bilim-Teknik",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 2,
                "questionText": "Eski Yunan'l\u0131 d\u00fc\u015f\u00fcn\u00fcr Platon'a Arap d\u00fcnyas\u0131nda verilen ad nedir?",
                "choice1": "Sokrates",
                "choice2": "Eflatun",
                "choice3": "Aristotales",
                "choice4": "Farabi",
                "rightAnswer": "Eflatun",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Felsefe",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 3,
                "questionText": "Tonyukuk,K\u00fcl Tigin ve Bilge Ka\u011fan yaz\u0131tlar\u0131n\u0131n da i\u00e7inde bulundu\u011fu,\u00fczerinde T\u00fcrk\u00e7e metinler olan an\u0131t\u0131n ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Elege\u015f Yaz\u0131tlar\u0131",
                "choice2": "Uygur Yaz\u0131tlar\u0131",
                "choice3": "Orhun Yaz\u0131tlar\u0131",
                "choice4": "K\u00fcl Tigin Yaz\u0131tlar\u0131",
                "rightAnswer": "Orhun Yaz\u0131tlar\u0131",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Tarih",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 4,
                "questionText": "Salih Memecan'\u0131n \u00e7izdi\u011fi,uzun s\u00fcre ATV haber b\u00fcltenlerinde yer alan ve g\u00fcncel olaylar\u0131 Vah\u015fi Bat\u0131'ya uyarlayan \u00e7izgi dizi hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "G\u00fcng\u00f6rm\u00fc\u015fler",
                "choice2": "Limon",
                "choice3": "Bizim City",
                "choice4": "Bay Yanl\u0131\u015f",
                "rightAnswer": "Bizim City",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "TV",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 5,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi ressam de\u011fildir?",
                "choice1": "Monet",
                "choice2": "Collina",
                "choice3": "Leonardo Da Vinci",
                "choice4": "Rafael",
                "rightAnswer": "Collina",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sanat",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 6,
                "questionText": "Catherine Zeta-Jones'un ilk uluslararas\u0131 ba\u015far\u0131s\u0131n\u0131 yakalad\u0131\u011f\u0131,Antonio Banderas ve Anthony Hopkins ile birlikte rol ald\u0131\u011f\u0131 filmin ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Zorro",
                "choice2": "Trafik",
                "choice3": "\u00d6ld\u00fcren Cazibe",
                "choice4": "Chicago",
                "rightAnswer": "Zorro",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Film",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 7,
                "questionText": "'A\u011fr\u0131 Da\u011f\u0131'',''Alyazmal\u0131m'' ve ''\u00c7i\u00e7ek Abbas'' gibi \u00fcnl\u00fc T\u00fcrk filmlerinin m\u00fczikleri kime aittir?",
                "choice1": "Z\u00fclf\u00fc Livaneli",
                "choice2": "Melih Kibar",
                "choice3": "Erkan O\u011fur",
                "choice4": "Cahit Berkay",
                "rightAnswer": "Cahit Berkay",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Sanat",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 8,
                "questionText": "'Bir Kad\u0131n\u0131n Portresi'',''Moulin Rouge'' ve ''Saatler'' adl\u0131 filmlerde oynam\u0131\u015f,\u00fc\u00e7 Golden Globe ve bir Oscar sahibi Avustralyal\u0131 \u00fcnl\u00fc sinema oyuncusu kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Sandra Bullock",
                "choice2": "Julia Roberts",
                "choice3": "Nicole Kidman",
                "choice4": "Catherine Zeta Jones",
                "rightAnswer": "Nicole Kidman",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Film",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 9,
                "questionText": "T\u00fcrkiye Cumhuriyeti'nin ilk k\u00fclt\u00fcr bakan\u0131 kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Mustafa Fehmi",
                "choice2": "Kemal Tengir\u015fek",
                "choice3": "Talat Sait Halman",
                "choice4": "Adnan Ad\u0131var",
                "rightAnswer": "Talat Sait Halman",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 10,
                "questionText": "Bir maddenin s\u0131v\u0131 halden kat\u0131 hale ge\u00e7mesine ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Donma",
                "choice2": "Erime",
                "choice3": "Buharla\u015fma",
                "choice4": "S\u00fcblimle\u015fme",
                "rightAnswer": "Donma",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Bilim ",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 11,
                "questionText": "G\u0131rtlak \u00e7\u0131k\u0131nt\u0131s\u0131na ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Adem Eri\u011fi",
                "choice2": "Adem Kemi\u011fi",
                "choice3": "Adem Yuta\u011f\u0131",
                "choice4": "Adem Elmas\u0131",
                "rightAnswer": "Adem Elmas\u0131",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 12,
                "questionText": "Elementlerin atom numaralar\u0131na ve kimyasal \u00f6zelliklerine g\u00f6re s\u0131ralan\u0131p kategorize edildi\u011fi sistemin ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Atomik Sistem",
                "choice2": "Periyodik Cetvel",
                "choice3": "Gruplama Cetveli",
                "choice4": "Atomik Periyot",
                "rightAnswer": "Periyodik Cetvel",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 13,
                "questionText": "Elektirik i\u00e7 tesisat kablolar\u0131nda kullan\u0131lan element hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Al\u00fcminyum",
                "choice2": "Civa",
                "choice3": "Bak\u0131r",
                "choice4": "G\u00fcm\u00fc\u015f",
                "rightAnswer": "Bak\u0131r",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 14,
                "questionText": "Is\u0131 enerjisi ile kinetik enerji aras\u0131ndaki ilgileri ve bu konuyla ilgili olaylar\u0131 inceleyen fizik dal\u0131na ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Termodinamik",
                "choice2": "Termostatik",
                "choice3": "Termomekanik",
                "choice4": "Termoelektirik",
                "rightAnswer": "Termodinamik",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 15,
                "questionText": "\u0130slam tarihinde Hz. Muhammed (sav)'i g\u00f6rm\u00fc\u015f,konu\u015fmalar\u0131n\u0131 dinlemi\u015f ki\u015filere ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Muhasip",
                "choice2": "Akabe",
                "choice3": "Sahabe",
                "choice4": "Habe\u015fi",
                "rightAnswer": "Sahabe",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Tarih",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 16,
                "questionText": "\u0130nsan y\u00fcz\u00fcn\u00fcn yandan g\u00f6r\u00fcn\u00fc\u015f\u00fcne ne denir?",
                "choice1": "Suret",
                "choice2": "Cephe",
                "choice3": "Kesit",
                "choice4": "Profil",
                "rightAnswer": "Profil",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 17,
                "questionText": "RoRo olarak bilinen ta\u015f\u0131mac\u0131l\u0131k t\u00fcr\u00fc hangisi \u00fczerinde ger\u00e7ekle\u015ftirilir?",
                "choice1": "Karayolu",
                "choice2": "Demir Yolu",
                "choice3": "Deniz Yolu",
                "choice4": "Hava Yolu",
                "rightAnswer": "Deniz Yolu",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 18,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131daki spor bran\u015flar\u0131ndan hangisi bir t\u00fcr k\u0131\u015f sporudur?",
                "choice1": "Kayakl\u0131 Ko\u015fu",
                "choice2": "Dekatlon",
                "choice3": "Squash",
                "choice4": "Jianzi",
                "rightAnswer": "Kayakl\u0131 Ko\u015fu",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 19,
                "questionText": "Futbolda ceza sahas\u0131 i\u00e7inde yer alan k\u00fc\u00e7\u00fck dikd\u00f6rtgenin ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Korner",
                "choice2": "Alt\u0131 Pas",
                "choice3": "Santra",
                "choice4": "Degajman",
                "rightAnswer": "Alt\u0131 Pas",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 20,
                "questionText": "Futbolda topu yava\u015f yava\u015f vurarak ileri g\u00f6t\u00fcrmeye ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Pas",
                "choice2": "Dripling",
                "choice3": "Plonje",
                "choice4": "Verka\u00e7",
                "rightAnswer": "Dripling",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 21,
                "questionText": "Ya\u015fayan efsane Michael Jordan hangi tak\u0131m ile birlikte an\u0131l\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Los Angeles Lakers",
                "choice2": "Detroit Pistons",
                "choice3": "Chicago Bulls",
                "choice4": "Boston Celtics",
                "rightAnswer": "Chicago Bulls",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 22,
                "questionText": "Sumo g\u00fcre\u015finde eri\u015filebilecek en y\u00fcksek mertebe hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Maegashira",
                "choice2": "Yokozuna",
                "choice3": "Ozeki",
                "choice4": "Makushita",
                "rightAnswer": "Yokozuna",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 23,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi ''ilgi uyand\u0131ran'' anlam\u0131na gelen bir s\u00f6zc\u00fckt\u00fcr?",
                "choice1": "Denek",
                "choice2": "Haris",
                "choice3": "Bencil",
                "choice4": "Cazip",
                "rightAnswer": "Cazip",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Kelime",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 24,
                "questionText": "Halk aras\u0131nda ''g\u00f6n\u00fcl ayart\u0131c\u0131,cilveli insanlara'' ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "\u00c7engi",
                "choice2": "Fettan",
                "choice3": "Ferik",
                "choice4": "Koko\u015f",
                "rightAnswer": "Fettan",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Kelime",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 25,
                "questionText": "Western filmlerinde s\u0131k\u00e7a duyulan bir s\u00f6zc\u00fck olan''Amigo'' ne anlama gelir?",
                "choice1": "Karde\u015f",
                "choice2": "Kabaday\u0131",
                "choice3": "Arkada\u015f",
                "choice4": "Kovboy",
                "rightAnswer": "Arkada\u015f",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Kelime",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 26,
                "questionText": "Harekete haz\u0131r,tetikte beklemeye ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Erkete",
                "choice2": "Huylu",
                "choice3": "Aheste",
                "choice4": "Alesta",
                "rightAnswer": "Alesta",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Kelime",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 27,
                "questionText": "AT ya da AET olarak k\u0131saca s\u00f6ylenen Avrupa Ekonomik Toplulu\u011fu'nun a\u00e7\u0131k ve \u00f6zet anlam\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Ortak Pazar",
                "choice2": "Dayan\u0131\u015fma",
                "choice3": "Ticaret",
                "choice4": "Kom\u00fcnikasyon",
                "rightAnswer": "Ortak Pazar",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Bilgi",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 28,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi ortak dili olmayan milletlerden biridir?",
                "choice1": "Almanlar",
                "choice2": "\u0130svi\u00e7reliler",
                "choice3": "\u0130ngilizler",
                "choice4": "Araplar",
                "rightAnswer": "\u0130svi\u00e7reliler",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 29,
                "questionText": "Bir i\u015fyerinin yeniden g\u00f6zden ge\u00e7irerek eskiyen aksam\u0131n de\u011fi\u015ftirilerek d\u00fczeltilmesine,eskiyen teknolojik birimlere \u00e7a\u011fa uygun ara\u00e7larla donatarak yenileme i\u015flemlerinin t\u00fcm\u00fcne ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Erizyon",
                "choice2": "Tamir",
                "choice3": "Tadilat",
                "choice4": "Revizyon",
                "rightAnswer": "Revizyon",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 30,
                "questionText": "D\u00fckkanlarda e\u015fya koymaya mahsus b\u00f6lmeli yere ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Huruf",
                "choice2": "Risale",
                "choice3": "Terek",
                "choice4": "Ni\u015f",
                "rightAnswer": "Terek",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 31,
                "questionText": "Kilim dokuma tezgah\u0131na ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Alatura",
                "choice2": "R\u00fczake",
                "choice3": "Hasabet",
                "choice4": "Istar",
                "rightAnswer": "Istar",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 32,
                "questionText": "Bir kimsenin \u00fcst\u00fcnl\u00fc\u011f\u00fcn\u00fc kay\u0131ts\u0131z \u015farts\u0131z kabul etmek ne demektir?",
                "choice1": "Biat etmek",
                "choice2": "Hicr etmek",
                "choice3": "Miat etmek",
                "choice4": "Zerk etmek",
                "rightAnswer": "Biat etmek",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 33,
                "questionText": "Hangisi bir ''Hababam S\u0131n\u0131f\u0131'' filmi tiplemesi de\u011fildir?",
                "choice1": "G\u00fcd\u00fck Sabri",
                "choice2": "Kel Mahmut",
                "choice3": "Badi Ekrem",
                "choice4": "\u0130nek \u015eaban",
                "rightAnswer": "G\u00fcd\u00fck Sabri",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 34,
                "questionText": "Bir bestenin veya par\u00e7as\u0131n\u0131n canl\u0131,h\u0131zl\u0131 ve ne\u015feli \u00e7al\u0131naca\u011f\u0131n\u0131 ifade eden kelime hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Aliterasyon",
                "choice2": "Allame",
                "choice3": "Allegro",
                "choice4": "\u00c7e\u015fni",
                "rightAnswer": "Allegro",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sanat",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 35,
                "questionText": "Devlet Ana kimin eseridir?",
                "choice1": "Cengiz Aytmatov",
                "choice2": "Turgut \u00d6zakman",
                "choice3": "Kemal Tahir",
                "choice4": "Mehmet Niyazi",
                "rightAnswer": "Kemal Tahir",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Edebiyat",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 36,
                "questionText": "Yeni oynanmaya ba\u015flayan tiyatro oyununun ilk temsiline ne denir?",
                "choice1": "Gala",
                "choice2": "Prima",
                "choice3": "Prova",
                "choice4": "Pr\u00f6miyer",
                "rightAnswer": "Pr\u00f6miyer",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 37,
                "questionText": "Kad\u0131nlar\u0131 ba\u015ftan \u00e7\u0131karan,hi\u00e7bir inanc\u0131 olmayan ac\u0131mas\u0131z bir tip olarak ba\u015fta Moliere olmak \u00fczere pek \u00e7ok sanat\u00e7\u0131ya esin kayna\u011f\u0131 olmu\u015f,\u0130spanyol k\u00f6kenli efsanevi ki\u015fi kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Don Juan",
                "choice2": "Melicarte",
                "choice3": "George Dandin",
                "choice4": "Alceste",
                "rightAnswer": "Don Juan",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 38,
                "questionText": "Bir \u015fiirde dizelerin ilk harflerinin yukar\u0131dan a\u015fa\u011f\u0131ya do\u011fru s\u0131raland\u0131\u011f\u0131nda anlaml\u0131 bir s\u00f6zc\u00fck meydana getirmesine ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Akrosti\u015f",
                "choice2": "Agnostik",
                "choice3": "Akrostik",
                "choice4": "Akrolik",
                "rightAnswer": "Akrosti\u015f",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Edebiyat",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 39,
                "questionText": "Venedikli \u00fcnl\u00fc bir ressam ailenin \u00e7ocu\u011fu olan Bellini hangi Osmanl\u0131 padi\u015fah\u0131n\u0131n g\u00fcn\u00fcm\u00fcze kalan portresini yapm\u0131\u015ft\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Fatih Sultan Mehmet",
                "choice2": "II.Mahmut",
                "choice3": "Yavuz Sultan Selim",
                "choice4": "Kanuni Sultan S\u00fcleyman",
                "rightAnswer": "Fatih Sultan Mehmet",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 40,
                "questionText": "O\u011fuz T\u00fcrkleri'nin destans\u0131 hikayelerinin anlat\u0131c\u0131s\u0131 efsanevi ozan hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Tonyukuk",
                "choice2": "Ozan Orhun",
                "choice3": "Dede Korkut",
                "choice4": "K\u00fcltigin",
                "rightAnswer": "Dede Korkut",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 41,
                "questionText": "Da Vinci \u015eifresi adl\u0131 roman\u0131 hangi \u00fcnl\u00fc yazar yazm\u0131\u015ft\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Dan Brown",
                "choice2": "Stephen King",
                "choice3": "Pavel Kohout",
                "choice4": "Jean Christophe Grange",
                "rightAnswer": "Dan Brown",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 42,
                "questionText": "Geleneksel T\u00fcrk Halk tiyatrosunun en \u00f6nemli seyirliklerinden olan Orta Oyunu'nda kad\u0131n rol\u00fcn\u00fc oynayan erkek oyuncuya ne denir?",
                "choice1": "\u00c7engi",
                "choice2": "Dilber",
                "choice3": "Zenne",
                "choice4": "Acem",
                "rightAnswer": "Zenne",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 43,
                "questionText": "Eski Ye\u015fil\u00e7am filmlerinde ''Cilal\u0131 \u0130bo'' karakterini hangi sanat\u00e7\u0131 oynam\u0131\u015ft\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Feridun Karakaya",
                "choice2": "\u0130brahim Tatl\u0131ses",
                "choice3": "Sadri Al\u0131\u015f\u0131k",
                "choice4": "\u0130brahim Karag\u00fclle",
                "rightAnswer": "Feridun Karakaya",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sinema",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 44,
                "questionText": "\u00c7ekilmi\u015f bir filmi sonradan seslendirmeye ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Dubar",
                "choice2": "Dubl\u00f6r",
                "choice3": "Dublaj",
                "choice4": "Telesine",
                "rightAnswer": "Dublaj",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Sinema",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 45,
                "questionText": "Vadideki Zambak,Goriot Baba,Eugenie Grandet gibi tan\u0131nm\u0131\u015f romanlar\u0131 olan \u00fcnl\u00fc realist yazar kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Balzac",
                "choice2": "Tolstoy",
                "choice3": "Gorki",
                "choice4": "Dostoyevski",
                "rightAnswer": "Balzac",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 46,
                "questionText": "Balalayka,hangi \u00fclkenin geleneksel \u00e7alg\u0131lar\u0131ndand\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Hindistan",
                "choice2": "Mo\u011folistan",
                "choice3": "\u0130spanya",
                "choice4": "Rusya",
                "rightAnswer": "Rusya",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 47,
                "questionText": "'Gecenin Tam \u00dc\u00e7\u00fcnde'' \u00fcnl\u00fc \u015fark\u0131lar\u0131ndan biriyle tan\u0131nan besteci ve yorumcu kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Fikret K\u0131z\u0131lok",
                "choice2": "Mazhar Alanson",
                "choice3": "B\u00fclent Orta\u00e7gil",
                "choice4": "\u0130lhan \u015ee\u015fen",
                "rightAnswer": "Fikret K\u0131z\u0131lok",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 48,
                "questionText": "Unutulan Nigar makam\u0131n\u0131 d\u00fczenleyerek ''Suzidilara'' ad\u0131nda bir makam yaratan,neyzen Osmanl\u0131 padi\u015fah\u0131 kimdir?",
                "choice1": "III.Mustafa",
                "choice2": "III.Ahmet",
                "choice3": "III.Selim",
                "choice4": "III.Mehmet",
                "rightAnswer": "III.Selim",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 49,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi kabuklu hayvanlar s\u0131n\u0131f\u0131na girer?",
                "choice1": "Y\u0131lan",
                "choice2": "Yenge\u00e7",
                "choice3": "Ku\u015f",
                "choice4": "K\u00f6pek",
                "rightAnswer": "Yenge\u00e7",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 50,
                "questionText": "Kimyasal tepkimelerde tepkimeyi h\u0131zland\u0131ran fakt\u00f6re ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Motoriz\u00f6r",
                "choice2": "Kataliz\u00f6r",
                "choice3": "Fakt\u00f6riz\u00f6r",
                "choice4": "Mobiliz\u00f6r",
                "rightAnswer": "Kataliz\u00f6r",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 51,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi mikroskop cam\u0131d\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Buzlu",
                "choice2": "Mikral",
                "choice3": "Lamel",
                "choice4": "Mikro",
                "rightAnswer": "Lamel",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 52,
                "questionText": "Suyun kald\u0131rma kuvvetini bulan bilim adam\u0131 kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Einstein",
                "choice2": "Loewenhook",
                "choice3": "Newton",
                "choice4": "Ar\u015fimet",
                "rightAnswer": "Ar\u015fimet",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 53,
                "questionText": "Taksonomide a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi en tepede kal\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "S\u0131n\u0131f",
                "choice2": "Filum",
                "choice3": "Alem",
                "choice4": "Familya",
                "rightAnswer": "Alem",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 54,
                "questionText": "Ku\u015flar d\u00fcnyas\u0131n\u0131 inceleyen billim dal\u0131 a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Ornitoloji",
                "choice2": "Mikoloji",
                "choice3": "\u0130htiyoloji",
                "choice4": "Entomoloji",
                "rightAnswer": "Ornitoloji",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 55,
                "questionText": "Elektrik devrelerinde direnci art\u0131r\u0131p azaltmaya yarayan s\u00fcrg\u00fcl\u00fc devre eleman\u0131n\u0131n ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Kondansat\u00f6r",
                "choice2": "Reosta",
                "choice3": "Bobin",
                "choice4": "Transformat\u00f6r",
                "rightAnswer": "Reosta",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 56,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi ''su terapisi''anlam\u0131na gelir?",
                "choice1": "Hidroloji",
                "choice2": "Suyani",
                "choice3": "Su \u00fcr\u00fcnleri",
                "choice4": "Hidroterapi",
                "rightAnswer": "Hidroterapi",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 57,
                "questionText": "Tahta \u00e7ubuklar ya da kibrit \u00e7\u00f6pleriye oynanan gelenksel Japon oyunu a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Go",
                "choice2": "Mikado",
                "choice3": "Dama",
                "choice4": "Dangram",
                "rightAnswer": "Mikado",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 58,
                "questionText": "Argoda bir kimsenin emek vermeden sa\u011flad\u0131\u011f\u0131 kazanca ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Avans",
                "choice2": "Cukka",
                "choice3": "Avanta",
                "choice4": "Zula",
                "rightAnswer": "Avanta",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 59,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden spor bran\u015flar\u0131ndan hangisi atletizmin bir dal\u0131 de\u011fildir?",
                "choice1": "G\u00fclle atma",
                "choice2": "Rounders",
                "choice3": "Disk atma",
                "choice4": "Cirit atma",
                "rightAnswer": "Rounders",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 60,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131daki spor bran\u015flar\u0131ndan hangisi jimnasti\u011fin bir dal\u0131 de\u011fildir?",
                "choice1": "Squash",
                "choice2": "Trambolin",
                "choice3": "Barfiks",
                "choice4": "Yer hareketleri",
                "rightAnswer": "Squash",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 61,
                "questionText": "1996 Avrupa futbol \u015fampiyonas\u0131nda gole giden rakibine faul yapmay\u0131p Fair Play \u00f6d\u00fcl\u00fc alan milli futbolcumuz kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Tayfur Havut\u00e7u",
                "choice2": "Alpay \u00d6zalan",
                "choice3": "Abdullah Ercan",
                "choice4": "B\u00fclent Korkmaz",
                "rightAnswer": "Alpay \u00d6zalan",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 62,
                "questionText": "Profesyonel boks ma\u00e7lar\u0131nda her raunt ka\u00e7 dakikad\u0131r?",
                "choice1": 4,
                "choice2": 2,
                "choice3": 3,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 3,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 63,
                "questionText": "Kad\u0131na g\u00f6re e\u015finin  k\u0131z karde\u015fine ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "G\u00f6r\u00fcmce",
                "choice2": "Elti",
                "choice3": "Yenge",
                "choice4": "Bald\u0131z",
                "rightAnswer": "G\u00f6r\u00fcmce",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 64,
                "questionText": "M\u0131knat\u0131sa ba\u015fka ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Demir \u0131s\u0131ran",
                "choice2": "Demiryama",
                "choice3": "Demiryan\u0131",
                "choice4": "Demir kapan",
                "rightAnswer": "Demir kapan",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 65,
                "questionText": "Bir arada ve bir komuta alt\u0131nda bulunan sava\u015f gemilerinin veya u\u00e7aklar\u0131n\u0131n b\u00fct\u00fcn\u00fcne ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Kilo",
                "choice2": "Filo",
                "choice3": "Silo",
                "choice4": "\u0130glo",
                "rightAnswer": "Filo",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 66,
                "questionText": "Sat\u0131n al\u0131na mal ile birlikte bedavaya verilen k\u00fc\u00e7\u00fck hediyelere ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Arma\u011fan",
                "choice2": "\u0130kramiye",
                "choice3": "E\u015fantiyon",
                "choice4": "\u00d6d\u00fcl",
                "rightAnswer": "E\u015fantiyon",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 67,
                "questionText": "Mevlevi dervi\u015flerinin h\u0131rka alt\u0131na giydikleri kolsuz,uzun etekli ve genellikle a\u00e7\u0131k renkli olan entariye ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Etamin",
                "choice2": "Tayy\u00f6r",
                "choice3": "Tennure",
                "choice4": "Semazen",
                "rightAnswer": "Tennure",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 68,
                "questionText": "10.000 metrekarelik y\u00fcz\u00f6l\u00e7\u00fcm\u00fcne ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Dekar",
                "choice2": "Hektar",
                "choice3": "Mil",
                "choice4": "Kilometre",
                "rightAnswer": "Hektar",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 69,
                "questionText": "\u0130nsan v\u00fccudunda hangisi \u00e7ift de\u011fildir?",
                "choice1": "Kromozom",
                "choice2": "Kalp",
                "choice3": "Kulak",
                "choice4": "Akci\u011fer",
                "rightAnswer": "Kalp",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 70,
                "questionText": "Hangisi bir hamur kabartma tozudur?",
                "choice1": "Soya lesitini",
                "choice2": "Ni\u015fasta",
                "choice3": "Sodyumbikarbonat",
                "choice4": "Vanilin",
                "rightAnswer": "Sodyumbikarbonat",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 71,
                "questionText": "Simgesi ''As'' olan,bir\u00e7ok metal cevherinde bulunan metal g\u00f6r\u00fcn\u00fcml\u00fc ve \u015fiddetli bir zehir olan kimyasal elementin ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Osmiyum",
                "choice2": "Potasyum",
                "choice3": "Arsenik",
                "choice4": "Astatin",
                "rightAnswer": "Arsenik",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 72,
                "questionText": "Kapal\u0131 kaplardaki bas\u0131n\u00e7 hangi cihazla \u00f6l\u00e7\u00fcl\u00fcr?",
                "choice1": "\u0130zometre",
                "choice2": "Barometre",
                "choice3": "Manometre",
                "choice4": "Galvanometre",
                "rightAnswer": "Manometre",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 73,
                "questionText": "T\u00fcrk sinemas\u0131nda ''Damat''olarak tan\u0131nan akt\u00f6r a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Kadir \u0130nan\u0131r",
                "choice2": "C\u00fcneyt Ark\u0131n",
                "choice3": "Kemal Sunal",
                "choice4": "Tar\u0131k Akan",
                "rightAnswer": "Tar\u0131k Akan",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 74,
                "questionText": "'Otuzbe\u015f Ya\u015f'' \u015fiiri hangi \u015fairimize aittir?",
                "choice1": "Naz\u0131m Hikmet Ran",
                "choice2": "Necip Faz\u0131l K\u0131sak\u00fcrek",
                "choice3": "Cahit S\u0131tk\u0131 Taranc\u0131",
                "choice4": "Orhan Veli Kan\u0131k",
                "rightAnswer": "Cahit S\u0131tk\u0131 Taranc\u0131",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 75,
                "questionText": "'Saatleri Ayarlama Enstit\u00fcs\u00fc'' ve ''Be\u015f \u015eehir'' kimin eseridir?",
                "choice1": "Yahya Kemal Beyatl\u0131",
                "choice2": "Ahmet Rasim",
                "choice3": "Beh\u00e7et Necatigil",
                "choice4": "Ahmet Hamdi Tanp\u0131nar",
                "rightAnswer": "Ahmet Hamdi Tanp\u0131nar",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 76,
                "questionText": "Bug\u00fcn kullan\u0131lan ba\u011flaman\u0131n ilk hali olarak da bilinen enst\u00fcr\u00fcman hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Divan",
                "choice2": "Cura",
                "choice3": "Tar",
                "choice4": "Kopuz",
                "rightAnswer": "Kopuz",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 77,
                "questionText": "Ah\u015fap ya da metal y\u00fczeyi de\u011fi\u015fik renkte boyad\u0131ktan sonra yer yer kaz\u0131yarak,oyarak resim yapma ve bu kal\u0131plara resim basma sanat\u0131na ne denir?",
                "choice1": "Grafitti",
                "choice2": "Minyat\u00fcr",
                "choice3": "Tezhip",
                "choice4": "Grav\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswer": "Grav\u00fcr",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 78,
                "questionText": "Dilimiz T\u00fcrk\u00e7e i\u00e7in ''Ses Bayra\u011f\u0131m'' diyen \u015fairimiz kimdir?",
                "choice1": "F.H\u00fcsn\u00fc Da\u011flarca",
                "choice2": "Kemalettin Kamu",
                "choice3": "Cahit S\u0131tk\u0131 Taranc\u0131",
                "choice4": "H.Fahri Ozansoy",
                "rightAnswer": "F.H\u00fcsn\u00fc Da\u011flarca",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 79,
                "questionText": "'Kalp Yaras\u0131'',''Sonbahar'',''Samanyolu''gibi eserleriyle tan\u0131nan 1984 y\u0131l\u0131nda vefat eden cumhuriyet d\u00f6neminin \u00fcnl\u00fc kad\u0131n yazar\u0131 kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Kerime Nadir Azrak",
                "choice2": "Peride Celal",
                "choice3": "Halide Edip Ad\u0131var",
                "choice4": "Halide Nusret Zorlutuna",
                "rightAnswer": "Kerime Nadir Azrak",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 80,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131daki filmlerden hangisi en fazla say\u0131da Oscar \u00f6d\u00fcl\u00fc alm\u0131\u015ft\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Bat\u0131 Yakas\u0131 Hikayesi",
                "choice2": "Ben H\u00fcr",
                "choice3": "R\u00fczgar Gibi Ge\u00e7ti",
                "choice4": "Gladyat\u00f6r",
                "rightAnswer": "Ben H\u00fcr",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 81,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi d\u00fcnyaca \u00fcnl\u00fc ''Madame Butterfly'' operas\u0131n\u0131n bestecisidir?",
                "choice1": "Verdi",
                "choice2": "Bach",
                "choice3": "Puccini",
                "choice4": "Bizet",
                "rightAnswer": "Puccini",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 82,
                "questionText": "Osmanl\u0131' da 1718'den 1730'a kadar s\u00fcren d\u00f6neme \u015fair''Lale Devri'' ad\u0131n\u0131 vermi\u015f ve bu adland\u0131rma tarihe ge\u00e7mi\u015ftir.Bu d\u00f6neme Lale Devri ismini veren \u015fair kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Necip Faz\u0131l",
                "choice2": "Yahya Kemal",
                "choice3": "\u015einasi",
                "choice4": "Faruk Nafiz \u00c7aml\u0131bel",
                "rightAnswer": "Yahya Kemal",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 83,
                "questionText": "Pehlivanlar\u0131n ya\u011fl\u0131 g\u00fcre\u015f yaparken giydikleri dar belli me\u015fin pantolona ne denir?",
                "choice1": "Kispet",
                "choice2": "\u015eort",
                "choice3": "Bermuda",
                "choice4": "\u015ealvar",
                "rightAnswer": "Kispet",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 84,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131daki spor bran\u015flar\u0131ndan hangisi bir tak\u0131m oyunudur?",
                "choice1": "Halat \u00e7ekme",
                "choice2": "Kung-Fu",
                "choice3": "Bungee Jumping",
                "choice4": "Kaykay",
                "rightAnswer": "Halat \u00e7ekme",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 85,
                "questionText": "Kayserispor'un forma renkleri a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Ye\u015fil-siyah",
                "choice2": "Sar\u0131-lacivert",
                "choice3": "Sar\u0131-k\u0131rm\u0131z\u0131",
                "choice4": "K\u0131rm\u0131z\u0131-siyah",
                "rightAnswer": "Sar\u0131-k\u0131rm\u0131z\u0131",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 86,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131daki spor bran\u015flar\u0131ndan hangisi bir t\u00fcr k\u0131\u015f sporudur?",
                "choice1": "Heptatlon",
                "choice2": "Kuzey kombine",
                "choice3": "Dekatlon",
                "choice4": "Pentatlon",
                "rightAnswer": "Kuzey kombine",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 87,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi jimnastik sporunun bir dal\u0131d\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Kulplu beygir",
                "choice2": "Buz hokeyi",
                "choice3": "Tenis",
                "choice4": "Jianzi",
                "rightAnswer": "Kulplu Beygir",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 88,
                "questionText": "Kendisine yap\u0131lan iyili\u011fin de\u011ferini bilmeyene ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Nank\u00f6r",
                "choice2": "Tamahkar",
                "choice3": "Pinti",
                "choice4": "Nekes",
                "rightAnswer": "Nank\u00f6r",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 89,
                "questionText": "Bir hizmeti g\u00f6rene hakk\u0131nda ayr\u0131 olarak verilen paraya ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Sadaka",
                "choice2": "Avanta",
                "choice3": "\u00d6denek",
                "choice4": "Bah\u015fi\u015f",
                "rightAnswer": "Bah\u015fi\u015f",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 90,
                "questionText": "\u015eark\u0131 s\u00f6ylemek anlam\u0131na gelen kelime hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Terenn\u00fcm",
                "choice2": "Tarumar",
                "choice3": "Teredd\u00fct",
                "choice4": "M\u00fctereddit",
                "rightAnswer": "Terenn\u00fcm",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 91,
                "questionText": "\u00c7ello hangi \u00e7alg\u0131n\u0131n di\u011fer ad\u0131d\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Viyola",
                "choice2": "Arp",
                "choice3": "Lir",
                "choice4": "Viyolonsel",
                "rightAnswer": "Viyolonsel",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 92,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi ''c\u00f6mertlik''anlam\u0131na gelir?",
                "choice1": "Fetret",
                "choice2": "Riya",
                "choice3": "F\u00fct\u00fcvvet",
                "choice4": "Neyyire",
                "rightAnswer": "F\u00fct\u00fcvvet",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 93,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011fp\u0131dakilerden hangisi bo\u015fanma anlam\u0131na gelir?",
                "choice1": "Salat",
                "choice2": "Talak",
                "choice3": "Rivaye",
                "choice4": "Galat",
                "rightAnswer": "Talak",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 94,
                "questionText": "Hamur durumundaki ekmeklerin,f\u0131r\u0131na at\u0131lmadan \u00f6nce i\u00e7ine konuldu\u011fu oyuk,g\u00f6zl\u00fc tahtaya ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Hatak",
                "choice2": "Ka\u015fkaval",
                "choice3": "K\u0131ra\u00e7a",
                "choice4": "Binit",
                "rightAnswer": "Binit",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 95,
                "questionText": "Kahramanlar\u0131 genellikle hayvan olan anlat\u0131lara ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Fabl",
                "choice2": "Roman",
                "choice3": "Romanesk",
                "choice4": "Destan",
                "rightAnswer": "Fabl",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 96,
                "questionText": "Zamkl\u0131 mat sulu boyaya ve bu boya ile yap\u0131lan resimlere ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Sufle",
                "choice2": "Lome",
                "choice3": "Guaj",
                "choice4": "Sa\u00e7atura",
                "rightAnswer": "Guaj",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 97,
                "questionText": "Ankara'da posta \u00e7ukuruna d\u00fc\u015ft\u00fckten bir hafta sonra vefat eden \u00fcnl\u00fc \u015fairimiz kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Cahit K\u00fclebi",
                "choice2": "Oktay Rifat",
                "choice3": "Orhan Veli",
                "choice4": "Melih Cevdet",
                "rightAnswer": "Orhan Veli",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 98,
                "questionText": "Polonya halk\u0131ndan olan kimselere ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Astrich",
                "choice2": "Leh",
                "choice3": "Bohem",
                "choice4": "Polikarya",
                "rightAnswer": "Leh",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 99,
                "questionText": "D\u0131\u015ftan gelen bir uyar\u0131 sonucunda do\u011fan istem d\u0131\u015f\u0131 geli\u015fen hareket ya da salg\u0131 tepkisine yol a\u00e7an sinirsel etkinli\u011fe ne denir?",
                "choice1": "Otonom",
                "choice2": "Parasempati",
                "choice3": "REFLEKS",
                "choice4": "Lenfatik Tepki",
                "rightAnswer": "Refleks",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 100,
                "questionText": "Guatr hastal\u0131\u011f\u0131na neden olan bez hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Hipofiz",
                "choice2": "Paratiroid",
                "choice3": "Tiroid",
                "choice4": "B\u00f6brek \u00fcst\u00fc",
                "rightAnswer": "Tiroid",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 101,
                "questionText": "Azot elementinin simgesi nedir?",
                "choice1": "Az",
                "choice2": "A",
                "choice3": "N",
                "choice4": "Na",
                "rightAnswer": "N",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 102,
                "questionText": "N\u00f6tron say\u0131s\u0131 farkl\u0131,proton say\u0131s\u0131 ayn\u0131 olan atomlara ne denir?",
                "choice1": "\u0130zobat",
                "choice2": "\u0130zobar",
                "choice3": "\u0130zoton",
                "choice4": "\u0130zotop",
                "rightAnswer": "\u0130zotop",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 103,
                "questionText": "Ac\u0131 tad\u0131 almam\u0131z\u0131 sa\u011flayan papillalar dilin neresinde bulunur?",
                "choice1": "Dilin yan taraf\u0131nda",
                "choice2": "Dilin arkas\u0131nda",
                "choice3": "Dilin ucunda",
                "choice4": "Dilin alt k\u0131sm\u0131nda",
                "rightAnswer": "Dilin arkas\u0131nda",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Bilim",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 104,
                "questionText": "B\u00fcy\u00fck bir i\u015fin bir par\u00e7as\u0131n\u0131 as\u0131l m\u00fcteahhitten alan ikinci m\u00fcteahhite ne denir?",
                "choice1": "Elevat\u00f6r",
                "choice2": "Ta\u015f\u0131y\u0131c\u0131",
                "choice3": "Komisyoner",
                "choice4": "Ta\u015feron",
                "rightAnswer": "Ta\u015feron",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 105,
                "questionText": "Ya\u011fmur suyu biriktirmeye yarayan yer alt\u0131 su deposuna ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Cebel",
                "choice2": "Sarn\u0131\u00e7",
                "choice3": "H\u00f6y\u00fck",
                "choice4": "Fahur",
                "rightAnswer": "Sarn\u0131\u00e7",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 106,
                "questionText": "Yanl\u0131zca ahlak \u00fczerine kurulu y\u00f6netim bi\u00e7imine ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Etokrasi",
                "choice2": "Etkorikse",
                "choice3": "Etr\u00fckseri",
                "choice4": "Etoklasi",
                "rightAnswer": "Etokrasi",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 107,
                "questionText": "'The Bodyguard'' filminde Whitney Houston'la ba\u015frol\u00fc payla\u015fan akt\u00f6r kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Kevin Costner",
                "choice2": "Keanu Reeves",
                "choice3": "Robert Redford",
                "choice4": "Gene Hackman",
                "rightAnswer": "Kevin Costner",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 108,
                "questionText": "En g\u00fc\u00e7l\u00fc kitle ileti\u015fim ara\u00e7lar\u0131ndan biri olan radyo kimin icad\u0131d\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Graham Bell",
                "choice2": "Aleksandr Popov",
                "choice3": "Trevor Bayl\u0131s",
                "choice4": "Guguelmo Marcon\u0131",
                "rightAnswer": "Guguelmo Marcon\u0131",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 109,
                "questionText": "\u00c7ocu\u011fun erken ya\u015flanma hastal\u0131\u011f\u0131na ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Werner",
                "choice2": "Vitiligo",
                "choice3": "Crohn",
                "choice4": "Charcot",
                "rightAnswer": "Werner",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 110,
                "questionText": "'Geni\u015f Zamanlar'' adl\u0131 roman hangi yazar\u0131m\u0131za aittir?",
                "choice1": "Orhan Pamuk",
                "choice2": "Mina Urgan",
                "choice3": "Ya\u015far Kemal",
                "choice4": "Ay\u015fe Kulin",
                "rightAnswer": "Ay\u015fe Kulin",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 111,
                "questionText": "RIAA'n\u0131n Amerikan mahkemelerinde sava\u015ft\u0131\u011f\u0131 bilgisayar program\u0131 hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Sawpro",
                "choice2": "Iconforge",
                "choice3": "Napster",
                "choice4": "Netscape",
                "rightAnswer": "Napster",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 112,
                "questionText": "1982'de g\u00f6sterilen ''Tootsie'' adl\u0131 filmde kad\u0131n k\u0131l\u0131\u011f\u0131na giren \u00fcnl\u00fc akt\u00f6r kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Ben Affleck",
                "choice2": "Tom Cruise",
                "choice3": "Adam Sandler",
                "choice4": "Dustin Hoffman",
                "rightAnswer": "Dustin Hoffman",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 113,
                "questionText": "\u0130nsan\u0131n i\u015fitme sisteminin niteliklerini ve performans\u0131n\u0131 ara\u015ft\u0131ran bilim dal\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Psikoakustik",
                "choice2": "Elektroakustik",
                "choice3": "Rezonans",
                "choice4": "Mikrotonal",
                "rightAnswer": "Psikoakustik",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 114,
                "questionText": "a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi tarihteki T\u00fcrk devletlerinden biri de\u011fildir?",
                "choice1": "Hun \u0130mparatorlu\u011fu",
                "choice2": "Avar Ka\u011fanl\u0131\u011f\u0131",
                "choice3": "Emevi Devleti",
                "choice4": "Sel\u00e7uklu Devleti",
                "rightAnswer": "Emevi Devleti",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Tarih",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 115,
                "questionText": "Galatasaray hangi y\u0131l UEFA kupas\u0131n\u0131 alm\u0131\u015ft\u0131r?",
                "choice1": 2000,
                "choice2": 2001,
                "choice3": 2002,
                "choice4": 2003,
                "rightAnswer": 2000,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Spor",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 116,
                "questionText": "K\u0131br\u0131s Bar\u0131\u015f Harekat\u0131 hangi tarihte ger\u00e7ekle\u015fmi\u015ftir?",
                "choice1": 1970,
                "choice2": 1972,
                "choice3": 1974,
                "choice4": 1975,
                "rightAnswer": 1974,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Tarih",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 117,
                "questionText": "Hangi \u00fclke Asya k\u0131tas\u0131ndad\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Madagaskar",
                "choice2": "Peru",
                "choice3": "Singapur",
                "choice4": "\u015eili",
                "rightAnswer": "Singapur",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 118,
                "questionText": "Kuyucakl\u0131 Yusuf adl\u0131 eser kime aittir?",
                "choice1": "Sabahattin Ali",
                "choice2": "Yusuf At\u0131lgan",
                "choice3": "Ya\u015far Kemal",
                "choice4": "Yahya Kemal Beyatl\u0131",
                "rightAnswer": "Sabahattin Ali",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 119,
                "questionText": "A\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisi Aziz Nesin'in bir eseri de\u011fildir?",
                "choice1": "Gol Kral\u0131",
                "choice2": "Z\u00fcb\u00fck",
                "choice3": "Yer Demir G\u00f6k Bak\u0131r",
                "choice4": "G\u0131d\u0131g\u0131d\u0131",
                "rightAnswer": "Yer Demir G\u00f6k Bak\u0131r",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 120,
                "questionText": "Osmanl\u0131 \u0130mparatorlu\u011fu ka\u00e7 as\u0131r h\u00fck\u00fcm s\u00fcrm\u00fc\u015ft\u00fcr?",
                "choice1": 5,
                "choice2": 6,
                "choice3": 7,
                "choice4": 8,
                "rightAnswer": 6,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 121,
                "questionText": "Fas'\u0131n ba\u015fkenti neresidir?",
                "choice1": "Kazablanka",
                "choice2": "Rabat",
                "choice3": "Kahire",
                "choice4": "Marake\u015f",
                "rightAnswer": "Rabat",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 122,
                "questionText": "\u0130stiklal Mar\u015f\u0131 hangi y\u0131l yaz\u0131lm\u0131\u015ft\u0131r?",
                "choice1": 1919,
                "choice2": 1920,
                "choice3": 1921,
                "choice4": 1922,
                "rightAnswer": 1921,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 123,
                "questionText": "T\u00fcrk Silahl\u0131 Kuvvetleri'nde hangi r\u00fctbe daha y\u00fcksektir?",
                "choice1": "T\u00fcmgeneral",
                "choice2": "Korgeneral",
                "choice3": "Tu\u011fgeneral",
                "choice4": "Mare\u015fal",
                "rightAnswer": "Mare\u015fal",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 124,
                "questionText": "1 metre ka\u00e7 milimetredir?",
                "choice1": 100,
                "choice2": 1000,
                "choice3": 10000,
                "choice4": 100000,
                "rightAnswer": 1000,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 125,
                "questionText": "Hangi sosyal medya platformu daha sonra kurulmu\u015ftur?",
                "choice1": "Twitter",
                "choice2": "Tinder",
                "choice3": "Snapchat",
                "choice4": "Facebook",
                "rightAnswer": "Tinder",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 126,
                "questionText": "Hangisi tarihteki Rus Devlet y\u00f6neticlerinden biridir?",
                "choice1": "Deli Petro",
                "choice2": "Kaz\u0131kl\u0131 Voyvoda",
                "choice3": "Sezar",
                "choice4": "\u0130skender",
                "rightAnswer": "Deli Petro",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 127,
                "questionText": "Mus,misk ve ren hangisinin t\u00fcrleridir?",
                "choice1": "Ay\u0131",
                "choice2": "Ke\u00e7i",
                "choice3": "Geyik",
                "choice4": "Koyun",
                "rightAnswer": "Geyik",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 128,
                "questionText": "Eyvah Eyvah film serisinde Ata Demirer ile ba\u015frol\u00fc payla\u015fan oyuncu kimdir?",
                "choice1": "G\u00fclse Birsel",
                "choice2": "Binnur Kaya",
                "choice3": "Demet Akba\u011f",
                "choice4": "Sumru Yavrucuk",
                "rightAnswer": "Demet Akba\u011f",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 129,
                "questionText": "S\u0131v\u0131lar\u0131 \u00f6l\u00e7mekte kullan\u0131lan 1 desimetrek\u00fcp hacmindeki \u00f6l\u00e7\u00fc birimi hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Gram",
                "choice2": "Litre",
                "choice3": "Ton",
                "choice4": "Kilogram",
                "rightAnswer": "Litre",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 130,
                "questionText": "'Bana \u00f6ld\u00fc demeyin;yoruldu,gitti deyin'' s\u00f6z\u00fc 2012 y\u0131l\u0131nda hayat\u0131n\u0131 kaybeden hangi sanat\u00e7\u0131ya aittir?",
                "choice1": "Ne\u015fet Erta\u015f",
                "choice2": "M\u00fcsl\u00fcm G\u00fcrses",
                "choice3": "Nejat Uygur",
                "choice4": "M\u00fcnir \u00d6zkur",
                "rightAnswer": "Ne\u015fet Erta\u015f",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 131,
                "questionText": "\u0130ngiliz Kraliyet ailesinin ya\u015fad\u0131\u011f\u0131 775 odal\u0131 saray a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Buckingham Saray\u0131",
                "choice2": "Westminister Saray\u0131",
                "choice3": "Versay Saray\u0131",
                "choice4": "Beyaz Saray",
                "rightAnswer": "Buckingham Saray\u0131",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 132,
                "questionText": "Muammer Karaca'n\u0131n T\u00fcrk Tiyatrosuna uyarlad\u0131\u011f\u0131,Nejat Uygur ve Zihni G\u00f6ktay'\u0131n uzun y\u0131llar oynad\u0131\u011f\u0131 oyun hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "L\u00fck\u00fcs Hayat",
                "choice2": "Cibali Karakolu",
                "choice3": "Ke\u015fanl\u0131 Ali Destan\u0131",
                "choice4": "\u0130stanbul Efendisi",
                "rightAnswer": "Cibali Karakolu",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 133,
                "questionText": "Hangi \u00fclkenin y\u00fcz\u00f6l\u00e7\u00fcm\u00fc di\u011ferlerinden fazlad\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "\u0130spanya ",
                "choice2": "Tayland",
                "choice3": "T\u00fcrkmenistan",
                "choice4": "Portekiz",
                "rightAnswer": "Tayland",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 134,
                "questionText": "'Ah nerede''ve''Delisin'' gibi T\u00fcrk filmlerinde ''Ferit'' isimli karakteri canland\u0131ran oyuncu kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Ayhan I\u015f\u0131k",
                "choice2": "Kadir \u0130nan\u0131r",
                "choice3": "Tar\u0131k Akan",
                "choice4": "Halit Ak\u00e7atepe",
                "rightAnswer": "Tar\u0131k Akan",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 135,
                "questionText": "Sinema ve foto\u011fraf\u00e7\u0131l\u0131kta g\u00f6r\u00fcnt\u00fcy\u00fc \u00e7er\u00e7eve i\u00e7ine almaya ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Montaj",
                "choice2": "Metraj",
                "choice3": "Kadraj",
                "choice4": "Fotomontaj",
                "rightAnswer": "Kadraj",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 136,
                "questionText": "'\u00c7ocuk Oyunu'' film serisiyle tan\u0131nan,bir seri katilin ruhunu ta\u015f\u0131yan oyuncak bebe\u011fin ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Freddy",
                "choice2": "Chucky",
                "choice3": "Piggy",
                "choice4": "Bonny",
                "rightAnswer": "Chucky",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 137,
                "questionText": "Charlie'nin Melekleri film serisinde Charlie'nin \u00e7e\u015fitli g\u00f6revler verdi\u011fi melekler ka\u00e7 ki\u015fidir?",
                "choice1": 2,
                "choice2": 3,
                "choice3": 4,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 3,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 138,
                "questionText": "Sessiz ve siyah-beyaz olarak \u00e7ekilen,Oskar \u00f6d\u00fcll\u00fc 2011 yap\u0131m\u0131 film hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "A\u015fk ",
                "choice2": "Umut I\u015f\u0131\u011f\u0131m",
                "choice3": "Artist",
                "choice4": "Yol",
                "rightAnswer": "Artist",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 139,
                "questionText": "Kartal Tibet'in yap\u0131mc\u0131,senarist ve y\u00f6netmenli\u011fin yan\u0131nda oyuncu olarak da yer al\u0131p kendini oynad\u0131\u011f\u0131 tek filmi hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Talih Ku\u015fu",
                "choice2": "Bitirimler Sosyetede",
                "choice3": "\u015eabaniye",
                "choice4": "\u00c7\u00f6p\u00e7\u00fcler Kral\u0131",
                "rightAnswer": "\u015eabaniye",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 140,
                "questionText": "Hangi karde\u015fler ''En iyi y\u00f6netmen oskar \u00f6d\u00fcl\u00fc''kazanm\u0131\u015ft\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Coen karde\u015fler",
                "choice2": "Wachowski karde\u015fler",
                "choice3": "Lumiere karde\u015fler",
                "choice4": "Waldorf Karde\u015fler",
                "rightAnswer": "Coen Karde\u015fler",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 141,
                "questionText": "Osmanl\u0131'da sitil,zarf ve pu\u015fide hangisinin sunumunda kullan\u0131l\u0131rd\u0131?",
                "choice1": "Yemek",
                "choice2": "Kahve",
                "choice3": "Tatl\u0131",
                "choice4": "\u015eerbet",
                "rightAnswer": "Kahve",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 142,
                "questionText": "Ulanbatur ve Karakurum \u015fehirleri hangi \u00fclkededir?",
                "choice1": "T\u00fcrkmenistan",
                "choice2": "Kazakistan",
                "choice3": "Mo\u011folistan",
                "choice4": "K\u0131rg\u0131zistan",
                "rightAnswer": "Mo\u011folistan",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 143,
                "questionText": "T\u00fcrkiye'nin Olimpiyatlardaki ilk alt\u0131n madalyas\u0131n\u0131 kazand\u0131\u011f\u0131 bran\u015f a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Halter",
                "choice2": "G\u00fcre\u015f",
                "choice3": "Atletizm",
                "choice4": "Jimnastik",
                "rightAnswer": "G\u00fcre\u015f",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 144,
                "questionText": "\u00c7arpanak,Ku\u015f ve Ad\u0131r adas\u0131 nerdedir?",
                "choice1": "Van G\u00f6l\u00fc",
                "choice2": "Karadeniz",
                "choice3": "Marmara denizi",
                "choice4": "Ege denizi",
                "rightAnswer": "Van g\u00f6l\u00fc",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 145,
                "questionText": "Eski Roma'da \u00f6zellikle soylulardan olu\u015fan y\u00f6neticiler meclisine ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Agora",
                "choice2": "Senato",
                "choice3": "Akropolis",
                "choice4": "Arena",
                "rightAnswer": "Senato",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 146,
                "questionText": "'Jon Arbuckle'' ve ''Odie'' hangi \u00e7izgi filmde yer alan karakterlerin ad\u0131d\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Garfield",
                "choice2": "Scooby Doo",
                "choice3": "Snoopy",
                "choice4": "Richie Rich",
                "rightAnswer": "Garfield",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 147,
                "questionText": "'Karpuz kabu\u011fu denize d\u00fc\u015ft\u00fc''s\u00f6z\u00fc hangi mevsimin geldi\u011fini haber verir?",
                "choice1": "Yaz",
                "choice2": "K\u0131\u015f",
                "choice3": "\u0130lkbahar",
                "choice4": "Sonbahar",
                "rightAnswer": "Yaz",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 148,
                "questionText": "Garsona do\u011fru el kald\u0131r\u0131p havaya yaz\u0131 yaz\u0131larak istenen \u015fey hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "\u00c7ay",
                "choice2": "Men\u00fc",
                "choice3": "Hesap",
                "choice4": "\u0130nternet \u015eifresi",
                "rightAnswer": "Hesap",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 149,
                "questionText": "A\u011flad\u0131\u011f\u0131n\u0131 gizlemeye \u00e7al\u0131\u015fan ki\u015filer genelde g\u00f6zlerine a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisinin ka\u00e7t\u0131\u011f\u0131n\u0131 iddia eder?",
                "choice1": "Toz",
                "choice2": "Su",
                "choice3": "Deterjan",
                "choice4": "K\u00fcl",
                "rightAnswer": "Toz",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 150,
                "questionText": "Frodo Baggins,Aragorn hangi filmde yer alan karakterlerdir?",
                "choice1": "Alacakaranl\u0131k",
                "choice2": "Y\u00fcz\u00fcklerin Efendisi",
                "choice3": "\u015earlo",
                "choice4": "Hobbit",
                "rightAnswer": "Y\u00fcz\u00fcklerin Efendisi",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 151,
                "questionText": "Macaristan'\u0131n ba\u015fkenti Budape\u015fte'nin i\u00e7inden ge\u00e7en ve \u015fehri Budin ve Pe\u015fte olarak ay\u0131ran nehrin ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Volga ",
                "choice2": "Tuna",
                "choice3": "Ural",
                "choice4": "Nil",
                "rightAnswer": "Tuna",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 152,
                "questionText": "Kesinlik kazanmam\u0131\u015f a\u011f\u0131zdan a\u011f\u0131za dola\u015fan s\u00f6ylenti anlam\u0131na gelen kelime hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Tevecc\u00fcl",
                "choice2": "Tevat\u00fcr",
                "choice3": "Tevell\u00fct",
                "choice4": "Tehecc\u00fct",
                "rightAnswer": "Tevat\u00fcr",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 153,
                "questionText": "'M\u00fc\u015fteri'' ve ''Erendiz'' hangi gezegenin eski ad\u0131d\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Mars",
                "choice2": "Ven\u00fcs",
                "choice3": "J\u00fcpiter",
                "choice4": "Uran\u00fcs",
                "rightAnswer": "J\u00fcpiter",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 154,
                "questionText": "Mozart'\u0131n \u00fcnl\u00fc ''Saraydan K\u0131z Ka\u00e7\u0131rma'' operas\u0131ndan,ka\u00e7\u0131r\u0131lan k\u0131z\u0131n ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Odette",
                "choice2": "Konstanze",
                "choice3": "Violetta",
                "choice4": "Rozenza",
                "rightAnswer": "Konstanze",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 155,
                "questionText": "Fast food restaurantlar\u0131nda sat\u0131lan men\u00fcler genellikle hangisi olur?",
                "choice1": "Hamburger,pizza",
                "choice2": "Nohut,Pilav",
                "choice3": "Kokore\u00e7,Midye",
                "choice4": "Tur\u015fu,Salata",
                "rightAnswer": "Hamburger,Pizza",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 156,
                "questionText": "Antika e\u015fyalar\u0131 satmak amac\u0131yla d\u00fczenlenen organizasyona ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Defile",
                "choice2": "M\u00fczayede",
                "choice3": "M\u00fcsamere",
                "choice4": "M\u00fcnazara",
                "rightAnswer": "M\u00fczayede",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 157,
                "questionText": "Ta\u015f,ka\u011f\u0131t,makas oyunun hangi kural\u0131 yanl\u0131\u015f verilmi\u015ftir?",
                "choice1": "Ta\u015f ka\u011f\u0131d\u0131 y\u0131rtar",
                "choice2": "Makas ka\u011f\u0131d\u0131 keser",
                "choice3": "Ta\u015f makas\u0131 k\u0131rar",
                "choice4": "Ka\u011f\u0131t makas\u0131 kaplar",
                "rightAnswer": "Ta\u015f ka\u011f\u0131d\u0131 y\u0131rtar",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 158,
                "questionText": "\u00c7i\u011f k\u00f6fte yap\u0131l\u0131rken bulgurun \u015fi\u015fmemesi i\u00e7in \u00f6zellikle yaz aylar\u0131nda i\u00e7ine ne konur?",
                "choice1": "Ya\u011f",
                "choice2": "Soda",
                "choice3": "S\u00fct",
                "choice4": "Buz",
                "rightAnswer": "Buz",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 159,
                "questionText": "Un,yumurta,tulum peyniri,tereya\u011f ve cevizi\u00e7inden yap\u0131lan Osmanl\u0131 d\u00f6nemi yeme\u011fine ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Piruhi",
                "choice2": "Nevriyye",
                "choice3": "Pelte\u015fin",
                "choice4": "Mutancana",
                "rightAnswer": "Piruhi",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 160,
                "questionText": "UNESCO'nun merkezi nerededir?",
                "choice1": "Paris",
                "choice2": "New York ",
                "choice3": "Cenevre",
                "choice4": "Londra",
                "rightAnswer": "Paris",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 161,
                "questionText": "Ma\u00e7 s\u0131ras\u0131nda en kalabal\u0131k oyuncu say\u0131s\u0131 hangi bran\u015ftad\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Voleybol",
                "choice2": "Basketbol",
                "choice3": "Futbol",
                "choice4": "Hentbol",
                "rightAnswer": "Futbol",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 162,
                "questionText": "Ye\u015fil\u00e7am'\u0131n ''\u00c7irkin Kral'' lakapl\u0131 oyuncusunun ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Tar\u0131k Akan",
                "choice2": "Y\u0131lmaz G\u00fcney",
                "choice3": "Ediz Hun",
                "choice4": "Kadir \u0130nan\u0131r",
                "rightAnswer": "Y\u0131lmaz G\u00fcney",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 163,
                "questionText": "Kuzey Yar\u0131m K\u00fcre'de en uzun gece hangi tarihte ya\u015fan\u0131r?",
                "choice1": 43545,
                "choice2": 43731,
                "choice3": 43820,
                "choice4": 43637,
                "rightAnswer": 43820,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 164,
                "questionText": "Ekonomide nakit,Fizik'te s\u0131v\u0131 anlam\u0131na gelen kelime hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Mevduat",
                "choice2": "Faiz",
                "choice3": "Hacim",
                "choice4": "Likit",
                "rightAnswer": "Likit",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 165,
                "questionText": "Karag\u00f6z oyunundaki kambur c\u00fccenin ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Beberuhi",
                "choice2": "\u0130bi\u015f",
                "choice3": "Pi\u015fekar",
                "choice4": "Hacivat",
                "rightAnswer": "Beberuhi",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 166,
                "questionText": "Sinemaya da uyarlanan ''Kuzular\u0131n Sessizli\u011fi'' roman\u0131n\u0131n yazar\u0131 kimdir?",
                "choice1": "John Boyne",
                "choice2": "Thomas Harris",
                "choice3": "Winston Gromm",
                "choice4": "J.K.Rowling",
                "rightAnswer": "Thomas Harris",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 167,
                "questionText": "Osmanl\u0131da hangi b\u00f6lgenin valilerine ''Hidiv'' unvan\u0131 verilirdi?",
                "choice1": "K\u0131br\u0131s",
                "choice2": "K\u0131r\u0131m",
                "choice3": "M\u0131s\u0131r",
                "choice4": "Rumeli",
                "rightAnswer": "M\u0131s\u0131r",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 168,
                "questionText": "'Tospik''hangi \u00e7izgi film karakterinin evcil hayvan\u0131n\u0131n ad\u0131d\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Niloya",
                "choice2": "Ma\u015fa ile Kocaay\u0131",
                "choice3": "Pepee",
                "choice4": "Kelo\u011flan",
                "rightAnswer": "Niloya",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 169,
                "questionText": "Galaksi kelimesi Antik Yunan dilinde hangi anlama gelen kelimeden t\u00fcretilmi\u015ftir?",
                "choice1": "Su",
                "choice2": "S\u00fct",
                "choice3": "Kum",
                "choice4": "Hava",
                "rightAnswer": "S\u00fct",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 170,
                "questionText": "\u0130ki sene \u00fcst \u00fcste en iyi kad\u0131n oyuncu Oskar \u00f6d\u00fcl\u00fcn\u00fc kazanan oyuncu kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Luise Rainer",
                "choice2": "Mary Pickford",
                "choice3": "Norma Shearer",
                "choice4": "Angelina Jolie",
                "rightAnswer": "Luise Rainer",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 171,
                "questionText": "Bir ma\u011fazan\u0131n vitrinindeki ''Patron \u00c7\u0131ld\u0131rd\u0131'' ifadesi muhtemelen hangisini anlatmak istiyordur?",
                "choice1": "Faturalar\u0131n y\u00fcksek geldi\u011fini",
                "choice2": "\u0130ndirim oldu\u011funu",
                "choice3": "Patronun tatile \u00e7\u0131kt\u0131\u011f\u0131n\u0131",
                "choice4": "\u0130\u015f yerine nazar de\u011fdi\u011fini",
                "rightAnswer": "\u0130ndirim oldu\u011funu",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 172,
                "questionText": "Halk aras\u0131nda ki\u015finin destek\u00e7isi,\u00f6zellikle aile b\u00fcy\u00fckleri i\u00e7in kullan\u0131lan ve genellikle ''koca''s\u0131fat\u0131yla an\u0131lan a\u011fa\u00e7 t\u00fcr\u00fc hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Me\u015fe",
                "choice2": "Kay\u0131n",
                "choice3": "\u00c7\u0131nar",
                "choice4": "servi",
                "rightAnswer": "\u00c7\u0131nar",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 173,
                "questionText": "Otomobillerde lastiklerin tak\u0131ld\u0131\u011f\u0131,tekerle\u011fin \u00e7ember bi\u00e7imindeki b\u00f6l\u00fcm\u00fcne ne denir?",
                "choice1": "Kriko",
                "choice2": "Jant",
                "choice3": "\u015easi",
                "choice4": "Dingil",
                "rightAnswer": "Jant",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 174,
                "questionText": "Hangisi ''M\u00fcdavim''s\u00f6zc\u00fc\u011f\u00fc ile ayn\u0131 anlamdad\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Rutin",
                "choice2": "Gedikli",
                "choice3": "Kalender",
                "choice4": "Kadim",
                "rightAnswer": "Gedikli",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 175,
                "questionText": "\u015eekli ve tad\u0131 benzemesine ra\u011fmen,kullan\u0131lan malzemelerdeki de\u011fi\u015fikliklerle yap\u0131lan yemek ve tatl\u0131lara ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Terbiyeli",
                "choice2": "Yalanc\u0131",
                "choice3": "M\u0131z\u0131k\u00e7\u0131",
                "choice4": "Do\u011frucu",
                "rightAnswer": "Yalanc\u0131",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 176,
                "questionText": "Hangisi bir m\u00fczik t\u00fcr\u00fcd\u00fcr?",
                "choice1": "\u0130stanbulin",
                "choice2": "New yorker",
                "choice3": "Parisien",
                "choice4": "napoliten",
                "rightAnswer": "Napoliten",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 177,
                "questionText": "Halk aras\u0131nda kullan\u0131lan s\u00f6ze g\u00f6re hangisinin cezas\u0131n\u0131 ayaklar \u00e7eker?",
                "choice1": "Ak\u0131ll\u0131 telefonun",
                "choice2": "Ak\u0131ls\u0131z ba\u015f\u0131n",
                "choice3": "Bilin\u00e7li tercihin",
                "choice4": "Bilin\u00e7siz t\u00fcketimin",
                "rightAnswer": "Ak\u0131ls\u0131z ba\u015f\u0131n",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 178,
                "questionText": "'G\u00fclen G\u00f6zler''filminde u\u00e7a\u011f\u0131yla sebdi\u011fi k\u0131z\u0131n evinin \u00fcst\u00fcnden ge\u00e7en ve filmin sonunda evin i\u00e7ine ini\u015f yapan \u015eener \u015een'in canland\u0131rd\u0131\u011f\u0131 karakterin ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "L\u00fctf\u00fc",
                "choice2": "\u015eakir",
                "choice3": "Vecihi",
                "choice4": "H\u00fcsamettin",
                "rightAnswer": "Vecihi",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 179,
                "questionText": "Ba\u015fkenti Bogota'da Alt\u0131n m\u00fczesi bulunan ve d\u00fcnyadaki z\u00fcmr\u00fct \u00fcretiminin b\u00fcy\u00fck k\u0131sm\u0131n\u0131 ger\u00e7ekle\u015ftiren,kahvesiyle \u00fcnl\u00fc \u00fclke hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "G\u00fcney Afrika",
                "choice2": "Kolombiya",
                "choice3": "Tunus",
                "choice4": "Botsvana",
                "rightAnswer": "Kolombiya",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 180,
                "questionText": "Hangisini giyenler i\u00e7in ''Jilet gibi'' olmu\u015fsun ifadesi kullan\u0131l\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "E\u015fofman",
                "choice2": "Mayo",
                "choice3": "Pijama",
                "choice4": "Tak\u0131m Elbise",
                "rightAnswer": "Tak\u0131m elbise",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 181,
                "questionText": "'Razak\u0131'' ''ku\u015f'' ve ''Mis'',''Sultani'' hangi meyvenin t\u00fcrlerine verilen isimlerdir?",
                "choice1": "Dut",
                "choice2": "Kiraz",
                "choice3": "\u00dcz\u00fcm",
                "choice4": "Kay\u0131s\u0131",
                "rightAnswer": "\u00dcz\u00fcm",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 182,
                "questionText": "Birbirleriyle selamla\u015f\u0131rken ''Volar Morghulis'' diyen gen\u00e7ler hangi dizinin hayran\u0131d\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Vikings",
                "choice2": "Merlin",
                "choice3": "Tudors",
                "choice4": "Game of Thrones",
                "rightAnswer": "Game of thrones",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 183,
                "questionText": "Osmanl\u0131 devletinde saraydaki ''Kehhalba\u015f\u0131''adl\u0131 hekim hangisinin tedavisi g\u00f6revliydi?",
                "choice1": "Di\u015f",
                "choice2": "G\u00f6z",
                "choice3": "Bel",
                "choice4": "Kulak",
                "rightAnswer": "G\u00f6z",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 184,
                "questionText": "'Gevrek Gevrek''ifadesi hangisiyle ilgili kullan\u0131l\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Ba\u011f\u0131rmak",
                "choice2": "G\u00fclmek",
                "choice3": "Ka\u015f\u0131nmak",
                "choice4": "A\u011flamak",
                "rightAnswer": "G\u00fclmek",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 185,
                "questionText": "Bir yar\u0131\u015fmada konulan \u00f6d\u00fcle uygun g\u00f6r\u00fclmemekle birlikte,an\u0131lmaya de\u011fer bulunan ki\u015fiye ya da esere verilen dereceye en denir?",
                "choice1": "Amorti",
                "choice2": "Mansiyon",
                "choice3": "Teselli",
                "choice4": "\u015eilt",
                "rightAnswer": "Mansiyon",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 186,
                "questionText": "'Hala k\u0131z\u0131 zehra'' ''Kom\u015fu k\u0131z\u0131 d\u00fcriye'' ve ''D\u00fcnyalar g\u00fczeli kezban''kimin \u015fark\u0131lar\u0131nda ge\u00e7en isimlerdir?",
                "choice1": "Cem Karaca",
                "choice2": "Bar\u0131\u015f Man\u00e7o",
                "choice3": "Erkin Koray",
                "choice4": "B\u00fclent Orta\u00e7gil",
                "rightAnswer": "Bar\u0131\u015f Man\u00e7o",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 187,
                "questionText": "Hangi yeme\u011fin yap\u0131m\u0131nda tahin kullan\u0131l\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Borani",
                "choice2": "Tabbule",
                "choice3": "Humus",
                "choice4": "\u00c7\u0131lb\u0131r",
                "rightAnswer": "Humus",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 188,
                "questionText": "'Charlie'nin \u00c7ikolata Fabrikas\u0131''filminde farbrikan\u0131n sahibi olan ve Johnny Deep'in canlandr\u0131d\u0131\u011f\u0131 ba\u015f karakterin ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Willy Wonka",
                "choice2": "Davy Jones",
                "choice3": "Charlie Brown",
                "choice4": "Sweeney Todd",
                "rightAnswer": "Willy Wonka",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 189,
                "questionText": "Yunan Mitolojisi'nde Eros ok atarak insanlar\u0131n birbirine hangi duyguyu hissetmesini sa\u011flard\u0131?",
                "choice1": "A\u015fk",
                "choice2": "\u015eefkat",
                "choice3": "G\u00fcven",
                "choice4": "Sab\u0131r",
                "rightAnswer": "A\u015fk",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 190,
                "questionText": "Kuma\u015f\u0131n kenar\u0131na t\u0131\u011f ile i\u015flenen,eski evlerde s\u0131k\u00e7a g\u00f6r\u00fclen,giysi ve \u00f6rt\u00fclerde kullan\u0131lan \u00f6rg\u00fcye ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Fisto",
                "choice2": "Kanevi\u00e7e",
                "choice3": "Kurdela",
                "choice4": "Dantel",
                "rightAnswer": "dantel",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 191,
                "questionText": "Eski bir T\u00fcrk masal\u0131na ad\u0131n\u0131 veren g\u00fclen ayva ile birlikte a\u011flayan meyve hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Elma",
                "choice2": "Nar",
                "choice3": "Dut",
                "choice4": "\u00dcz\u00fcm",
                "rightAnswer": "Nar",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 192,
                "questionText": "Peter Jackson'\u0131n y\u00f6netti\u011fi ''Tha Hobbit''serisinin son filmi hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Beklenmedik Yolculuk",
                "choice2": "Smaug'un \u00c7orak Topraklar\u0131",
                "choice3": "Be\u015f Ordunun sava\u015f\u0131",
                "choice4": "Kral\u0131n d\u00f6n\u00fc\u015f\u00fc",
                "rightAnswer": "Be\u015f Ordunun Sava\u015f\u0131",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 193,
                "questionText": "Kurtulu\u015f Sava\u015f\u0131'nda cephede Mustafa Kemal'in yan\u0131nda onba\u015f\u0131 olarak yer alan,''Mor Salk\u0131ml\u0131 Ev''kitab\u0131n\u0131n yazar\u0131 kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Yakup Kadri Karaosmano\u011flu",
                "choice2": "Halide Edip Ad\u0131var",
                "choice3": "Re\u015fat Nuri G\u00fcntekin",
                "choice4": "Nezihe Meri\u00e7",
                "rightAnswer": "Halide Edip Ad\u0131var",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 194,
                "questionText": "G\u00fcne\u015fte veya hafif alevde kurutulmu\u015f ete ne denir?",
                "choice1": "Dumur",
                "choice2": "Tirit",
                "choice3": "Fodul",
                "choice4": "Kadit",
                "rightAnswer": "Kadit",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 195,
                "questionText": "Medeni kanunumuza g\u00f6re vasiyetname haz\u0131rlamak i\u00e7in ka\u00e7 ya\u015f\u0131n\u0131 doldurmak gerekir?",
                "choice1": 15,
                "choice2": 18,
                "choice3": 21,
                "choice4": 25,
                "rightAnswer": 15,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 196,
                "questionText": "D\u00fcd\u00fck,futbol ma\u00e7lar\u0131nda kullan\u0131lmadan \u00f6nce hakemler hangisini kullan\u0131rlard\u0131?",
                "choice1": "Beyaz mendil",
                "choice2": "\u015eapka",
                "choice3": "Gong",
                "choice4": "\u00c7an",
                "rightAnswer": "Beyaz Mendil",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 197,
                "questionText": "'Melul melul'' bakan ki\u015filerin ruh hali nas\u0131ld\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "\u00dczg\u00fcn",
                "choice2": "Nazl\u0131",
                "choice3": "\u015ea\u015fk\u0131n",
                "choice4": "Utanga\u00e7",
                "rightAnswer": "\u00dczg\u00fcn",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 198,
                "questionText": "Tavla kar\u015f\u0131la\u015fmalar\u0131 genelde ka\u00e7ta biter?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 5,
                "choice3": 7,
                "choice4": 10,
                "rightAnswer": 5,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 199,
                "questionText": "\u0130nsanlarla ya\u015famaya karar verip kendi kendini evcille\u015ftiren hayvan hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "K\u00f6pek",
                "choice2": "Kedi",
                "choice3": "Geyik",
                "choice4": "Fil",
                "rightAnswer": "Kedi",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 200,
                "questionText": "Eski d\u00f6nem sava\u015flar\u0131nda surlar\u0131n kap\u0131s\u0131n\u0131 k\u0131rmak i\u00e7in kullan\u0131lan,en az 6 askerin kald\u0131rabildi\u011fi sava\u015f aletine ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "At ba\u015f\u0131",
                "choice2": "E\u015f\u015fek",
                "choice3": "Geyik ba\u015f\u0131",
                "choice4": "Ko\u00e7 ba\u015f\u0131",
                "rightAnswer": "Ko\u00e7 ba\u015f\u0131",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 201,
                "questionText": "Bir \u015feyin en fazla olabilecek miktar\u0131 hangi s\u00f6zle ifade edilir?",
                "choice1": "Yer yar\u0131lsa",
                "choice2": "\u0130\u011fne d\u00fc\u015fse",
                "choice3": "Ta\u015f \u00c7atlasa",
                "choice4": "Top patlasa",
                "rightAnswer": "Ta\u015f \u00c7atlasa",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 202,
                "questionText": "\u0130nsanlar hangisini anlat\u0131rken kli\u015fe olarak''Biliyorsan anlatmayay\u0131m''der?",
                "choice1": "Askerlik an\u0131s\u0131",
                "choice2": "Masal",
                "choice3": "F\u0131kra",
                "choice4": "Dedikodu",
                "rightAnswer": "F\u0131kra",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 203,
                "questionText": "Dedenizin damat dedi\u011fi,baban\u0131z\u0131n bacanak dedi\u011fi,kuzeninizin baba dedi\u011fi ki\u015fi sizin neyiniz olur?",
                "choice1": "Day\u0131",
                "choice2": "Koca",
                "choice3": "Amca",
                "choice4": "Eni\u015fte",
                "rightAnswer": "Eni\u015fte",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 204,
                "questionText": "Hangisi bir motosiklet t\u00fcr\u00fcd\u00fcr?",
                "choice1": "Ginger",
                "choice2": "Chopper",
                "choice3": "Cruise",
                "choice4": "Roadster",
                "rightAnswer": "Chopper",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 205,
                "questionText": "Hababam S\u0131n\u0131f\u0131 filmlerindeki Mahmut Hoca karakteri hangi bran\u015f \u00f6\u011fretmenidir?",
                "choice1": "Co\u011frafya",
                "choice2": "Edebiyat",
                "choice3": "Tarih",
                "choice4": "Matematik",
                "rightAnswer": "Tarih",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 206,
                "questionText": "'Domat ve tav\u015fan y\u00fcre\u011fi''hangisinin t\u00fcrleridir?",
                "choice1": "Zeytin",
                "choice2": "Domates",
                "choice3": "\u0130ncir",
                "choice4": "\u00dcz\u00fcm",
                "rightAnswer": "Zeytin",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 207,
                "questionText": "'Yaban ve Sodom ve Gomore'' kitaplar\u0131n\u0131n yazar\u0131 kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Halit Ziya U\u015fakl\u0131gil",
                "choice2": "Yakup Kadri Karaosmano\u011flu",
                "choice3": "Ahmet Hamdi Tanp\u0131nar",
                "choice4": "Sait Faik Abas\u0131yan\u0131k",
                "rightAnswer": "Yakup Kadri Karaosmano\u011flu",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 208,
                "questionText": "Uzay istasyonu Skylab'\u0131n par\u00e7alar\u0131n\u0131n \u00fclkeisne d\u00fc\u015fmesinin ard\u0131ndan NASA'ya \u00e7evreyi kirletti\u011fi i\u00e7in ceza kesen \u00fclke hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "\u0130ngiltere",
                "choice2": "Avustralya",
                "choice3": "Hindistan",
                "choice4": "Rusya",
                "rightAnswer": "Avustralya",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 209,
                "questionText": "'Homer,Barge,Bart,Lisa ve Maggie''hangi \u00e7izgi dizinin karakterleridir?",
                "choice1": "Southpark",
                "choice2": "The Simpsons",
                "choice3": "Family Guy",
                "choice4": "American Dad",
                "rightAnswer": "The Simpsons",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 210,
                "questionText": "19,yy boyunca ''\u00dczerinde g\u00fcne\u015f batmayan imparatorluk''olarak an\u0131lan \u00fclke hangisidir*",
                "choice1": "\u00c7in",
                "choice2": "\u0130ngiltere",
                "choice3": "Rusya",
                "choice4": "Japonya",
                "rightAnswer": "\u0130ngiltere",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 211,
                "questionText": "'Y\u0131lanlar\u0131n \u00d6c\u00fc'' ve ''Yol'' filmlerinin y\u00f6netmeni kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Yavuz Turgul",
                "choice2": "At\u0131f Y\u0131lmaz",
                "choice3": "Ertem E\u011filmez",
                "choice4": "\u015eerif G\u00f6ren",
                "rightAnswer": "\u015eerif G\u00f6ren",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 212,
                "questionText": "'15-16'y\u0131 ver'' deyince hangisinin bir t\u00fcr\u00fc isteniyordur?",
                "choice1": "\u0130ngiliz anahtar\u0131",
                "choice2": "Kriko",
                "choice3": "\u00c7eki\u00e7",
                "choice4": "Tornavida",
                "rightAnswer": "\u0130ngiliz Anahtar\u0131",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 213,
                "questionText": "'Fazla abartmak''analm\u0131nda kullan\u0131lan s\u00f6zde hangisini ka\u00e7\u0131rmaktan bahsedilir?",
                "choice1": "Endaze",
                "choice2": "Ar\u015f\u0131n",
                "choice3": "Karat",
                "choice4": "Okka",
                "rightAnswer": "Endaze",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 214,
                "questionText": "\u015eansl\u0131'anlam\u0131na gelen s\u00f6zc\u00fck a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Ac\u0131l\u0131",
                "choice2": "Ek\u015fili",
                "choice3": "Ball\u0131",
                "choice4": "Hardall\u0131",
                "rightAnswer": "Ball\u0131",
                "difficulty": 0,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 215,
                "questionText": "Co\u011frafya kitab\u0131nda kar\u015f\u0131la\u015f\u0131labilecek ''Akdeniz,Karadeniz,Ege,Marmara..'' \u015feklindeki bir listenin ba\u015fl\u0131\u011f\u0131 hangisi olamaz?",
                "choice1": "T\u00fcrkiye'nin co\u011frafi b\u00f6lgeleri",
                "choice2": "T\u00fcrkiye'ye k\u0131y\u0131s\u0131 olan denizler",
                "choice3": "Anadolu'ya k\u0131y\u0131s\u0131 olan denizler",
                "choice4": "Anadolu'da bulunan yanarda\u011flar",
                "rightAnswer": "Anadolu'da bulunan yanarda\u011flar",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 216,
                "questionText": "Bir boks ma\u00e7\u0131nda boks\u00f6rlerden biri yere d\u00fc\u015fm\u00fc\u015fse hakem ka\u00e7a kadar say\u0131p nakavt der?",
                "choice1": 5,
                "choice2": 10,
                "choice3": 15,
                "choice4": 9,
                "rightAnswer": 10,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 217,
                "questionText": "'Sert,k\u0131r\u0131c\u0131,g\u00f6n\u00fcl k\u0131r\u0131c\u0131'' anlam\u0131na gelen ifade a\u015fa\u011fdakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Ha\u015fin",
                "choice2": "Ha\u015far\u0131",
                "choice3": "Haylaz",
                "choice4": "Hayta",
                "rightAnswer": "Ha\u015fin",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 218,
                "questionText": "Ba\u011flamay\u0131 m\u0131zrap kullanmadan sadece parmak u\u00e7lar\u0131yla \u00e7alma tekni\u011fine ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "Dizek",
                "choice2": "\u015eelte",
                "choice3": "Porte",
                "choice4": "Gam",
                "rightAnswer": "\u015eelte",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 219,
                "questionText": "Halk aras\u0131nda ''G\u00fcle g\u00fcle giy''anlam\u0131nda kullan\u0131lan s\u00f6z a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "\u00dcst\u00fcnde kurulans\u0131n",
                "choice2": "\u00dcst\u00fcnde durulans\u0131",
                "choice3": "\u00dcst\u00fcnde paralans\u0131n",
                "choice4": "\u00dcst\u00fcnde \u00fct\u00fclensin",
                "rightAnswer": "\u00dcst\u00fcnde paralans\u0131n",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 220,
                "questionText": "Hangi arac\u0131 kullanmak i\u00e7in g\u00f6rme duyusuna gerek yoktur?",
                "choice1": "Periskop",
                "choice2": "Teleskop",
                "choice3": "Steteskop",
                "choice4": "Mikroskop",
                "rightAnswer": "Steteskop",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 221,
                "questionText": "Hangisin di\u011fer ad\u0131 ''Alt\u0131n top''tur?",
                "choice1": "Kay\u0131s\u0131",
                "choice2": "Greyfurt",
                "choice3": "Yenid\u00fcnya",
                "choice4": "Kavun",
                "rightAnswer": "Greyfurt",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 222,
                "questionText": "Bir e\u015fyan\u0131n kendisine emanet edildi\u011fi,kaybolmas\u0131 halinde sorumlu tutulaca\u011f\u0131n\u0131 s\u00f6ylemek isteyen biri,oe\u015fya i\u00e7in hangi ifadeyi kullan\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "\u00dcst\u00fcme iyilik sa\u011fl\u0131k",
                "choice2": "\u00dczerinize afiyet",
                "choice3": "\u00dcst\u00fcme vazife de\u011fil",
                "choice4": "\u00dczerime zimmetli",
                "rightAnswer": "\u00dczerime zimmetli",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 223,
                "questionText": "Osmanl\u0131 Devleti zaman\u0131nda ya\u015fanan sava\u015flar\u0131n anlat\u0131ld\u0131\u011f\u0131 derste a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisinden bahsedilmez?",
                "choice1": "I.D\u00fcnya Sava\u015f\u0131",
                "choice2": "Dandanakan Sava\u015f\u0131",
                "choice3": "Ankara Sava\u015f\u0131",
                "choice4": "Balkan Sava\u015flar\u0131",
                "rightAnswer": "Dandanakan Sava\u015f\u0131",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 224,
                "questionText": "D\u00f6rt d\u00f6nem milletvekilli\u011fi de yapan,''Aya\u015fl\u0131 ile Kirac\u0131lar\u0131'' ve ''Otlak\u00e7\u0131''kitaplar\u0131yla tan\u0131nan \u00f6yk\u00fc yazar\u0131 kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Memduh \u015eevket Esendal",
                "choice2": "Sait Faik Abas\u0131yan\u0131k",
                "choice3": "Tar\u0131k Bu\u011fra",
                "choice4": "\u00d6mer Seyfettin",
                "rightAnswer": "Memduh \u015eevket Esendal",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 225,
                "questionText": "Hangisi kilim ve hal\u0131larda kullan\u0131lan bir fig\u00fcr\u00fcn ad\u0131d\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Elibelinde",
                "choice2": "Diliuzun",
                "choice3": "G\u00f6z\u00fckeskin",
                "choice4": "Kalbiyumu\u015fak",
                "rightAnswer": "Elibelinde",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 226,
                "questionText": "Felsefe kelimesinin k\u00f6keni olan ''Philo'' ve ''Sophia'' kelimeleri ne anlama gelir?",
                "choice1": "Bilgelik sevgisi",
                "choice2": "Mutluluk kayna\u011f\u0131",
                "choice3": "Hayat\u0131n anlam\u0131",
                "choice4": "Ya\u015fam d\u00f6ng\u00fcs\u00fc",
                "rightAnswer": "Bilgelik sevgisi",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 227,
                "questionText": "'G\u00fc\u00e7l\u00fc ve \u00fcst\u00fcn h\u00fck\u00fcmdar''anlam\u0131na gelen,Timur i\u00e7inde kendi tarih\u00e7ileri taraf\u0131ndan kullna\u0131lan \u00fcnvan a\u015fa\u011f\u0131dakilerden hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Ordubozan",
                "choice2": "Ba\u015fe\u011fdiren",
                "choice3": "Demirb\u00fcken",
                "choice4": "Sahipk\u0131ran",
                "rightAnswer": "Sahipk\u0131ran",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 228,
                "questionText": "Hangisin ABD'de bir \u00fcniversite taraf\u0131ndan verilmi\u015f fahri doktoras\u0131 vard\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "\u00d6r\u00fcmcek Adam",
                "choice2": "Homer Simpson",
                "choice3": "S\u00fcnger Bob",
                "choice4": "Kurba\u011fa Kermit",
                "rightAnswer": "Kurba\u011fa Kermit",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 229,
                "questionText": "Hangisi ''\u00c7eli\u015fki'' anlam\u0131na gelir?",
                "choice1": "Metafor",
                "choice2": "Kaotik",
                "choice3": "Paradoks",
                "choice4": "Girift",
                "rightAnswer": "Paradoks",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 230,
                "questionText": "'Los Angeles Galaxy'',''Atlanta United'',''Chicago Fire'' ve ''Real Salt Lake'' ABD'nin hangi spor dal\u0131n\u0131n \u00fcst liginde m\u00fccadele eden tak\u0131mlar\u0131d\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Basketbol",
                "choice2": "Amerikan Futbolu",
                "choice3": "Beyzbol",
                "choice4": "Futbol",
                "rightAnswer": "Futbol",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 231,
                "questionText": "37 ya\u015f\u0131na kadar ablas\u0131 sand\u0131\u011f\u0131 ki\u015finin asl\u0131nda annesi oldu\u011funu \u00f6\u011frenen,''Cinnet'' ve ''Birka\u00e7 \u0130yi Adam'' filmlerinde oynayan Oscar \u00f6d\u00fcll\u00fc oyuncu kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Jack Nicholson",
                "choice2": "Kevin Costner",
                "choice3": "John Travolta",
                "choice4": "Robert De Niro",
                "rightAnswer": "Jack Nicholson",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 232,
                "questionText": "Ankara'dan yola \u00e7\u0131k\u0131p K\u0131rk\u0131kkale,Kayseri,Sivas,Malatya,Diyarbak\u0131r,Batman \u00fczerinden Siirt'e ula\u015fan ve son zamanlarda pop\u00fclerli\u011fi artan TCDD'ye ait tren hatt\u0131 hangisidir?",
                "choice1": "Do\u011fu Ekspresi",
                "choice2": "Kurtalan Ekspresi",
                "choice3": "Orient Ekspresi",
                "choice4": "Anadolu Ekspresi",
                "rightAnswer": "Kurtalan Ekspresi",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 233,
                "questionText": "K\u0131l\u00e7\u0131k atma'hangi sporla ilgili bir terimdir?",
                "choice1": "Boks",
                "choice2": "Ok\u00e7uluk",
                "choice3": "G\u00fcre\u015f",
                "choice4": "Eskrim",
                "rightAnswer": "G\u00fcre\u015f",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 234,
                "questionText": "Bovlingte \u00fc\u00e7gen \u015feklinde dizilen,standart a\u011f\u0131rl\u0131\u011fa sahip olan ve bovling topuyla d\u00fc\u015f\u00fcr\u00fclmeye \u00e7al\u0131\u015f\u0131lan nesnelere ne ad verilir?",
                "choice1": "\u0130steka",
                "choice2": "Baton",
                "choice3": "Lobut",
                "choice4": "Epe",
                "rightAnswer": "Lobut",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 235,
                "questionText": "Osmanl\u0131 Devleti'nde hangi isimde bir makam olmam\u0131\u015ft\u0131r?",
                "choice1": "Anadolu Beylerbeyli\u011fi",
                "choice2": "Trakya Beylerbeyli\u011fi",
                "choice3": "Karaman Beylerbeyli\u011fi",
                "choice4": "Rumeli Beylerbeyli\u011fi",
                "rightAnswer": "Trakya Beylerbeyli\u011fi",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 236,
                "questionText": "Ba\u015frollerinde M\u00fcnir \u00d6zkul ve Adile Na\u015fit'in oldu\u011fu ''Ne\u015feli G\u00fcnler'' ve ''Aile \u015eerefi'' filmlerinin y\u00f6netmeni kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Memduh \u00dcn",
                "choice2": "Orhan Aksoy",
                "choice3": "Ertem E\u011filmez",
                "choice4": "Tun\u00e7 Ba\u015faran",
                "rightAnswer": "Orhan Aksoy",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 237,
                "questionText": "Kan bas\u0131nc\u0131n\u0131n t\u0131p terminolojisindeki ad\u0131 nedir?",
                "choice1": "Endoskopi",
                "choice2": "Anjiyo",
                "choice3": "Tansiyon",
                "choice4": "Ultrason",
                "rightAnswer": "Tansiyon",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 238,
                "questionText": "Hindistan'a deniz yoluyla giden ilk Avrupal\u0131 kimdir?",
                "choice1": "Ferdinand Magellan",
                "choice2": "Vasco da Gama",
                "choice3": "Kristof Kolomb",
                "choice4": "Marco Polo",
                "rightAnswer": "Vasco da Gama",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 239,
                "questionText": "Hangisi Bar\u0131\u015f Man\u00e7o'nun \u015fark\u0131lar\u0131ndan biri de\u011fildir?",
                "choice1": "Kahve",
                "choice2": "Kazma",
                "choice3": "Cac\u0131k",
                "choice4": "Anahtar",
                "rightAnswer": "Kahve",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 240,
                "questionText": "'O mahilerki derya i\u00e7redir deryay\u0131 bilmezler''dizesindeki ''derya'' ve ''mahi'' kelimeleri ne anlama gelir?",
                "choice1": "\u0130nsan ve \u015fehir",
                "choice2": "Deniz ve bal\u0131k",
                "choice3": "Defter ve yaprak",
                "choice4": "Top ve g\u00fclle",
                "rightAnswer": "Deniz ve Bal\u0131k",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Genel K\u00fclt\u00fcr",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            }
        ],
        "en": [
            {
                "questionId": 0,
                "questionText": "How many countries border San Marino?",
                "choice1": 2,
                "choice2": 1,
                "choice3": 3,
                "choice4": 4,
                "rightAnswer": 1,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 1,
                "questionText": "With how many countries does the US share a land border?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 2,
                "choice3": 4,
                "choice4": 1,
                "rightAnswer": 2,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 2,
                "questionText": "How many faces has the clock on Big Ben's tower?",
                "choice1": 4,
                "choice2": 3,
                "choice3": 1,
                "choice4": 2,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 3,
                "questionText": "How many hours behind Greenwich Mean Time is California?",
                "choice1": 12,
                "choice2": 8,
                "choice3": 6,
                "choice4": 10,
                "rightAnswer": 8,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 4,
                "questionText": "How many fountains are found in the gardens at the Palace of Versailles?\u00a0",
                "choice1": "140\u00a0",
                "choice2": 14000,
                "choice3": 14,
                "choice4": 1400,
                "rightAnswer": 1400,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 5,
                "questionText": "How many candles were used to light the Hall of Mirrors in the Palace of Versailles?\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0",
                "choice1": 33000,
                "choice2": 333000,
                "choice3": 300,
                "choice4": 3000,
                "rightAnswer": 3000,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 6,
                "questionText": "On a clear day how far can one see from the observation platform of the Empire State Building?",
                "choice1": "630 \u00a0km",
                "choice2": "3 km",
                "choice3": "30 km",
                "choice4": "130 km",
                "rightAnswer": "130 km",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 7,
                "questionText": "Peter Minuit of the Dutch West India Company bought Manhattan island from the local indians in 1626 with cloth, trinkets and beads worth\u00a0the equivalent \u00a0of what?",
                "choice1": "2,400 dollars",
                "choice2": "24 cents",
                "choice3": "240 dollars",
                "choice4": "24 dollars",
                "rightAnswer": "24 dollars",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 8,
                "questionText": "In which European city is Schiphol airport?",
                "choice1": "Amsterdam",
                "choice2": "Budapest",
                "choice3": "Athens",
                "choice4": "Warsaw",
                "rightAnswer": "Amsterdam",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 9,
                "questionText": "Where is Dam Square?",
                "choice1": "Berlin",
                "choice2": "Darmstadt",
                "choice3": "Copenhagen",
                "choice4": "Amsterdam",
                "rightAnswer": "Amsterdam",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 10,
                "questionText": "In which city can one visit the Palace of the Popes?",
                "choice1": "Rome",
                "choice2": "Nancy",
                "choice3": "Avignon",
                "choice4": "Madrid",
                "rightAnswer": "Avignon",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 11,
                "questionText": "The\u00a0jade green waters of Lake Louise are found in which national park?",
                "choice1": "Yellowstone, USA",
                "choice2": "Kruger, South Africa",
                "choice3": "Banff, Canada",
                "choice4": "Serengeti, Tanzania",
                "rightAnswer": "Banff, Canada",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 12,
                "questionText": "In which county can one find Luton Airport?",
                "choice1": "Hertfordshire",
                "choice2": "Bedfordshire",
                "choice3": "Essex",
                "choice4": "Kent",
                "rightAnswer": "Bedfordshire",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 13,
                "questionText": "With 196 tonnes, the heaviest what ever built is found within the walls of the Kremlin?",
                "choice1": "statue",
                "choice2": "cannon ball",
                "choice3": "gold bar",
                "choice4": "bell",
                "rightAnswer": "bell",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 14,
                "questionText": "Since 1981, Mumbai is the official name for which Indian city?",
                "choice1": "Delhi",
                "choice2": "Calcutta",
                "choice3": "Bombay",
                "choice4": "Bangalore",
                "rightAnswer": "Bombay",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 15,
                "questionText": "The name of which capital city is the Latin word for a red dye wood?",
                "choice1": "Berlin",
                "choice2": "Rome",
                "choice3": "Brasilia",
                "choice4": "Vienna",
                "rightAnswer": "Brasilia",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 16,
                "questionText": "Where in London can one view the Magna Carta and the Rosetta Stone?",
                "choice1": "National Gallery",
                "choice2": "Tate Gallery",
                "choice3": "British Museum",
                "choice4": "Tower of London",
                "rightAnswer": "British Museum",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 17,
                "questionText": "With 40 tonnes, the largest what ever built is found\u00a0within the walls of\u00a0the Kremlin?",
                "choice1": "crucifix",
                "choice2": "chandelier",
                "choice3": "chalice",
                "choice4": "cannon",
                "rightAnswer": "cannon",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 18,
                "questionText": "Where is the Astronaut Hall of Fame located?",
                "choice1": "Houston",
                "choice2": "Cape Canaveral",
                "choice3": "Washington",
                "choice4": "New York",
                "rightAnswer": "Cape Canaveral",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 19,
                "questionText": "In which city can one board the luxurious 'Blue Train'?",
                "choice1": "Edinburgh",
                "choice2": "Vancouver",
                "choice3": "Cape Town",
                "choice4": "Istanbul",
                "rightAnswer": "Cape Town",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 20,
                "questionText": "In which city does the National Assembly of Wales sit?",
                "choice1": "Newport",
                "choice2": "St. Davids",
                "choice3": "Swansea",
                "choice4": "Cardiff",
                "rightAnswer": "Cardiff",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 21,
                "questionText": "Which London street does one associate with the 1960s fashion scene?",
                "choice1": "Fleet",
                "choice2": "Pall Mall",
                "choice3": "Carnaby",
                "choice4": "Threadneedle",
                "rightAnswer": "Carnaby",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 22,
                "questionText": "In which city is the world famous Sears Tower skyscraper located?",
                "choice1": "Chicago",
                "choice2": "Detroit",
                "choice3": "Boston",
                "choice4": "New York",
                "rightAnswer": "Chicago",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 23,
                "questionText": "How many litres of beer are consumed each year at the Oktoberfest in Munich?",
                "choice1": "circa 600,000",
                "choice2": "\u00a0circa 60,000,000",
                "choice3": "circa 60,000",
                "choice4": "circa 6,000,000",
                "rightAnswer": "circa 6,000,000",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 24,
                "questionText": "Which metal was used to construct the outside hull of the\u00a0Statue\u00a0of Liberty?",
                "choice1": "iron",
                "choice2": "copper",
                "choice3": "silver",
                "choice4": "brass",
                "rightAnswer": "copper",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 25,
                "questionText": "In which city is the world famous Burg Al Arab skyscraper located?",
                "choice1": "Tehran",
                "choice2": "Dubai",
                "choice3": "Kuwait City",
                "choice4": "Cairo",
                "rightAnswer": "Dubai",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 26,
                "questionText": "Which language is Afrikaans derived from?",
                "choice1": "German",
                "choice2": "Dutch",
                "choice3": "Spanish",
                "choice4": "English",
                "rightAnswer": "Dutch",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 27,
                "questionText": "The Royal Mile is a famous street in which capital city?",
                "choice1": "Ottawa",
                "choice2": "Edinburgh",
                "choice3": "London",
                "choice4": "Dublin",
                "rightAnswer": "Edinburgh",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 28,
                "questionText": "Which European capital has the nickname 'The Athens of the north'?",
                "choice1": "Edinburgh",
                "choice2": "Berlin",
                "choice3": "Paris",
                "choice4": "Helsinki",
                "rightAnswer": "Edinburgh",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 29,
                "questionText": "Famine in which country triggered the Band Aid Charity?",
                "choice1": "Ethiopia",
                "choice2": "South Africa",
                "choice3": "Zimbabwe",
                "choice4": "Sudan",
                "rightAnswer": "Ethiopia",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 30,
                "questionText": "Which country's postage stamps bear the inscription \"Suomi\"?",
                "choice1": "Norway",
                "choice2": "Finland",
                "choice3": "Sweden",
                "choice4": "Denmark",
                "rightAnswer": "Finland",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 31,
                "questionText": "The Uffizien museum, a feast for the eyes for lovers of Renaissance paintings, is located in which city?",
                "choice1": "Florence",
                "choice2": "Vatican City",
                "choice3": "Rome",
                "choice4": "Milan",
                "rightAnswer": "Florence",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 32,
                "questionText": "Whose upper house of Parliament is called the Bundesrat?",
                "choice1": "Spain's",
                "choice2": "Germany's",
                "choice3": "Belgium's",
                "choice4": "France's",
                "rightAnswer": "Germany's",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 33,
                "questionText": "What is the name of the film prize awarded each year at the Venice film festival?",
                "choice1": "Golden Eagle",
                "choice2": "Golden Bear",
                "choice3": "Golden Star",
                "choice4": "Golden Lion",
                "rightAnswer": "Golden Lion",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 34,
                "questionText": "In which country is the harbour city\u00a0Mumbai?",
                "choice1": "Senegal",
                "choice2": "Japan",
                "choice3": "India",
                "choice4": "China",
                "rightAnswer": "India",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 35,
                "questionText": "In which city is the world famous skyscraper Petronas Towers located?",
                "choice1": "Dubai",
                "choice2": "Kuala Lumpur",
                "choice3": "New York",
                "choice4": "Shanghai",
                "rightAnswer": "Kuala Lumpur",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 36,
                "questionText": "It is said that the residents of which European capital never sleep?",
                "choice1": "Oslo",
                "choice2": "Madrid",
                "choice3": "Warsaw",
                "choice4": "Dublin",
                "rightAnswer": "Madrid",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 37,
                "questionText": "In which city is the famous Prado museum?",
                "choice1": "St Petersburg",
                "choice2": "Vatican",
                "choice3": "Florence",
                "choice4": "Madrid",
                "rightAnswer": "Madrid",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 38,
                "questionText": "Which\u00a0destination for 60s hippies has been called the Paris of the Sahara?\u00a0\u00a0",
                "choice1": "Luxor",
                "choice2": "Marrakesh",
                "choice3": "Cairo",
                "choice4": "Tripolis",
                "rightAnswer": "Marrakesh",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 39,
                "questionText": "The German city of\u00a0L\u00fcbeck is world famous for which product?",
                "choice1": "marzipan",
                "choice2": "Frankfurters",
                "choice3": "sauerkraut",
                "choice4": "pickled herring",
                "rightAnswer": "marzipan",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 40,
                "questionText": "GUM is the world famous dept store in which city?",
                "choice1": "Moscow",
                "choice2": "New York",
                "choice3": "Paris",
                "choice4": "Tokyo",
                "rightAnswer": "Moscow",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 41,
                "questionText": "Which famous castle was the inspiration for the Disney theme park castle?",
                "choice1": "Windsor Castle",
                "choice2": "Neuschwanstein Castle",
                "choice3": "Edinburgh Castle",
                "choice4": "Mount Saint Michel Castle",
                "rightAnswer": "Neuschwanstein Castle",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 42,
                "questionText": "In which city is the world famous\u00a0Chrysler Building skyscraper\u00a0located?",
                "choice1": "Detroit",
                "choice2": "New York",
                "choice3": "San Francisco\u00a0",
                "choice4": "Chicago",
                "rightAnswer": "New York",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 43,
                "questionText": "In which city is the world famous Woolworth Building skyscraper located?",
                "choice1": "Boston",
                "choice2": "Chicago",
                "choice3": "London",
                "choice4": "New York",
                "rightAnswer": "New York",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 44,
                "questionText": "In which country can one find the Giant's Causeway?",
                "choice1": "Canada",
                "choice2": "France",
                "choice3": "Northern Ireland",
                "choice4": "Scotland",
                "rightAnswer": "Northern Ireland",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 45,
                "questionText": "The famous 'Lake Palace' in India,\u00a0once a summer residence for royalty and now a luxury hotel, was the setting\u00a0 for which action film?\u00a0",
                "choice1": "Star Wars. The Empire Strikes Back",
                "choice2": "Mission Impossible II",
                "choice3": "Octopussy",
                "choice4": "Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon",
                "rightAnswer": "Octopussy",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 46,
                "questionText": "In which capital city is the Roland Garos stadium?",
                "choice1": "Prague",
                "choice2": "Budapest",
                "choice3": "Madrid",
                "choice4": "Paris",
                "rightAnswer": "Paris",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 47,
                "questionText": "The victory goddess Victoria and her chariot\u00a0on the top of the Brandenburger Gate in Berlin spent the years between 1806 and 1814 in which capital city?",
                "choice1": "Moscow",
                "choice2": "Rome",
                "choice3": "Paris",
                "choice4": "London",
                "rightAnswer": "Paris",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 48,
                "questionText": "The Emperors Palace or Forbidden City is located in which city?",
                "choice1": "Hong Kong",
                "choice2": "Xi'an",
                "choice3": "Shanghai",
                "choice4": "Peking",
                "rightAnswer": "Peking",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 49,
                "questionText": "The Cathedral of our Lady in Antwerp contains four masterpieces\u00a0depicting Biblical scenes by which famous Baroque painter?",
                "choice1": "Raffael",
                "choice2": "Peter Paul Rubens",
                "choice3": "Vincent van Gogh",
                "choice4": "Rembrandt",
                "rightAnswer": "Peter Paul Rubens",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 50,
                "questionText": "The 'Liberty Bell' is found in which US city?",
                "choice1": "Washington",
                "choice2": "New York",
                "choice3": "Philadelphia",
                "choice4": "Boston",
                "rightAnswer": "Philadelphia",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 51,
                "questionText": "In which harbour city is Lord Nelson's flagship HMS Victory?",
                "choice1": "Liverpool",
                "choice2": "Bristol",
                "choice3": "Portsmouth",
                "choice4": "Plymouth",
                "rightAnswer": "Portsmouth",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 52,
                "questionText": "The longest bridge built in the middleages\u00a0in Europe, the Charles Bridge, is located in which capital city?",
                "choice1": "Oslo",
                "choice2": "Paris",
                "choice3": "London",
                "choice4": "Prague",
                "rightAnswer": "Prague",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 53,
                "questionText": "What creature appears on the Welsh national flag?",
                "choice1": "Red dragon",
                "choice2": "Yellow dafffodil",
                "choice3": "Green leek",
                "choice4": "White sheep",
                "rightAnswer": "Red dragon",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 54,
                "questionText": "Which city has the nickname 'Venice of the north'?",
                "choice1": "Helsinki",
                "choice2": "Montreal",
                "choice3": "St Petersburg",
                "choice4": "Glasgow",
                "rightAnswer": "St Petersburg",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 55,
                "questionText": "Which famous city, sometimes called the Venice of the north, was built on 12 islands?",
                "choice1": "Glasgow",
                "choice2": "Ottawa",
                "choice3": "Oslo",
                "choice4": "St Petersburg",
                "rightAnswer": "St Petersburg",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 56,
                "questionText": "What is the name of the famous mountain that overlooks Cape Town, South Africa?",
                "choice1": "Table",
                "choice2": "Divan",
                "choice3": "Chalice",
                "choice4": "Plate",
                "rightAnswer": "Table",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 57,
                "questionText": "In which famous buiding did Catherine the Great keep her private art collection?",
                "choice1": "The Summer Palace",
                "choice2": "The Kremlin",
                "choice3": "The Bolshoi Theatre",
                "choice4": "The Eremitage",
                "rightAnswer": "The Eremitage",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 58,
                "questionText": "Niagara Falls Canada, where the awe inspiring Horseshoe Falls is located, has been given which nickname?\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0",
                "choice1": "The City of Lights",
                "choice2": "The Misty City",
                "choice3": "The Windy City",
                "choice4": "The Honeymoon City",
                "rightAnswer": "The Honeymoon City",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 59,
                "questionText": "Which golf course is called 'the home of golf'?",
                "choice1": "The Royal and Ancient Golf Club St Andrews",
                "choice2": "Pebble Beach",
                "choice3": "Gleneagles",
                "choice4": "Sunningdale",
                "rightAnswer": "The Royal and Ancient Golf Club St Andrews",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 60,
                "questionText": "Hadrian's Wall was built in order to keep which wild men out of the Roman Empire?",
                "choice1": "The Mongols",
                "choice2": "The Vikings",
                "choice3": "The Scots",
                "choice4": "The Welsh",
                "rightAnswer": "The Scots",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 61,
                "questionText": "The Potala Palace was once\u00a0the\u00a0winter\u00a0residence for which man?\u00a0",
                "choice1": "The\u00a0Dalai Lama",
                "choice2": "Kubla Khan",
                "choice3": "El Cid",
                "choice4": "Pu \u00a0Li",
                "rightAnswer": "The\u00a0Dalai Lama",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 62,
                "questionText": "In which city is the CN Tower, the tallest free standing structure in the world?",
                "choice1": "Chicago",
                "choice2": "Hong Kong",
                "choice3": "Moscow",
                "choice4": "Toronto",
                "rightAnswer": "Toronto",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 63,
                "questionText": "The 'Book of Kells',\u00a0a\u00a01,300 year old masterpiece\u00a0of\u00a0western calligraphy,\u00a0is found in which\u00a0university?",
                "choice1": "Cambridge",
                "choice2": "Trinity College, Dublin",
                "choice3": "\u00a0Oxford",
                "choice4": "Sorbonne, Paris\u00a0\u00a0",
                "rightAnswer": "Trinity College, Dublin",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 64,
                "questionText": "Angel Falls, the worlds highest waterfall is located in which country?",
                "choice1": "Canada",
                "choice2": "Venezuela",
                "choice3": "Switzerland",
                "choice4": "Zambia",
                "rightAnswer": "Venezuela",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 65,
                "questionText": "\u00a0In which city is the famous Bridge of Sighs?",
                "choice1": "Venice",
                "choice2": "Prague",
                "choice3": "Rome",
                "choice4": "Paris",
                "rightAnswer": "Venice",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 66,
                "questionText": "Which Canadian provincial capital is nicknamed 'Little England'?",
                "choice1": "Toronto",
                "choice2": "Quebec City",
                "choice3": "Halifax",
                "choice4": "Victoria",
                "rightAnswer": "Victoria",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 67,
                "questionText": "The Taj Mahal was constructed with which material?",
                "choice1": "White Ivory",
                "choice2": "White Opals",
                "choice3": "White Marble",
                "choice4": "White Granite",
                "rightAnswer": "White Marble",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 68,
                "questionText": "In which US national park is the geysir named 'Old Faithful' located?",
                "choice1": "Grand Teton",
                "choice2": "Yellowstone",
                "choice3": "Bryce Canyon",
                "choice4": "Banff",
                "rightAnswer": "Yellowstone",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 69,
                "questionText": "How many bridges are there over the firth of fourth?",
                "choice1": 4,
                "choice2": 1,
                "choice3": 2,
                "choice4": 3,
                "rightAnswer": 2,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 70,
                "questionText": "How many American states begin and end with the letter 'A'?",
                "choice1": 5,
                "choice2": 3,
                "choice3": 2,
                "choice4": 4,
                "rightAnswer": 3,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 71,
                "questionText": "How many time zones are there in the USA?",
                "choice1": 5,
                "choice2": 2,
                "choice3": 4,
                "choice4": 1,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 72,
                "questionText": "What is the unlucky number in China?",
                "choice1": 7,
                "choice2": 33,
                "choice3": 4,
                "choice4": 13,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 73,
                "questionText": "How many stories high is the Empire State building?",
                "choice1": 202,
                "choice2": 62,
                "choice3": 162,
                "choice4": 102,
                "rightAnswer": 102,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 74,
                "questionText": "What is the population of the Czech Rep?",
                "choice1": "10.3 million",
                "choice2": "4.5 million",
                "choice3": "80.2 million",
                "choice4": "57.6 million",
                "rightAnswer": "10.3 million",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 75,
                "questionText": "Angel Falls, the highest waterfall in the world is how many times higher than the Niagara Falls?",
                "choice1": "25X",
                "choice2": "15X",
                "choice3": "5X",
                "choice4": "2X",
                "rightAnswer": "15X",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 76,
                "questionText": "How\u00a0much does\u00a0the\u00a0Petersglocke, the worlds heaviest church bell\u00a0in the Cologne Cathedral\u00a0weigh ?",
                "choice1": "24 tonnes",
                "choice2": "124 tonnes",
                "choice3": "240 tonnes",
                "choice4": "4 tonnes",
                "rightAnswer": "24 tonnes",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 77,
                "questionText": "To the nearest million, what was the population of Wales in 2001?",
                "choice1": "3 million",
                "choice2": "1 million",
                "choice3": "5 million",
                "choice4": "10 million",
                "rightAnswer": "3 million",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 78,
                "questionText": "What is the cozy\u00a0interior temperature in the world\u00a0famous\u00a0Ice Hotel in Jukkasj\u00e4rvi Sweden?",
                "choice1": "0\u00b0C to -3\u00b0C",
                "choice2": "-13\u00b0C to -16\u00b0C",
                "choice3": "-5\u00b0 C to -8\u00b0C",
                "choice4": "-27\u00b0C to -30\u00b0C",
                "rightAnswer": "-5\u00b0 C to -8\u00b0C",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 79,
                "questionText": "What is the population of Iran?",
                "choice1": "33.5 million",
                "choice2": "144.5 million",
                "choice3": "71.4 million",
                "choice4": "3.8 million",
                "rightAnswer": "71.4 million",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 80,
                "questionText": "What is the population of Vietnam?",
                "choice1": "39.9 million",
                "choice2": "78.8 million",
                "choice3": "10.1 million",
                "choice4": "123.3 million",
                "rightAnswer": "78.8 million",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 81,
                "questionText": "Lake Assal is the lowest point on which continent?",
                "choice1": "Asia",
                "choice2": "Africa",
                "choice3": "Australia",
                "choice4": "Antarctic",
                "rightAnswer": "Africa",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 82,
                "questionText": "Where do the largest vegetables in the US grow?",
                "choice1": "Hawaii",
                "choice2": "Florida",
                "choice3": "New Mexico",
                "choice4": "Alaska",
                "rightAnswer": "Alaska",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 83,
                "questionText": "What is the name of the famous\u00a0ancient temple city in the jungle of Cambodia?",
                "choice1": "Angkor Wat",
                "choice2": "Yogyakarta",
                "choice3": "Penang",
                "choice4": "Amanwana",
                "rightAnswer": "Angkor Wat",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 84,
                "questionText": "The Chrysler Building in New York City is an example of which style of architecture?",
                "choice1": "Baroque",
                "choice2": "Art Deco",
                "choice3": "Post Modernism",
                "choice4": "Byzantine",
                "rightAnswer": "Art Deco",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 85,
                "questionText": "The Sagrada Familia Cathedral in Barcelona is an example of which style of architecture?",
                "choice1": "Romanesque",
                "choice2": "Art Nouveau",
                "choice3": "Renaissance",
                "choice4": "Neo Gothic",
                "rightAnswer": "Art Nouveau",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 86,
                "questionText": "Lake Eyre is the lowest point on which continent?",
                "choice1": "Europe",
                "choice2": "North America",
                "choice3": "Australia",
                "choice4": "Antarctic",
                "rightAnswer": "Australia",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 87,
                "questionText": "The\u00a0Gibson desert is\u00a0found in which country?",
                "choice1": "South Africa",
                "choice2": "Canada",
                "choice3": "Australia",
                "choice4": "USA",
                "rightAnswer": "Australia",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 88,
                "questionText": "Which country does not border Poland?",
                "choice1": "Germany",
                "choice2": "Austria",
                "choice3": "Lithuania",
                "choice4": "Slovakia",
                "rightAnswer": "Austria",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 89,
                "questionText": "The Palace of Versailles is an example of which style of architecture?",
                "choice1": "Baroque",
                "choice2": "Romanesque",
                "choice3": "Gothic",
                "choice4": "Greek",
                "rightAnswer": "Baroque",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 90,
                "questionText": "St Paul's Cathedral in London is an example of which style of architecture?",
                "choice1": "Neo Classical",
                "choice2": "Baroque",
                "choice3": "Art Deco",
                "choice4": "Gothic",
                "rightAnswer": "Baroque",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 91,
                "questionText": "What is the only breed of dog that is allowed to testify in a US courtroom?",
                "choice1": "Poodle",
                "choice2": "German Shepard",
                "choice3": "Bloodhound",
                "choice4": "Collie",
                "rightAnswer": "Bloodhound",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 92,
                "questionText": "Until 1763, Salvador de Bahia was the capital of which country?",
                "choice1": "Brazil",
                "choice2": "Spain",
                "choice3": "Mexico",
                "choice4": "Portugal",
                "rightAnswer": "Brazil",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 93,
                "questionText": "The Hagia Sophia in Istanbul is an example of which style of architecture?",
                "choice1": "Byzantine",
                "choice2": "Gothic",
                "choice3": "Roman",
                "choice4": "Greek",
                "rightAnswer": "Byzantine",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 94,
                "questionText": "The Bay of Fundy is off the coast of which country?",
                "choice1": "New Zealand",
                "choice2": "South Africa",
                "choice3": "Australia",
                "choice4": "Canada",
                "rightAnswer": "Canada",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 95,
                "questionText": "The name of which capital city\u00a0stems from the native word for 'meeting place'?",
                "choice1": "Edinburgh, Scotland",
                "choice2": "Paris, France",
                "choice3": "Ottawa, Canada",
                "choice4": "Canberra, Australia",
                "rightAnswer": "Canberra, Australia",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 96,
                "questionText": "What is the name of the 13th century\u00a0spa city in the Czech Rep. that attracted the likes of Chopin, Beethoven, Bach\u00a0and King Edward VII?",
                "choice1": "Baden Baden",
                "choice2": "Carlsbad",
                "choice3": "Spa",
                "choice4": "Bad Gastein",
                "rightAnswer": "Carlsbad",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 97,
                "questionText": "Which country has only one time zone?",
                "choice1": "Russia",
                "choice2": "China",
                "choice3": "Brazil",
                "choice4": "Canada",
                "rightAnswer": "China",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 98,
                "questionText": "Which country has the largest army in the world?",
                "choice1": "India",
                "choice2": "North Korea",
                "choice3": "China",
                "choice4": "USA",
                "rightAnswer": "China",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 99,
                "questionText": "Which contemporary artist wrapped up the Reichstag in Berlin with 100,000 m2 of polypropylene fabric in the summer of 1995?",
                "choice1": "H.R. Giger",
                "choice2": "Christo",
                "choice3": "Yoko Ono",
                "choice4": "Andy Warhol",
                "rightAnswer": "Christo",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 100,
                "questionText": "When\u00a0did\u00a0the construction of the\u00a0\u00a0Pyramids of Giseh\u00a0first begin?\u00a0\u00a0",
                "choice1": "circa 500 BC",
                "choice2": "circa 50 BC",
                "choice3": "circa 2500 BC",
                "choice4": "\u00a0circa 5500 BC",
                "rightAnswer": "circa 2500 BC",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 101,
                "questionText": "The Grand Place or main market square in Brussels hosts the 'flower carpet' festival each August. How many begonias are used?",
                "choice1": "circa 700,000",
                "choice2": "circa 7,000,000",
                "choice3": "circa 70,000",
                "choice4": "circa 7,000",
                "rightAnswer": "circa 700,000",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 102,
                "questionText": "In which cathedral is the Petersglocke, the worlds largest church bell?",
                "choice1": "Cologne",
                "choice2": "St Peters, Vatican City",
                "choice3": "Canterbury",
                "choice4": "Durham",
                "rightAnswer": "Cologne",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 103,
                "questionText": "Which country does not border Bolivia?",
                "choice1": "Peru",
                "choice2": "Brazil",
                "choice3": "Colombia",
                "choice4": "Chile",
                "rightAnswer": "Colombia",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 104,
                "questionText": "Which country does not border Greece?",
                "choice1": "Bulgaria",
                "choice2": "Croatia",
                "choice3": "Albania",
                "choice4": "Turkey",
                "rightAnswer": "Croatia",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 105,
                "questionText": "Banana is a harbour city in which country?",
                "choice1": "Brazil",
                "choice2": "Colombia",
                "choice3": "Dem Rep of Congo",
                "choice4": "Indonesia",
                "rightAnswer": "Dem Rep of Congo",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 106,
                "questionText": "Mount Elbrus is the highest point on which continent?",
                "choice1": "Europe",
                "choice2": "Antarctic",
                "choice3": "Asia",
                "choice4": "North America",
                "rightAnswer": "Europe",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 107,
                "questionText": "The world famous Oberammergau passion play in Bayern is held how often?",
                "choice1": "every year",
                "choice2": "every 2 years",
                "choice3": "every 10 years",
                "choice4": "every 50 years",
                "rightAnswer": "every 10 years",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 108,
                "questionText": "In which city, famous for its\u00a0ship building, was the ocean liner\u00a0QE2 \u00a0built?",
                "choice1": "Belfast",
                "choice2": "Glasgow",
                "choice3": "Portsmouth",
                "choice4": "Southampton",
                "rightAnswer": "Glasgow",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 109,
                "questionText": "South Africa is the world's leading exporter of what?",
                "choice1": "Diamond",
                "choice2": "Platinum",
                "choice3": "Gold",
                "choice4": "Silver",
                "rightAnswer": "Gold",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 110,
                "questionText": "Which railway station has the most platforms in the world?",
                "choice1": "Waterloo, London",
                "choice2": "Grand Central, New York",
                "choice3": "Gare du Nord, Paris",
                "choice4": "Frankfurt Main",
                "rightAnswer": "Grand Central, New York",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 111,
                "questionText": "Which strait seperates the Persian gulf and the gulf of Oman?",
                "choice1": "Dardanelles",
                "choice2": "Hormuz",
                "choice3": "Malacca",
                "choice4": "Bosporus",
                "rightAnswer": "Hormuz",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 112,
                "questionText": "What country does not border Afghanistan?",
                "choice1": "India",
                "choice2": "China",
                "choice3": "Uzbekistan",
                "choice4": "Pakistan",
                "rightAnswer": "India",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 113,
                "questionText": "Where would you find the volcano named Krakatoa? ",
                "choice1": "India",
                "choice2": "Indonesia",
                "choice3": "China",
                "choice4": "Malaysia",
                "rightAnswer": "Indonesia",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 114,
                "questionText": "Dingle Bay is off the coast of which country?",
                "choice1": "Ireland",
                "choice2": "Australia",
                "choice3": "New Zealand",
                "choice4": "Canada",
                "rightAnswer": "Ireland",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 115,
                "questionText": "Which city in Turkey is located in Europe and in Asia?",
                "choice1": "Istanbul",
                "choice2": "Pamukulai",
                "choice3": "Dodomar",
                "choice4": "Ankara",
                "rightAnswer": "Istanbul",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 116,
                "questionText": "Montego Bay is off the coast of which country?",
                "choice1": "Barbados",
                "choice2": "Jamaica",
                "choice3": "Trinidad and Tobago",
                "choice4": "Bermuda",
                "rightAnswer": "Jamaica",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 117,
                "questionText": "Where in New York City is the 'Canyon of Heroes', where the famous ticker tape parades take\u00a0place?",
                "choice1": "Fifth Avenue",
                "choice2": "Times Square",
                "choice3": "Lower Broadway",
                "choice4": "Wall Street",
                "rightAnswer": "Lower Broadway",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 118,
                "questionText": "According to the World Health Organisation which capital city has the worst air pollution?",
                "choice1": "London",
                "choice2": "Moscow",
                "choice3": "Mexico City",
                "choice4": "Cairo",
                "rightAnswer": "Mexico City",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 119,
                "questionText": "Who designed the uniform worn by the Vatican City's Swiss Guard?",
                "choice1": "Galileo",
                "choice2": "Michalangelo",
                "choice3": "Raffael",
                "choice4": "Da Vinci",
                "rightAnswer": "Michalangelo",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 120,
                "questionText": "Which Is The Most Densely Populated Country In Europe?",
                "choice1": "Luxembourg",
                "choice2": "Monaco",
                "choice3": "Vatican City",
                "choice4": "Andorra",
                "rightAnswer": "Monaco",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 121,
                "questionText": "What do the citizens of Brussels love to eat with their frites (French fries)?",
                "choice1": "mussels",
                "choice2": "Brussel sprouts",
                "choice3": "savoury sausage",
                "choice4": "eel",
                "rightAnswer": "mussels",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 122,
                "questionText": "The Houses Of Parliament in London is an example of which style of architecture?",
                "choice1": "Gothic",
                "choice2": "Baroque",
                "choice3": "Neo Gothic",
                "choice4": "Art Deco",
                "rightAnswer": "Neo Gothic",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 123,
                "questionText": "The Dominion Parliament buildings in Ottawa are an example of which style of architecture?",
                "choice1": "Neo Gothic",
                "choice2": "Art Deco",
                "choice3": "Roman",
                "choice4": "Renaissance",
                "rightAnswer": "Neo Gothic",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 124,
                "questionText": "In which country is the mountain named\u00a0Annapurna found?",
                "choice1": "Argentina",
                "choice2": "Nepal",
                "choice3": "Russia",
                "choice4": "Switzerland",
                "rightAnswer": "Nepal",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 125,
                "questionText": "In which US state is Area 51?",
                "choice1": "Nevada",
                "choice2": "New Mexico",
                "choice3": "Texas",
                "choice4": "Arizona",
                "rightAnswer": "Nevada",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 126,
                "questionText": "The Bay of Plenty is off the coast of which country?",
                "choice1": "Australia",
                "choice2": "New Zealand",
                "choice3": "Canada",
                "choice4": "South Africa",
                "rightAnswer": "New Zealand",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 127,
                "questionText": "In which country is Mt Cook?",
                "choice1": "New Zealand",
                "choice2": "USA",
                "choice3": "Argentina",
                "choice4": "Canada",
                "rightAnswer": "New Zealand",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 128,
                "questionText": "Into which body of water does the Rhine river flow?",
                "choice1": "Black sea",
                "choice2": "Caspian Sea",
                "choice3": "Baltic Sea",
                "choice4": "North Sea",
                "rightAnswer": "North Sea",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 129,
                "questionText": "In which country is there a town named 'Hell'?",
                "choice1": "Norway",
                "choice2": "Canada",
                "choice3": "Ireland",
                "choice4": "Australia",
                "rightAnswer": "Norway",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 130,
                "questionText": "On what river is the capital city of Canada?",
                "choice1": "Windigo",
                "choice2": "Montreal ",
                "choice3": "Ottawa",
                "choice4": "Winnipeg ",
                "rightAnswer": "Ottawa",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 131,
                "questionText": "The\u00a0mysterious Inca city Machu Picchu is found in which country?",
                "choice1": "Mexico",
                "choice2": "Peru",
                "choice3": "Colombia",
                "choice4": "Chile",
                "rightAnswer": "Peru",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 132,
                "questionText": "Which country does not border Austria?",
                "choice1": "Germany",
                "choice2": "Hungary",
                "choice3": "Czech Rep",
                "choice4": "Poland",
                "rightAnswer": "Poland",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 133,
                "questionText": "With a capacity\u00a0for 220,000 spectators, in which capital city is Strahov, the largest stadium in the world?",
                "choice1": "Vienna",
                "choice2": "Prague",
                "choice3": "Warsaw",
                "choice4": "\u00a0Moscow",
                "rightAnswer": "Prague",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 134,
                "questionText": "In which City would you find St. Peter's Basilica?",
                "choice1": "Madrid",
                "choice2": "Rome",
                "choice3": "Moscow",
                "choice4": "St. Petersburg",
                "rightAnswer": "Rome",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 135,
                "questionText": "Why was the Munich Oktoberfest cancelled in 1923 and 1924?",
                "choice1": "Brewery strike",
                "choice2": "Runaway inflation",
                "choice3": "Civil war",
                "choice4": "Spanish flu",
                "rightAnswer": "Runaway inflation",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 136,
                "questionText": "When motoring west in which city does Route 66 end?",
                "choice1": "Oakland",
                "choice2": "LA",
                "choice3": "San Francisco",
                "choice4": "Santa Monica",
                "rightAnswer": "Santa Monica",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 137,
                "questionText": "In which city is the world famous Jin Mao skyscraper located?",
                "choice1": "Taipei",
                "choice2": "Hong Kong",
                "choice3": "Shanghai",
                "choice4": "Beijing",
                "rightAnswer": "Shanghai",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 138,
                "questionText": "Which metal made the Bolivian city Potosi one of the richest cities in the world in the 17th century?",
                "choice1": "gold",
                "choice2": "aluminium",
                "choice3": "copper",
                "choice4": "silver",
                "rightAnswer": "silver",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 139,
                "questionText": "Which country produces the most gold?",
                "choice1": "South Africa",
                "choice2": "Canada",
                "choice3": "Australia",
                "choice4": "Dem Rep Congo",
                "rightAnswer": "South Africa",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 140,
                "questionText": "The Valdes Peninsula is the lowest point on which continent?",
                "choice1": "South America",
                "choice2": "Europe",
                "choice3": "Antarctic",
                "choice4": "Australia",
                "rightAnswer": "South America",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 141,
                "questionText": "Mount Aconcagua is the highest point on which continent?",
                "choice1": "Australia",
                "choice2": "Asia",
                "choice3": "Antarctic",
                "choice4": "South America",
                "rightAnswer": "South America",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 142,
                "questionText": "In which country is the harbour city Inchon?",
                "choice1": "South Korea",
                "choice2": "Japan",
                "choice3": "India",
                "choice4": "Brazil",
                "rightAnswer": "South Korea",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 143,
                "questionText": "50% of all the men on the Greek island Corfu have which first name?",
                "choice1": "Spiro",
                "choice2": "Stavros",
                "choice3": "Achilles",
                "choice4": "Alexis",
                "rightAnswer": "Spiro",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 144,
                "questionText": "What is the name of the largest star sapphire in the world which\u00a0is found in\u00a0New York City's American Museum of Natural History?",
                "choice1": "Star\u00a0of Africa\u00a0",
                "choice2": "Star of Cairo",
                "choice3": "Star of Bethleham",
                "choice4": "Star of India",
                "rightAnswer": "Star of India",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 145,
                "questionText": "Which country does not border Luxembourg?",
                "choice1": "Switzerland",
                "choice2": "Germany",
                "choice3": "France",
                "choice4": "Belgium",
                "rightAnswer": "Switzerland",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 146,
                "questionText": "In which country is the mountain named\u00a0Jungfrau found?",
                "choice1": "France",
                "choice2": "Switzerland",
                "choice3": "New\u00a0Zealand \u00a0",
                "choice4": "Italy",
                "rightAnswer": "Switzerland",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 147,
                "questionText": "Which country does not border South Africa?",
                "choice1": "Namibia",
                "choice2": "Lesotho",
                "choice3": "Swaziland",
                "choice4": "Tanzania",
                "rightAnswer": "Tanzania",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 148,
                "questionText": "Younge Street,\u00a0the\u00a0longest street in the world, begins in which Canadian\u00a0city?",
                "choice1": "Toronto",
                "choice2": "Quebec City",
                "choice3": "Vancouver",
                "choice4": "Montreal",
                "rightAnswer": "Toronto",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 149,
                "questionText": "The ruins of ancient Carthage are found in the suburbs of which modern city?",
                "choice1": "Cairo",
                "choice2": "Beirut",
                "choice3": "Tunis",
                "choice4": "Tripolis",
                "rightAnswer": "Tunis",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 150,
                "questionText": "Which African country is not a monarchy?",
                "choice1": "Tunisia",
                "choice2": "Morocco",
                "choice3": "Swaziland",
                "choice4": "Lesotho",
                "rightAnswer": "Tunisia",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 151,
                "questionText": "In which country is Mt Ararat?",
                "choice1": "Switzerland",
                "choice2": "Russia",
                "choice3": "Turkey",
                "choice4": "Nepal",
                "rightAnswer": "Turkey",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 152,
                "questionText": "Which country does not border Turkey?",
                "choice1": "Bulgaria",
                "choice2": "Iran",
                "choice3": "Turkmenistan",
                "choice4": "Iraq",
                "rightAnswer": "Turkmenistan",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 153,
                "questionText": "Where does a Halbardier Gaurdsman work?",
                "choice1": "Tower of London",
                "choice2": "Vatican",
                "choice3": "Swiss Border",
                "choice4": "Mt Olympus",
                "rightAnswer": "Vatican",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 154,
                "questionText": "The oldest film festival in the world takes place in which European city?",
                "choice1": "Cannes",
                "choice2": "Edinburgh",
                "choice3": "Berlin",
                "choice4": "Venice",
                "rightAnswer": "Venice",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 155,
                "questionText": "Which goddess of victory is riding a chariot on the Brandenberger Gate in Berlin?",
                "choice1": "Athena",
                "choice2": "Brunhilda",
                "choice3": "Victoria",
                "choice4": "Nike",
                "rightAnswer": "Victoria",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 156,
                "questionText": "What is Europe's longest river? ",
                "choice1": "Volga",
                "choice2": "Rhone",
                "choice3": "Rhine",
                "choice4": "Danube",
                "rightAnswer": "Volga",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 157,
                "questionText": "Which countries name stems from the Germanic word for foreign?",
                "choice1": "Wales",
                "choice2": "Poland",
                "choice3": "Germany",
                "choice4": "Spain",
                "rightAnswer": "Wales",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 158,
                "questionText": "With 1,000 plus rooms, what is the largest inhabited castle in the world?",
                "choice1": "The\u00a0Alhambra",
                "choice2": "Edinburgh Castle",
                "choice3": "Warwich Castle",
                "choice4": "Windsor Castle",
                "rightAnswer": "Windsor Castle",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 159,
                "questionText": "During a\u00a0WWII air raid\u00a0the firemen in Freiburg im Breisgau used what\u00a0to put out the fire in the historic Kaufhaus after they ran out of water?",
                "choice1": "milk",
                "choice2": "beer",
                "choice3": "wine",
                "choice4": "schnapps",
                "rightAnswer": "wine",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 160,
                "questionText": "How many months does the average American spend in a lifetime waiting at a red light?",
                "choice1": 1,
                "choice2": 6,
                "choice3": 18,
                "choice4": 12,
                "rightAnswer": 6,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 161,
                "questionText": "How many countries lie between Mexico and Colombia?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 7,
                "choice3": 10,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 7,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 162,
                "questionText": "How many hours a month does the average American spend in a shopping mall?",
                "choice1": 48,
                "choice2": 12,
                "choice3": 24,
                "choice4": 6,
                "rightAnswer": 12,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 163,
                "questionText": "How many countries border Russia?",
                "choice1": 8,
                "choice2": 19,
                "choice3": 14,
                "choice4": 25,
                "rightAnswer": 14,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 164,
                "questionText": "How many countries border China?",
                "choice1": 26,
                "choice2": 16,
                "choice3": 7,
                "choice4": 10,
                "rightAnswer": 16,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 165,
                "questionText": "How many people live on Ellesmere Island, the 10th largest island in the world?",
                "choice1": 10106,
                "choice2": 106,
                "choice3": 6,
                "choice4": 1106,
                "rightAnswer": 106,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 166,
                "questionText": "How many rooms are there in the White House?",
                "choice1": 72,
                "choice2": 132,
                "choice3": 272,
                "choice4": 32,
                "rightAnswer": 132,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 167,
                "questionText": "How many lakes are there in Finland?",
                "choice1": 8880,
                "choice2": 887880,
                "choice3": 187880,
                "choice4": 87880,
                "rightAnswer": 187880,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 168,
                "questionText": "According to the UN how many people in the world are starving?",
                "choice1": 820000000,
                "choice2": 82000000,
                "choice3": "1.5 billion",
                "choice4": 420000000,
                "rightAnswer": 820000000,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 169,
                "questionText": "Most sources claim that Route 66 is how many miles all the way?",
                "choice1": "2,848 miles",
                "choice2": "2,448 miles",
                "choice3": "1,848 miles",
                "choice4": "3,448 miles",
                "rightAnswer": "2,448 miles",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 170,
                "questionText": "To the nearest thousand square kilometres what is the land area of Wales?",
                "choice1": "5,000 sq km",
                "choice2": "21,000 sq km",
                "choice3": "100,100 sq km",
                "choice4": "51,000 sq km",
                "rightAnswer": "21,000 sq km",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 171,
                "questionText": "What is the population of Saudi Arabia?",
                "choice1": "3.2 million",
                "choice2": "22.million",
                "choice3": "65.2 million",
                "choice4": "123.3 million",
                "rightAnswer": "22.million",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 172,
                "questionText": "The salt content in the Dead Sea which enables a swimmer to float like a cork is how many times higher than that of the Atlantic ocean?",
                "choice1": "7X",
                "choice2": "2X",
                "choice3": "22X",
                "choice4": "77x",
                "rightAnswer": "7X",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 173,
                "questionText": "The Bridge of Sighs in Venice connected \u00a0the Doge's Palace with what?",
                "choice1": "A tax office",
                "choice2": "A hospital",
                "choice3": "A Turkish bath house",
                "choice4": "A state prison and place of execution",
                "rightAnswer": "A state prison and place of execution",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 174,
                "questionText": "Which European city is nicknamed the 'Granite City'?",
                "choice1": "Aberdeen",
                "choice2": "The Vatican",
                "choice3": "Lisbon",
                "choice4": "Munich",
                "rightAnswer": "Aberdeen",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 175,
                "questionText": "The crown of the Empire State building was originally built for which purpose?",
                "choice1": "weather station",
                "choice2": "airship dock",
                "choice3": "flag pole",
                "choice4": "firemans lookout",
                "rightAnswer": "airship dock",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 176,
                "questionText": "The Vinson Massive is the highest point on which continent?",
                "choice1": "South America",
                "choice2": "Antarctic",
                "choice3": "Australia",
                "choice4": "Europe",
                "rightAnswer": "Antarctic",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 177,
                "questionText": "In which country is the mountain named\u00a0Aconcagua found?",
                "choice1": "Argentina",
                "choice2": "Mexico",
                "choice3": "Switzerland",
                "choice4": "Nepal",
                "rightAnswer": "Argentina",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 178,
                "questionText": "Which country produces the most opals?",
                "choice1": "India",
                "choice2": "USA",
                "choice3": "Australia",
                "choice4": "Russia",
                "rightAnswer": "Australia",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 179,
                "questionText": "Mount Kosciusko is the highest point on which continent?",
                "choice1": "Antarctic",
                "choice2": "Australia",
                "choice3": "Africa",
                "choice4": "Europe",
                "rightAnswer": "Australia",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 180,
                "questionText": "Red, as in Red Square, was the old Slavic synonym for what?",
                "choice1": "power",
                "choice2": "death",
                "choice3": "beauty",
                "choice4": "wealth",
                "rightAnswer": "beauty",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 181,
                "questionText": "Into which body of water does the Danube river flow?",
                "choice1": "Black Sea",
                "choice2": "Baltic Sea",
                "choice3": "North Sea",
                "choice4": "Caspian Sea",
                "rightAnswer": "Black Sea",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 182,
                "questionText": "Which country does not have a bird on its flag?",
                "choice1": "Brazil",
                "choice2": "Dominican Rep",
                "choice3": "Mexico",
                "choice4": "Eygpt",
                "rightAnswer": "Brazil",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 183,
                "questionText": "In which county is chequers, the prime ministers country residence?",
                "choice1": "Buckinghamshire",
                "choice2": "Oxfordshire",
                "choice3": "Middlesex",
                "choice4": "Surrey",
                "rightAnswer": "Buckinghamshire",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 184,
                "questionText": "Lake Tahoe is on the border of Nevada and which other US state?",
                "choice1": "California",
                "choice2": "Arizona",
                "choice3": "Oregon",
                "choice4": "Utah",
                "rightAnswer": "California",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 185,
                "questionText": "The Gothic Chartes Cathedral in France\u00a0has famous stained glass windows which produce which unique colour?\u00a0",
                "choice1": "Chartes Green",
                "choice2": "Chartes Blue",
                "choice3": "Chartes Red",
                "choice4": "Chartes White",
                "rightAnswer": "Chartes Blue",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 186,
                "questionText": "In which country is the port of Odense?",
                "choice1": "Norway",
                "choice2": "Sweden",
                "choice3": "Denmark",
                "choice4": "Finland",
                "rightAnswer": "Denmark",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 187,
                "questionText": "Which country's name means Sunday?",
                "choice1": "Australia\u00a0",
                "choice2": "Canada",
                "choice3": "Russia",
                "choice4": "Dominica",
                "rightAnswer": "Dominica",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 188,
                "questionText": "The highest mountain in Japan is Mount Fuji. What does Fuji mean?\u00a0",
                "choice1": "harmony",
                "choice2": "snow",
                "choice3": "beauty",
                "choice4": "fire",
                "rightAnswer": "fire",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 189,
                "questionText": "The only person with 5 stars for excellence on the\u00a0Hollywood Boulevard\u00a0Walk Of Fame?",
                "choice1": "Gene Autry",
                "choice2": "George Burns",
                "choice3": "Bing Crosby",
                "choice4": "Diana Ross",
                "rightAnswer": "Gene Autry",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 190,
                "questionText": "Which country does not border Slovakia?",
                "choice1": "Austria",
                "choice2": "Poland",
                "choice3": "Germany",
                "choice4": "Hungary",
                "rightAnswer": "Germany",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 191,
                "questionText": "In which country does the volcano Unzen grumble?",
                "choice1": "Philippines",
                "choice2": "Japan",
                "choice3": "Iceland",
                "choice4": "Indonesia",
                "rightAnswer": "Japan",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 192,
                "questionText": "Who was the\u00a0Hollywood star\u00a0who used his nose rather than hands or feet to make an impression\u00a0in the sidewalk in front of 'Grauman's Chinese'?\u00a0\u00a0",
                "choice1": "Lassie",
                "choice2": "Bob Hope",
                "choice3": "Jimmy Durante",
                "choice4": "Karl Malden",
                "rightAnswer": "Jimmy Durante",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 193,
                "questionText": "In which country does the volcano Mt Pelee grumble?",
                "choice1": "Iceland",
                "choice2": "USA",
                "choice3": "Martinique",
                "choice4": "Italy",
                "rightAnswer": "Martinique",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 194,
                "questionText": "Which country produces the most silver?",
                "choice1": "Brazil",
                "choice2": "USA",
                "choice3": "Mexico",
                "choice4": "Canada",
                "rightAnswer": "Mexico",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 195,
                "questionText": "In which country does the volcano Popocatepetl grumble?",
                "choice1": "Greece",
                "choice2": "Indonesia",
                "choice3": "Mexico",
                "choice4": "Colombia",
                "rightAnswer": "Mexico",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 196,
                "questionText": "Which country does not border Libya?",
                "choice1": "Tunisia",
                "choice2": "Morocco",
                "choice3": "Eygpt",
                "choice4": "Algeria",
                "rightAnswer": "Morocco",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 197,
                "questionText": "What is the most populated city north of the arctic circle?",
                "choice1": "Ottawa",
                "choice2": "Aberdeen",
                "choice3": "Murmansk",
                "choice4": "Fairbanks",
                "rightAnswer": "Murmansk",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 198,
                "questionText": "In which country does the volcano Ruapehu grumble?",
                "choice1": "New Zealand",
                "choice2": "Indonesia",
                "choice3": "USA",
                "choice4": "Japan",
                "rightAnswer": "New Zealand",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 199,
                "questionText": "According to the 'Global Peace Index' what is the safest country in the world?",
                "choice1": "Australia",
                "choice2": "Norway",
                "choice3": "Canada",
                "choice4": "Switzerland",
                "rightAnswer": "Norway",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 200,
                "questionText": "The Taj Mahal. Taj means 'crown', what does Mahal mean?",
                "choice1": "queen",
                "choice2": "palace",
                "choice3": "crypt",
                "choice4": "king",
                "rightAnswer": "palace",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 201,
                "questionText": "Which street in London takes its name from a croquet like game once played by Charles I ?",
                "choice1": "Portobello",
                "choice2": "Pall Mall",
                "choice3": "Threadneedle",
                "choice4": "Piccadilly",
                "rightAnswer": "Pall Mall",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 202,
                "questionText": "Which\u00a0'street' in London\u00a0takes its name from the\u00a0ornamental collars once\u00a0made by the\u00a0 17th century tailor Robert Baker?",
                "choice1": "Threadneedle",
                "choice2": "Piccadilly",
                "choice3": "Pall Mall",
                "choice4": "Carnaby",
                "rightAnswer": "Piccadilly",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 203,
                "questionText": "Which country produces the most amber?",
                "choice1": "Canada",
                "choice2": "China",
                "choice3": "Poland",
                "choice4": "India",
                "rightAnswer": "Poland",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 204,
                "questionText": "The largest industrial complex in the world in the 19th century was found in which English harbour city?",
                "choice1": "Dover",
                "choice2": "Liverpool",
                "choice3": "Newcastle",
                "choice4": "Portsmouth",
                "rightAnswer": "Portsmouth",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 205,
                "questionText": "Which country is not on the shores of Lake Victoria?",
                "choice1": "Tanzania",
                "choice2": "Uganda",
                "choice3": "Kenya",
                "choice4": "Rwanda",
                "rightAnswer": "Rwanda",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 206,
                "questionText": "The most visited city in Brittany has the\u00a0highest ratio\u00a0of sea food restaurants in Europe. Which port city is it?",
                "choice1": "Saint Malo",
                "choice2": "Rennes",
                "choice3": "Lannion",
                "choice4": "Brest",
                "rightAnswer": "Saint Malo",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 207,
                "questionText": "A native indian\u00a0legend claims that the scored marks that run down the side of Devil's Tower in Wyoming were gouged by a giant bear that was trying to reach what?",
                "choice1": "Seven stranded\u00a0young maidens",
                "choice2": "His own shadow",
                "choice3": "The other end of the rainbow",
                "choice4": "The honey coloured sun\u00a0",
                "rightAnswer": "Seven stranded\u00a0young maidens",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 208,
                "questionText": "What are the winds called below the latitude 60 degrees south?",
                "choice1": "Shrieking 60s",
                "choice2": "Screaming 60s",
                "choice3": "Sullen 60s",
                "choice4": "Scary 60s",
                "rightAnswer": "Shrieking 60s",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 209,
                "questionText": "Which Saint is not a US Virgin Island?",
                "choice1": "St John",
                "choice2": "St Croix",
                "choice3": "St Vincent",
                "choice4": "St Thomas",
                "rightAnswer": "St Vincent",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 210,
                "questionText": "Which country does not border Syria?",
                "choice1": "Isreal",
                "choice2": "Turkey",
                "choice3": "Lebanon",
                "choice4": "Sudan",
                "rightAnswer": "Sudan",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 211,
                "questionText": "In which South American country would you find the city New Amsterdam?",
                "choice1": "Ecuador",
                "choice2": "Surinam",
                "choice3": "Guyana",
                "choice4": "Brazil",
                "rightAnswer": "Surinam",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 212,
                "questionText": "What\u00a0is found on the flag of Rwanda?",
                "choice1": "An Assualt Rifle",
                "choice2": "A Star",
                "choice3": "The letter 'R'",
                "choice4": "A Half Moon",
                "rightAnswer": "The letter 'R'",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 213,
                "questionText": "In which country does the volcano Kilauea grumble?",
                "choice1": "Japan",
                "choice2": "Spain",
                "choice3": "USA",
                "choice4": "Iceland",
                "rightAnswer": "USA",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Geography",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 214,
                "questionText": "How many seats did the Spitfire fighter plane have?",
                "choice1": 2,
                "choice2": 3,
                "choice3": 1,
                "choice4": "None",
                "rightAnswer": 1,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 215,
                "questionText": "How many wives did Henry VIII have?",
                "choice1": 8,
                "choice2": 6,
                "choice3": 5,
                "choice4": 4,
                "rightAnswer": 6,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 216,
                "questionText": "\u00a0How many years\u00a0did the '21\u00a0Year War'\u00a0\u00a0between Sweden and Russia last?\u00a0",
                "choice1": 21,
                "choice2": 2,
                "choice3": 55,
                "choice4": 103,
                "rightAnswer": 21,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 217,
                "questionText": "How many pennies were there in a pre decimal pound?",
                "choice1": 100,
                "choice2": 200,
                "choice3": 240,
                "choice4": 140,
                "rightAnswer": 240,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 218,
                "questionText": "In which year was the Gunpowder Plot?",
                "choice1": 1605,
                "choice2": 1505,
                "choice3": 1805,
                "choice4": 1705,
                "rightAnswer": 1605,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 219,
                "questionText": "What year saw Adolph Hitler committing suicide?",
                "choice1": 1946,
                "choice2": 1945,
                "choice3": 1947,
                "choice4": 1944,
                "rightAnswer": 1945,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 220,
                "questionText": "In which year did JFK get assassinated?",
                "choice1": 1963,
                "choice2": 1966,
                "choice3": 1968,
                "choice4": 1960,
                "rightAnswer": 1963,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 221,
                "questionText": "In what year was the Falkland war?",
                "choice1": 1984,
                "choice2": 1980,
                "choice3": 1982,
                "choice4": 1978,
                "rightAnswer": 1982,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 222,
                "questionText": "In which year did a US-led coalition invade Iraq?",
                "choice1": 1999,
                "choice2": 2005,
                "choice3": 2001,
                "choice4": 2003,
                "rightAnswer": 2003,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 223,
                "questionText": "Which country did the USSR invade in 1979?",
                "choice1": "Iran",
                "choice2": "China",
                "choice3": "Afghanistan",
                "choice4": "Iraq",
                "rightAnswer": "Afghanistan",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 224,
                "questionText": "What was banned in USA in January 1920?",
                "choice1": "Gambling",
                "choice2": "Strikes",
                "choice3": "Smoking",
                "choice4": "Alcohol",
                "rightAnswer": "Alcohol",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 225,
                "questionText": "One of the ancient world wonders, the 'Hanging Gardens', was found in which city?",
                "choice1": "Alexandria",
                "choice2": "Athens",
                "choice3": "Rome",
                "choice4": "Babylon",
                "rightAnswer": "Babylon",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 226,
                "questionText": "What was named after a hydrogen bomb test?",
                "choice1": "Bikini",
                "choice2": "Matchbox",
                "choice3": "Frisbee",
                "choice4": "Hoola Hoop",
                "rightAnswer": "Bikini",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 227,
                "questionText": "Robben Island was a prison near which city?",
                "choice1": "Athens",
                "choice2": "San Francisco",
                "choice3": "Exeter",
                "choice4": "Cape Town",
                "rightAnswer": "Cape Town",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 228,
                "questionText": "Iceland and the Uk were caught up in which war?",
                "choice1": "Salmon",
                "choice2": "Lobster",
                "choice3": "Herring",
                "choice4": "Cod",
                "rightAnswer": "Cod",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 229,
                "questionText": "King William the Bastard was also known by which other name?",
                "choice1": "Conqueror",
                "choice2": "Orange",
                "choice3": "Rufus",
                "choice4": "Young King",
                "rightAnswer": "Conqueror",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 230,
                "questionText": "Of which country was Greenland a colony until 1981?",
                "choice1": "Denmark",
                "choice2": "Iceland",
                "choice3": "Russia",
                "choice4": "Sweden",
                "rightAnswer": "Denmark",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 231,
                "questionText": "The patron saint of England is famous for killing which type of creature?",
                "choice1": "Dragon",
                "choice2": "Devil",
                "choice3": "Unicorn",
                "choice4": "Angel",
                "rightAnswer": "Dragon",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 232,
                "questionText": "William Kemmler, back in 1890, was the first person to be killed using what lethal method?",
                "choice1": "Electric Chair",
                "choice2": "Radiation",
                "choice3": "Lethal Injection",
                "choice4": "Death by Firing Squad",
                "rightAnswer": "Electric Chair",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 233,
                "questionText": "What was special about Louise Brown, born July 25, 1978 in England?",
                "choice1": "First surviving 20 week old foetus",
                "choice2": "First test tube baby",
                "choice3": "First surviving separated Siamese twin",
                "choice4": "First surrogate mother",
                "rightAnswer": "First test tube baby",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 234,
                "questionText": "During the second world war in Germany it was forbidden to give a horse which name?",
                "choice1": "Mussolini",
                "choice2": "Hitler",
                "choice3": "Stalin",
                "choice4": "Winston",
                "rightAnswer": "Hitler",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 235,
                "questionText": "Who shot Lee Harvey Oswald?",
                "choice1": "Jack Ruby",
                "choice2": "Jack Diamond",
                "choice3": "Jack Sapphire",
                "choice4": "Jack Emerald",
                "rightAnswer": "Jack Ruby",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 236,
                "questionText": "What was the first name of the US President known by the nickname JFK?",
                "choice1": "Jerry",
                "choice2": "John",
                "choice3": "Jack",
                "choice4": "Joe",
                "rightAnswer": "John",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 237,
                "questionText": "Which explorer was the first to circumnavigate the globe?",
                "choice1": "Columbus",
                "choice2": "Drake",
                "choice3": "Marco Polo",
                "choice4": "Magellan",
                "rightAnswer": "Magellan",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 238,
                "questionText": "What species were Benjy and Laska, who were sent into space in 1958?",
                "choice1": "Cats",
                "choice2": "Rats",
                "choice3": "Monkeys",
                "choice4": "Mice",
                "rightAnswer": "Mice",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 239,
                "questionText": "Which European country is ruled by The House of Orange?",
                "choice1": "Netherlands",
                "choice2": "Norway",
                "choice3": "Sweden",
                "choice4": "Belgium",
                "rightAnswer": "Netherlands",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 240,
                "questionText": "What was the name of Christopher Columbus' smallest\u00a0 ship?",
                "choice1": "Tina",
                "choice2": "Mina",
                "choice3": "Gina",
                "choice4": "Nina",
                "rightAnswer": "Nina",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 241,
                "questionText": "What nationality was Roald Amundsen, the first man to reach the South Pole?",
                "choice1": "Dutch",
                "choice2": "Swedish",
                "choice3": "Belgian",
                "choice4": "Norwegian",
                "rightAnswer": "Norwegian",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 242,
                "questionText": "In what industry did John Davidson Rockefeller get rich?",
                "choice1": "Movie",
                "choice2": "Oil",
                "choice3": "Music",
                "choice4": "Motor",
                "rightAnswer": "Oil",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 243,
                "questionText": "Who was Pakistan's President in 2006?",
                "choice1": "Nawaz Sharif",
                "choice2": "Pratibha Patil",
                "choice3": "Benazir Bhutto",
                "choice4": "Pervez Musharraf",
                "rightAnswer": "Pervez Musharraf",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 244,
                "questionText": "Which organisation was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1917?",
                "choice1": "Fathers for Justice",
                "choice2": "The Red Cross",
                "choice3": "The Police",
                "choice4": "The Boy Scouts",
                "rightAnswer": "The Red Cross",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 245,
                "questionText": "What was 10th century English king Ethelred's nickname?",
                "choice1": "The Unshaven",
                "choice2": "The Unlucky",
                "choice3": "The Unsweetened",
                "choice4": "The Unready",
                "rightAnswer": "The Unready",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 246,
                "questionText": "Queen Elizabeth I of England was also known by which name?",
                "choice1": "The virgin queen",
                "choice2": "The ginger queen",
                "choice3": "Bloody queen Elizabeth",
                "choice4": "The Richmond queen",
                "rightAnswer": "The virgin queen",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 247,
                "questionText": "What weather phenomenon was the Norse god Thor thought to control? ",
                "choice1": "Lightening",
                "choice2": "Typhoon",
                "choice3": "Earthquakes",
                "choice4": "Thunder",
                "rightAnswer": "Thunder",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 248,
                "questionText": "King Henry VII of England was a member of which royal house?",
                "choice1": "York",
                "choice2": "Stuart",
                "choice3": "Lancaster",
                "choice4": "Tudor",
                "rightAnswer": "Tudor",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 249,
                "questionText": "Which Swedish motor vehicle manufacturer acquired the Dutch company DAF in the mid-1970s?",
                "choice1": "Saab",
                "choice2": "Ford",
                "choice3": "Dacia",
                "choice4": "Volvo",
                "rightAnswer": "Volvo",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 250,
                "questionText": "Where did Napoleon Bonaparte suffer his last defeat? ",
                "choice1": "Waterloo",
                "choice2": "Elba",
                "choice3": "Leipzig",
                "choice4": "Rome",
                "rightAnswer": "Waterloo",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 251,
                "questionText": "How many baths did Louis XIV take in his lifetime?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 51,
                "choice3": 1,
                "choice4": 0,
                "rightAnswer": 3,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 252,
                "questionText": "How many brothers and sisters did John F. Kennedy have?",
                "choice1": 8,
                "choice2": 3,
                "choice3": 2,
                "choice4": 0,
                "rightAnswer": 8,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 253,
                "questionText": "How many days were there in\u00a0one week in ancient Roman times?",
                "choice1": 8,
                "choice2": 10,
                "choice3": 6,
                "choice4": 7,
                "rightAnswer": 8,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 254,
                "questionText": "Out of every 10 women in Scotland, how many were pregnant on their wedding day, according to a Royal Commission of 1868?",
                "choice1": 2,
                "choice2": 0,
                "choice3": 9,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 9,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 255,
                "questionText": "How many kings of England have been named Edward? ",
                "choice1": 4,
                "choice2": 7,
                "choice3": 9,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 9,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 256,
                "questionText": "How many people are there in a US Grand Jury?",
                "choice1": 11,
                "choice2": 12,
                "choice3": 23,
                "choice4": 17,
                "rightAnswer": 23,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 257,
                "questionText": "An estimated how many Popes have been murdered?",
                "choice1": 13,
                "choice2": 46,
                "choice3": 26,
                "choice4": 6,
                "rightAnswer": 26,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 258,
                "questionText": "How many days was William Harrison President of the United States?",
                "choice1": 16,
                "choice2": 8,
                "choice3": 64,
                "choice4": 32,
                "rightAnswer": 32,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 259,
                "questionText": "How many years were there between the Silver Jubilees of George V and Elizabeth II? ",
                "choice1": 42,
                "choice2": 32,
                "choice3": 52,
                "choice4": 62,
                "rightAnswer": 42,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 260,
                "questionText": "How many km long was the Berlin Wall?",
                "choice1": 82,
                "choice2": 42,
                "choice3": 12,
                "choice4": 22,
                "rightAnswer": 42,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 261,
                "questionText": "For how many years did Queen Victoria reign?",
                "choice1": 53,
                "choice2": 63,
                "choice3": 73,
                "choice4": 43,
                "rightAnswer": 63,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 262,
                "questionText": "In Roman Numerals what does LXX stand for?",
                "choice1": 1200,
                "choice2": 70,
                "choice3": 60,
                "choice4": 120,
                "rightAnswer": 70,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 263,
                "questionText": "How many pilgrims left Plymouth for America on the Mayflower?",
                "choice1": 202,
                "choice2": 64,
                "choice3": 104,
                "choice4": 264,
                "rightAnswer": 104,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 264,
                "questionText": "How many years did the 'One Hundred Years War' last?",
                "choice1": 144,
                "choice2": 114,
                "choice3": 100,
                "choice4": 99,
                "rightAnswer": 114,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 265,
                "questionText": "How many minutes did Neil Armstrong spend on the moon?",
                "choice1": 1162,
                "choice2": 62,
                "choice3": 12,
                "choice4": 152,
                "rightAnswer": 152,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 266,
                "questionText": "According to Forbes new Rich List for 2009, how many billionares are there in the world?\u00a0",
                "choice1": 241,
                "choice2": 5205,
                "choice3": 793,
                "choice4": 2355,
                "rightAnswer": 793,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 267,
                "questionText": "In which year did King Richard the 'lionhearted' die?",
                "choice1": 99,
                "choice2": 1599,
                "choice3": 599,
                "choice4": 1199,
                "rightAnswer": 1199,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 268,
                "questionText": "In which year did Henry VIII die?",
                "choice1": 1647,
                "choice2": 1597,
                "choice3": 1507,
                "choice4": 1547,
                "rightAnswer": 1547,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 269,
                "questionText": "What number on Pennsylvania Avenue would you find the white house?",
                "choice1": 1200,
                "choice2": 2000,
                "choice3": 1800,
                "choice4": 1600,
                "rightAnswer": 1600,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 270,
                "questionText": "In which year was St Pauls cathedral completed?",
                "choice1": 1911,
                "choice2": 1711,
                "choice3": 1611,
                "choice4": 1811,
                "rightAnswer": 1711,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 271,
                "questionText": "In which year was the revolver invented?",
                "choice1": 1835,
                "choice2": 1802,
                "choice3": 1888,
                "choice4": 1788,
                "rightAnswer": 1835,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 272,
                "questionText": "The Spanish Dublone was legal tender in the USA until which year?",
                "choice1": 1777,
                "choice2": 1657,
                "choice3": 1927,
                "choice4": 1857,
                "rightAnswer": 1857,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 273,
                "questionText": "In which year did electricity replace steam powered locomotives in the London Underground?",
                "choice1": 1910,
                "choice2": 1890,
                "choice3": 1850,
                "choice4": 1930,
                "rightAnswer": 1890,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 274,
                "questionText": "In which year was the Tower Bridge in London completed?",
                "choice1": 1794,
                "choice2": 1911,
                "choice3": 1894,
                "choice4": 1811,
                "rightAnswer": 1894,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 275,
                "questionText": "What year did the infamous San Francisco earthquake take place?",
                "choice1": 1906,
                "choice2": 1916,
                "choice3": 1926,
                "choice4": 1896,
                "rightAnswer": 1906,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 276,
                "questionText": "In which year was the first successful Channel crossing by an airplane?",
                "choice1": 1913,
                "choice2": 1909,
                "choice3": 1903,
                "choice4": 1897,
                "rightAnswer": 1909,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 277,
                "questionText": "In which year did the Titanic sink?",
                "choice1": 1909,
                "choice2": 1912,
                "choice3": 1905,
                "choice4": 1915,
                "rightAnswer": 1912,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 278,
                "questionText": "In which year was the infamous 'black sox' scandal?",
                "choice1": 1929,
                "choice2": 1939,
                "choice3": 1919,
                "choice4": 1909,
                "rightAnswer": 1919,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 279,
                "questionText": "In what year was Mahatma Gandhi assassinated?",
                "choice1": 1942,
                "choice2": 1948,
                "choice3": 1938,
                "choice4": 1950,
                "rightAnswer": 1948,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 280,
                "questionText": "In which year was the first successful heart transplant performed?",
                "choice1": 1947,
                "choice2": 1967,
                "choice3": 1957,
                "choice4": 1977,
                "rightAnswer": 1967,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 281,
                "questionText": "In which year was Prince Charles invested as The Prince of Wales?",
                "choice1": 1989,
                "choice2": 1969,
                "choice3": 1959,
                "choice4": 1979,
                "rightAnswer": 1969,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 282,
                "questionText": "In which year did the Rainbow Warrior sink?",
                "choice1": 1986,
                "choice2": 1985,
                "choice3": 1984,
                "choice4": 1987,
                "rightAnswer": 1985,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 283,
                "questionText": "In which year was Rajiv Gandhi assassinated?",
                "choice1": 1981,
                "choice2": 1991,
                "choice3": 1971,
                "choice4": 2001,
                "rightAnswer": 1991,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 284,
                "questionText": "In which year was the EURO TUNNEL officially opened?",
                "choice1": 1994,
                "choice2": 1990,
                "choice3": 1998,
                "choice4": 1986,
                "rightAnswer": 1994,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 285,
                "questionText": "What was the worlds population in AD 1?",
                "choice1": "1 billion",
                "choice2": 25000000,
                "choice3": 500000000,
                "choice4": 200000000,
                "rightAnswer": 200000000,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 286,
                "questionText": "Which amendment of the US constitution abolished slavery?",
                "choice1": "10th",
                "choice2": "9th",
                "choice3": "13th",
                "choice4": "18th",
                "rightAnswer": "13th",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 287,
                "questionText": "For how long did Queen Jane rule England?",
                "choice1": "9 days",
                "choice2": "9 years",
                "choice3": "9 months",
                "choice4": "9 weeks",
                "rightAnswer": "9 days",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 288,
                "questionText": "According to an old legend, who can't shed more than 3 tears?",
                "choice1": "a King",
                "choice2": "a lawyer",
                "choice3": "a witch",
                "choice4": "a bride\u00a0",
                "rightAnswer": "a witch",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 289,
                "questionText": "Who was the 2nd man in space?",
                "choice1": "Alan Shepard",
                "choice2": "John Glenn",
                "choice3": "Scott Carpenter",
                "choice4": "Virgil Grissom",
                "rightAnswer": "Alan Shepard",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 290,
                "questionText": "King Zog ruled which country?",
                "choice1": "Prussia",
                "choice2": "Albania",
                "choice3": "Russia",
                "choice4": "Persia",
                "rightAnswer": "Albania",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 291,
                "questionText": "What was the name of the research ship Charles Darwin travelled with?",
                "choice1": "Turtle",
                "choice2": "Beagle",
                "choice3": "Eagle",
                "choice4": "Mermaid",
                "rightAnswer": "Beagle",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 292,
                "questionText": "Charles Darwin was a passenger on which research ship?",
                "choice1": "Albatross",
                "choice2": "Beagle",
                "choice3": "Dolphin",
                "choice4": "Eagle",
                "rightAnswer": "Beagle",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 293,
                "questionText": "In which city was the Titanic built?",
                "choice1": "Belfast",
                "choice2": "Liverpool",
                "choice3": "Glasgow",
                "choice4": "Southampton",
                "rightAnswer": "Belfast",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 294,
                "questionText": "Who was not the mayor of a US town?",
                "choice1": "Bruce Willis",
                "choice2": "Anthony Hopkins",
                "choice3": "Clint Eastwood",
                "choice4": "Sony Bono",
                "rightAnswer": "Bruce Willis",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 295,
                "questionText": "Which ship was the first to arrive and rescue\u00a0Titanic survivors?",
                "choice1": "Arizona",
                "choice2": "Carpathia",
                "choice3": "George Washington",
                "choice4": "Bremen",
                "rightAnswer": "Carpathia",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 296,
                "questionText": "Which animal\u00a0is not a Chinese year?",
                "choice1": "Rooster",
                "choice2": "Dragon",
                "choice3": "Cat",
                "choice4": "Pig",
                "rightAnswer": "Cat",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 297,
                "questionText": "Who was the first wife of King Henry VIII?",
                "choice1": "Anne Boleyn",
                "choice2": "Jane Seymour",
                "choice3": "Catherine of Aragon",
                "choice4": "Anne of Cleeves",
                "rightAnswer": "Catherine of Aragon",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 298,
                "questionText": "Which English Monarch succeeded James I?",
                "choice1": "Charles I",
                "choice2": "James II",
                "choice3": "Mary II",
                "choice4": "William III",
                "rightAnswer": "Charles I",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 299,
                "questionText": "The Gregorian Calendar was adopted by which country in 1912?",
                "choice1": "Persia",
                "choice2": "China",
                "choice3": "Ireland",
                "choice4": "India",
                "rightAnswer": "China",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 300,
                "questionText": "Which country was not a Portugese colony?",
                "choice1": "Angola",
                "choice2": "Colombia",
                "choice3": "Brazil",
                "choice4": "Mozambique",
                "rightAnswer": "Colombia",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 301,
                "questionText": "Which word from the inaugural address by Barack Obama was cut out of the speech whilst being broadcast in China?",
                "choice1": "Tibet",
                "choice2": "Earthquakes",
                "choice3": "Chinese",
                "choice4": "Communism",
                "rightAnswer": "Communism",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 302,
                "questionText": "What was the name of Wellington's horse?",
                "choice1": "Washington",
                "choice2": "Paris",
                "choice3": "Rome",
                "choice4": "Copenhagen",
                "rightAnswer": "Copenhagen",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 303,
                "questionText": "Florence Nightingale achieved fame during which war?",
                "choice1": "Boer War",
                "choice2": "Crimean",
                "choice3": "First World War",
                "choice4": "100 Years War",
                "rightAnswer": "Crimean",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 304,
                "questionText": "Which animal is not a Chinese year?",
                "choice1": "Ox",
                "choice2": "Monkey",
                "choice3": "Pig",
                "choice4": "Crow",
                "rightAnswer": "Crow",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 305,
                "questionText": "Which animal is not a Chinese year?\u00a0",
                "choice1": "Goat",
                "choice2": "Dolphin",
                "choice3": "Monkey",
                "choice4": "Dog",
                "rightAnswer": "Dolphin",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 306,
                "questionText": "Which English King died in 1553 at the age of 15?",
                "choice1": "Edward VII",
                "choice2": "Edward IV",
                "choice3": "Edward V",
                "choice4": "Edward VI",
                "rightAnswer": "Edward VI",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 307,
                "questionText": "The crown of which New York City landmark was originally built as an airship dock?",
                "choice1": "Trump Tower",
                "choice2": "Chrysler Building",
                "choice3": "Empire State Building",
                "choice4": "Statue of Liberty",
                "rightAnswer": "Empire State Building",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 308,
                "questionText": "What was the 1969 war between El Salvador and Honduras called?",
                "choice1": "cod",
                "choice2": "football",
                "choice3": "cola",
                "choice4": "postage stamp",
                "rightAnswer": "football",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 309,
                "questionText": "Which English King bought Buckingham Palace?",
                "choice1": "Charles II",
                "choice2": "George II",
                "choice3": "Charles I",
                "choice4": "George III",
                "rightAnswer": "George III",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 310,
                "questionText": "Which US President said \"I cannot tell a lie\"?",
                "choice1": "Bill Clinton",
                "choice2": "Richard Nixon",
                "choice3": "George W Bush",
                "choice4": "George. Washington",
                "rightAnswer": "George. Washington",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 311,
                "questionText": "Which language did King George I speak?",
                "choice1": "Latin",
                "choice2": "German",
                "choice3": "French",
                "choice4": "Russian",
                "rightAnswer": "German",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 312,
                "questionText": "Which King Harold died during the battle of Hastings?",
                "choice1": "Godwinson",
                "choice2": "Ironside",
                "choice3": "the Elder",
                "choice4": "Harefoot",
                "rightAnswer": "Godwinson",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 313,
                "questionText": "Which ancient world wonder was found in Giza?",
                "choice1": "Statue Of Zeus",
                "choice2": "Great Pyramid",
                "choice3": "Lighthouse",
                "choice4": "Temple Of Artemis",
                "rightAnswer": "Great Pyramid",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 314,
                "questionText": "What was Ehrich Weiss better known as?",
                "choice1": "David Copperfield ",
                "choice2": "The Great Suprendo",
                "choice3": "Harry Houdini",
                "choice4": "Charlie Chaplin",
                "rightAnswer": "Harry Houdini",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 315,
                "questionText": "On which island was Capt Cook killed in 1779?",
                "choice1": "Australia",
                "choice2": "Moluccan Islands",
                "choice3": "Hawaii",
                "choice4": "New\u00a0Zealand",
                "rightAnswer": "Hawaii",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 316,
                "questionText": "The\u00a0falsely accused WW I\u00a0spy Mata Hari was from which country?",
                "choice1": "Holland",
                "choice2": "Italy",
                "choice3": "India",
                "choice4": "France",
                "rightAnswer": "Holland",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 317,
                "questionText": "Which country founded the West India Company?",
                "choice1": "Germany",
                "choice2": "Holland",
                "choice3": "Spain",
                "choice4": "France",
                "rightAnswer": "Holland",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 318,
                "questionText": "Diana was the Roman goddess of what?",
                "choice1": "War",
                "choice2": "Passion",
                "choice3": "Beauty",
                "choice4": "Hunting",
                "rightAnswer": "Hunting",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 319,
                "questionText": "What country provided the birthplace of Christopher Columbus?",
                "choice1": "Italy",
                "choice2": "Portugal",
                "choice3": "Spain",
                "choice4": "France",
                "rightAnswer": "Italy",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 320,
                "questionText": "Which English Monarch was the first from the House of Stuart?",
                "choice1": "Charles I",
                "choice2": "Henry VII",
                "choice3": "James I",
                "choice4": "Edward IV",
                "rightAnswer": "James I",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 321,
                "questionText": "Which English Monarch was succeeded by William III of Orange?",
                "choice1": "Charles II",
                "choice2": "Mary II",
                "choice3": "James II",
                "choice4": "James I",
                "rightAnswer": "James II",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 322,
                "questionText": "Which English Monarch succeeded Charles II?",
                "choice1": "James II",
                "choice2": "Mary II",
                "choice3": "William III",
                "choice4": "James I",
                "rightAnswer": "James II",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 323,
                "questionText": "Who hosted the music\u00a0radio program The Perfumed Garden?",
                "choice1": "Vernon Kay",
                "choice2": "Noel Edmunds",
                "choice3": "John Peel",
                "choice4": "Kenny Everett",
                "rightAnswer": "John Peel",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 324,
                "questionText": "Joseph Stalin twice ordered the KGB to assassinate which US actor?",
                "choice1": "James Cagney",
                "choice2": "Humphrey Bogart",
                "choice3": "Bob Hope",
                "choice4": "John Wayne",
                "rightAnswer": "John Wayne",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 325,
                "questionText": "The Mau Mau were terrorists in which country late 50s early 60s?",
                "choice1": "Kenya",
                "choice2": "Ghana",
                "choice3": "Sudan",
                "choice4": "Malaysia",
                "rightAnswer": "Kenya",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 326,
                "questionText": "What was the name of the atom bomb dropped on Hiroshima?",
                "choice1": "Little Boy",
                "choice2": "Good Boy",
                "choice3": "Fat Boy",
                "choice4": "Bad Boy",
                "rightAnswer": "Little Boy",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 327,
                "questionText": "Which explorers expedition was the first to circumnavigate the earth?",
                "choice1": "Magellan",
                "choice2": "de Gama",
                "choice3": "Cook",
                "choice4": "Cartier",
                "rightAnswer": "Magellan",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 328,
                "questionText": "Which English Monarch succeeded William III of Orange?",
                "choice1": "Charles II",
                "choice2": "James I",
                "choice3": "James II",
                "choice4": "Mary II",
                "rightAnswer": "Mary II",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 329,
                "questionText": "Which famous outlaws last words were \"That's life\"?",
                "choice1": "Billy the Kid",
                "choice2": "Dick Turpin",
                "choice3": "Ned Kelly",
                "choice4": "Al Capone",
                "rightAnswer": "Ned Kelly",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 330,
                "questionText": "In which month of 1987 was weatherman Michael Fish embarrassed for failing to give warning of severe gales?",
                "choice1": "December",
                "choice2": "August",
                "choice3": "September",
                "choice4": "October",
                "rightAnswer": "October",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 331,
                "questionText": "Which English Monarch was also known as Old Ironsides",
                "choice1": "Oliver Cromwell",
                "choice2": "Charles II",
                "choice3": "Richard Cromwell",
                "choice4": "Charles I",
                "rightAnswer": "Oliver Cromwell",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 332,
                "questionText": "From which country did Bangladesh claim its independence?",
                "choice1": "Pakistan",
                "choice2": "China",
                "choice3": "Britain",
                "choice4": "India",
                "rightAnswer": "Pakistan",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 333,
                "questionText": "Where did the 30 years war start and finish?",
                "choice1": "Paris",
                "choice2": "Berlin",
                "choice3": "London",
                "choice4": "Prague",
                "rightAnswer": "Prague",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 334,
                "questionText": "Which member of the British Royal Family was made Deputy Sheriff of Harris County, Texas in 1960?",
                "choice1": "The Queen",
                "choice2": "Prince Philip",
                "choice3": "Prince Andrew",
                "choice4": "Prince Charles",
                "rightAnswer": "Prince Philip",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 335,
                "questionText": "Who directly succeeded King Edward VI as Monarch of England?",
                "choice1": "Queen Elizabeth I",
                "choice2": "Queen Jane",
                "choice3": "King James I",
                "choice4": "Queen Mary I",
                "rightAnswer": "Queen Jane",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 336,
                "questionText": "Seti I was the father of which Egyptian?",
                "choice1": "Tutankhamun",
                "choice2": "Ramesses II",
                "choice3": "Nefertiti",
                "choice4": "Cleopatra",
                "rightAnswer": "Ramesses II",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 337,
                "questionText": "Julius Caesar said \"The die is cast\" after crossing which river?",
                "choice1": "Rubicon",
                "choice2": "Danube",
                "choice3": "Thames",
                "choice4": "Tiber",
                "rightAnswer": "Rubicon",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 338,
                "questionText": "The crossing of which river started a civil war?",
                "choice1": "St. Lawrence",
                "choice2": "Avon",
                "choice3": "Danube",
                "choice4": "Rubicon",
                "rightAnswer": "Rubicon",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 339,
                "questionText": "What kind of march did Gandhi lead?",
                "choice1": "Sugar",
                "choice2": "Pepper",
                "choice3": "Salt",
                "choice4": "Flower",
                "rightAnswer": "Salt",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 340,
                "questionText": "Which city was destroyed by an earthquake in 1906?",
                "choice1": "Lisbon",
                "choice2": "San Francisco",
                "choice3": "Naples",
                "choice4": "Havana",
                "rightAnswer": "San Francisco",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 341,
                "questionText": "What was the name of the flu that killed an estimated 40 million people in 1918?",
                "choice1": "European",
                "choice2": "Spanish",
                "choice3": "Asian",
                "choice4": "Hong Kong",
                "rightAnswer": "Spanish",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 342,
                "questionText": "Olaf Palme was assassinated in 1986. Of which country was he the prime minister?",
                "choice1": "Norway",
                "choice2": "Denmark",
                "choice3": "Sweden",
                "choice4": "Finland",
                "rightAnswer": "Sweden",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 343,
                "questionText": "What was sometimes used as currency in 18th century Siberia?",
                "choice1": "Tea",
                "choice2": "Snow",
                "choice3": "Tulips",
                "choice4": "Coffee",
                "rightAnswer": "Tea",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 344,
                "questionText": "What did Captain Cook call the Islands of Tonga?",
                "choice1": "The Tongan Islands",
                "choice2": "The Cook Islands",
                "choice3": "The Scary Islands",
                "choice4": "The Friendly Islands",
                "rightAnswer": "The Friendly Islands",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 345,
                "questionText": "Which of these radio programmes did John Peel once present?",
                "choice1": "The tendered garden",
                "choice2": "The Musical garden",
                "choice3": "The perfumed garden",
                "choice4": "The poisoned garden",
                "rightAnswer": "The perfumed garden",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 346,
                "questionText": "Which major British newspaper closed down for almost a year in 1978?",
                "choice1": "The Mirror",
                "choice2": "The Times",
                "choice3": "The Sun",
                "choice4": "The Telegraph",
                "rightAnswer": "The Times",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 347,
                "questionText": "Which ancient world wonder was found in Alexandria?",
                "choice1": "Great Pyramid",
                "choice2": "The\u00a0Lighthouse",
                "choice3": "Hanging Gardens",
                "choice4": "Temple Of Artemis",
                "rightAnswer": "The\u00a0Lighthouse",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 348,
                "questionText": "The Rainbow Warrior was what form of transport?",
                "choice1": "Oil Tanker",
                "choice2": "Tugboat",
                "choice3": "Cruise Ship",
                "choice4": "Trawler",
                "rightAnswer": "Trawler",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 349,
                "questionText": "What was the name of the cat that survived the sinking of the Bismark, HMS Cossack and the HMS Ark Royal in WW II ?",
                "choice1": "Unsinkable Sam",
                "choice2": "Kit Cat",
                "choice3": "Wet Willy",
                "choice4": "Unsinkable Molly Brown",
                "rightAnswer": "Unsinkable Sam",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 350,
                "questionText": "Marco Polo was a citizen of which city?",
                "choice1": "Venice",
                "choice2": "Florence",
                "choice3": "Rome",
                "choice4": "Naples",
                "rightAnswer": "Venice",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 351,
                "questionText": "Which animal is not a Chinese year?",
                "choice1": "Hare",
                "choice2": "Whale",
                "choice3": "Tiger",
                "choice4": "Snake",
                "rightAnswer": "Whale",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 352,
                "questionText": "In history, the highwayman Dick Turpin was hanged in which city?",
                "choice1": "York",
                "choice2": "Leeds",
                "choice3": "London",
                "choice4": "Portsmouth",
                "rightAnswer": "York",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 353,
                "questionText": "How many wheels had a hansom cab?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 5,
                "choice3": 4,
                "choice4": 2,
                "rightAnswer": 2,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 354,
                "questionText": "How many seconds did it take Napoleons surgeon Baron Dominique Larrey\u00a0to amputate a leg?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 32,
                "choice3": 60,
                "choice4": 14,
                "rightAnswer": 14,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 355,
                "questionText": "How many swings of the axe did it take to remove Maria Stuarts head?",
                "choice1": 15,
                "choice2": 1,
                "choice3": 3,
                "choice4": 35,
                "rightAnswer": 15,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 356,
                "questionText": "How many dollars did the first settlers pay the native Indians for Manhattan Island?",
                "choice1": 48,
                "choice2": 96,
                "choice3": 24,
                "choice4": 4,
                "rightAnswer": 24,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 357,
                "questionText": "Concubines excluded, how many wives did a Chinese Emperor have?",
                "choice1": 1,
                "choice2": 13,
                "choice3": 88,
                "choice4": 40,
                "rightAnswer": 40,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 358,
                "questionText": "According to legend,\u00a0how many bears did Davy Crockett\u00a0kill in 7 months?\u00a0",
                "choice1": 705,
                "choice2": 77,
                "choice3": 7,
                "choice4": 105,
                "rightAnswer": 105,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 359,
                "questionText": "How old was the Biblical figure Methusalem?",
                "choice1": 969,
                "choice2": 622,
                "choice3": 369,
                "choice4": 844,
                "rightAnswer": 969,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 360,
                "questionText": "In which year were the Salem witchcraft trials?",
                "choice1": 1744,
                "choice2": 1519,
                "choice3": 1581,
                "choice4": 1692,
                "rightAnswer": 1692,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 361,
                "questionText": "In which year was the last legal execution of a witch in Scotland?",
                "choice1": 1827,
                "choice2": 1727,
                "choice3": 1627,
                "choice4": 1927,
                "rightAnswer": 1727,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 362,
                "questionText": "In which year was the lightning rod invented?",
                "choice1": 1752,
                "choice2": 1825,
                "choice3": 1322,
                "choice4": 1901,
                "rightAnswer": 1752,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 363,
                "questionText": "In which year did New York become a US state?",
                "choice1": 1837,
                "choice2": 1819,
                "choice3": 1788,
                "choice4": 1792,
                "rightAnswer": 1788,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 364,
                "questionText": "In which year did the first steam ship cross the Atlantic?",
                "choice1": 1859,
                "choice2": 1819,
                "choice3": 1780,
                "choice4": 1910,
                "rightAnswer": 1819,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 365,
                "questionText": "The age of the railway began in which year with the introduction of the Liverpool-Manchester line?",
                "choice1": 1860,
                "choice2": 1770,
                "choice3": 1800,
                "choice4": 1830,
                "rightAnswer": 1830,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 366,
                "questionText": "In which year did the first passenger die in a rail accident?",
                "choice1": 1830,
                "choice2": 1780,
                "choice3": 1870,
                "choice4": 1850,
                "rightAnswer": 1830,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 367,
                "questionText": "In which year were postage stamps introduced?",
                "choice1": 1745,
                "choice2": 1899,
                "choice3": 1650,
                "choice4": 1840,
                "rightAnswer": 1840,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 368,
                "questionText": "In which year did Texas become a US state?",
                "choice1": 1845,
                "choice2": 1912,
                "choice3": 1959,
                "choice4": 1861,
                "rightAnswer": 1845,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 369,
                "questionText": "The first weather report in a newspaper appeared in which year?",
                "choice1": 1788,
                "choice2": 1902,
                "choice3": 1848,
                "choice4": 1871,
                "rightAnswer": 1848,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 370,
                "questionText": "In which year were blue jeans invented?",
                "choice1": 1874,
                "choice2": 1836,
                "choice3": 1902,
                "choice4": 1580,
                "rightAnswer": 1874,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 371,
                "questionText": "In which year was the light bulb invented?",
                "choice1": 1880,
                "choice2": 1901,
                "choice3": 1911,
                "choice4": 1825,
                "rightAnswer": 1880,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 372,
                "questionText": "In which year did Oklahoma become a US state?",
                "choice1": 1889,
                "choice2": 1907,
                "choice3": 1850,
                "choice4": 1819,
                "rightAnswer": 1907,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 373,
                "questionText": "In which year did New Mexico become a US state?",
                "choice1": 1867,
                "choice2": 1959,
                "choice3": 1912,
                "choice4": 1788,
                "rightAnswer": 1912,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 374,
                "questionText": "In which year were false eyelashes invented?",
                "choice1": 1888,
                "choice2": 1925,
                "choice3": 1939,
                "choice4": 1916,
                "rightAnswer": 1916,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 375,
                "questionText": "In which year did Charles Lindbergh fly solo across the Atlantic?",
                "choice1": 1927,
                "choice2": 1937,
                "choice3": 1917,
                "choice4": 1907,
                "rightAnswer": 1927,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 376,
                "questionText": "In which year was nylon invented?",
                "choice1": 1885,
                "choice2": 1935,
                "choice3": 1906,
                "choice4": 1951,
                "rightAnswer": 1935,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 377,
                "questionText": "In which year was the transistor invented?",
                "choice1": 1975,
                "choice2": 1947,
                "choice3": 1844,
                "choice4": 1902,
                "rightAnswer": 1947,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 378,
                "questionText": "In which year was the microwave oven invented?",
                "choice1": 1977,
                "choice2": 1921,
                "choice3": 1982,
                "choice4": 1947,
                "rightAnswer": 1947,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 379,
                "questionText": "In which year did the hula hoop craze first\u00a0circle the world?",
                "choice1": 1952,
                "choice2": 1963,
                "choice3": 1966,
                "choice4": 1958,
                "rightAnswer": 1958,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 380,
                "questionText": "In which year was the Berlin wall built?",
                "choice1": 1965,
                "choice2": 1958,
                "choice3": 1961,
                "choice4": 1946,
                "rightAnswer": 1961,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 381,
                "questionText": "In which year was Nelson Mandela sentenced to life in prison?",
                "choice1": 1972,
                "choice2": 1978,
                "choice3": 1964,
                "choice4": 1956,
                "rightAnswer": 1964,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 382,
                "questionText": "In which year did the mini skirt first turn heads?",
                "choice1": 1968,
                "choice2": 1964,
                "choice3": 1961,
                "choice4": 1958,
                "rightAnswer": 1964,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 383,
                "questionText": "In which year was the first 'Great Blackout' in the eastern United States and Canada?",
                "choice1": 1955,
                "choice2": 1965,
                "choice3": 1975,
                "choice4": 1985,
                "rightAnswer": 1965,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 384,
                "questionText": "In which year was the 747 Jumbo jet introduced?",
                "choice1": 1964,
                "choice2": 1984,
                "choice3": 1978,
                "choice4": 1970,
                "rightAnswer": 1970,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 385,
                "questionText": "Timber selected from how many fully grown oak trees were needed to build a large 3 decker Royal Navy battle ship in the 18th century?",
                "choice1": 500,
                "choice2": 1500,
                "choice3": 50,
                "choice4": 3500,
                "rightAnswer": 3500,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 386,
                "questionText": "In 1970 the 'Blue Flame' became the first car to break\u00a0which speed barrier?",
                "choice1": "500 km hr",
                "choice2": "1,500 km hr",
                "choice3": "1,000 km hr",
                "choice4": "250 km hr",
                "rightAnswer": "1,000 km hr",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 387,
                "questionText": "The 'football' or briefcase with the nuclear codes must always be within how many metres of the US President?",
                "choice1": "24 m",
                "choice2": "2 m",
                "choice3": "6 m",
                "choice4": "12 m",
                "rightAnswer": "12 m",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 388,
                "questionText": "How long did the Apollo 11 mission last?",
                "choice1": "295 hours 18 min",
                "choice2": "195 hours 18 min",
                "choice3": "95 hours 18 min",
                "choice4": "495 hours 18 min",
                "rightAnswer": "195 hours 18 min",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 389,
                "questionText": "What was the average life expectancy of an Englishman in the middle ages?",
                "choice1": "13 years",
                "choice2": "41 years",
                "choice3": "33 years",
                "choice4": "21 years",
                "rightAnswer": "33 years",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 390,
                "questionText": "How long was the war between GB \u00a0and Zansibar in 1896?",
                "choice1": "38 min",
                "choice2": "38 days",
                "choice3": "38 hours",
                "choice4": "38 sec",
                "rightAnswer": "38 min",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 391,
                "questionText": "How long did the Wright Brothers first flight last?",
                "choice1": "12 sec",
                "choice2": "3 sec\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0",
                "choice3": "59 sec",
                "choice4": "24 sec",
                "rightAnswer": "59 sec",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 392,
                "questionText": "What was the cargo on board the HMS Bounty?",
                "choice1": "Breadfruit",
                "choice2": "Sauerkraut",
                "choice3": "Watermelon",
                "choice4": "Grapefruit",
                "rightAnswer": "Breadfruit",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 393,
                "questionText": "Who was Patrick Stewart's best man at his wedding?",
                "choice1": "Brent Spiner",
                "choice2": "LeVar Burton",
                "choice3": "Johnathan Frakes",
                "choice4": "William Shatner",
                "rightAnswer": "Brent Spiner",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 394,
                "questionText": "Off the coast of which country did the Edmund Fitzgerald sink?",
                "choice1": "Ireland",
                "choice2": "Scotland",
                "choice3": "Canada",
                "choice4": "Australia",
                "rightAnswer": "Canada",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 395,
                "questionText": "The press coined which famous pilot 'The Flying Fool' in 1927?",
                "choice1": "Charles Lindbergh",
                "choice2": "Orville Wright",
                "choice3": "Baron von Richtofen",
                "choice4": "Amelia Earhart",
                "rightAnswer": "Charles Lindbergh",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 396,
                "questionText": "In which country did an earthquake kill an estimated 650,000 people in 1976?",
                "choice1": "Japan",
                "choice2": "Mexico",
                "choice3": "Pakistan",
                "choice4": "China",
                "rightAnswer": "China",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 397,
                "questionText": "Punch editor A P Herbert once wrote a cheque on the side of a what?",
                "choice1": "taxi",
                "choice2": "egg",
                "choice3": "bus",
                "choice4": "cow",
                "rightAnswer": "cow",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 398,
                "questionText": "The USA bought the Virgin islands from which country?",
                "choice1": "France",
                "choice2": "Holland",
                "choice3": "GB",
                "choice4": "Denmark",
                "rightAnswer": "Denmark",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 399,
                "questionText": "Which city was never the capital of the USA?",
                "choice1": "Baltimore",
                "choice2": "Detroit",
                "choice3": "Philadelphia",
                "choice4": "New York\u00a0",
                "rightAnswer": "Detroit",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 400,
                "questionText": "Tollbooth was an infamous 18th century prison in which city?",
                "choice1": "Edinburgh",
                "choice2": "Halifax",
                "choice3": "Bristol",
                "choice4": "London",
                "rightAnswer": "Edinburgh",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 401,
                "questionText": "Which queen at one time\u00a0banned the use of mirrors?",
                "choice1": "Elizabeth I\u00a0",
                "choice2": "Freddie Mercury",
                "choice3": "Elizabeth II\u00a0",
                "choice4": "Mary",
                "rightAnswer": "Elizabeth I\u00a0",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 402,
                "questionText": "How often does Airforce One undergo a complete overhaul or D-Check?",
                "choice1": "every 54 days",
                "choice2": "every 154 days",
                "choice3": "every 254 days",
                "choice4": "every 354 days",
                "rightAnswer": "every 154 days",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 403,
                "questionText": "In the 1930s, what was the 'Phalange'?",
                "choice1": "Fascist movement in Spain",
                "choice2": "Abstract art movement",
                "choice3": "Secret police in Italy",
                "choice4": "Dance craze",
                "rightAnswer": "Fascist movement in Spain",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 404,
                "questionText": "The NAZIS declared war on which country 3 March 1945?",
                "choice1": "Italy",
                "choice2": "Japan",
                "choice3": "Finland",
                "choice4": "France",
                "rightAnswer": "Finland",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 405,
                "questionText": "What did the\u00a0Roman Catholic church condemned in the 16th century?",
                "choice1": "knife",
                "choice2": "fork",
                "choice3": "corkscrew",
                "choice4": "spoon",
                "rightAnswer": "fork",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 406,
                "questionText": "Off the coast of which country did the Amoco Cadiz sink?",
                "choice1": "Spain",
                "choice2": "USA",
                "choice3": "France",
                "choice4": "South Africa",
                "rightAnswer": "France",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 407,
                "questionText": "The Roman province Aquitania was found in which modern day country?",
                "choice1": "Portugal",
                "choice2": "Austria",
                "choice3": "Scotland",
                "choice4": "France",
                "rightAnswer": "France",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 408,
                "questionText": "Which explorer first entered San Francisco Bay in 1579?",
                "choice1": "Henry Hudson",
                "choice2": "Amerigo Vespucci",
                "choice3": "Francis Drake",
                "choice4": "Juan Ponce de Leon",
                "rightAnswer": "Francis Drake",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 409,
                "questionText": "Baby Doc Duvalier was the dictator of which country?",
                "choice1": "Haiti",
                "choice2": "Vietnam",
                "choice3": "Senegal",
                "choice4": "Algeria",
                "rightAnswer": "Haiti",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 410,
                "questionText": "Herodotus is known as the father of what?",
                "choice1": "Theatre",
                "choice2": "Medicine",
                "choice3": "History",
                "choice4": "Music",
                "rightAnswer": "History",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 411,
                "questionText": "Between which two countries was the 1969 'Football War'?",
                "choice1": "Honduras and El Salvador",
                "choice2": "Algeria and Tunisia",
                "choice3": "Brazil and Argentina",
                "choice4": "\u00a0Chile and Peru\u00a0",
                "rightAnswer": "Honduras and El Salvador",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 412,
                "questionText": "Off the coast of which country did the QE I sink?",
                "choice1": "USA",
                "choice2": "Brazil",
                "choice3": "Spain",
                "choice4": "Hong Kong",
                "rightAnswer": "Hong Kong",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 413,
                "questionText": "Which ship sank in the Denmark Strait?",
                "choice1": "Titanic",
                "choice2": "Bismark",
                "choice3": "Hood",
                "choice4": "Exon Valdez",
                "rightAnswer": "Hood",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 414,
                "questionText": "Which country invented Venetian Blinds?",
                "choice1": "France",
                "choice2": "USA",
                "choice3": "Italy",
                "choice4": "Japan",
                "rightAnswer": "Japan",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 415,
                "questionText": "Who was the captain of PT 109?",
                "choice1": "Gerald Ford",
                "choice2": "George Bush sr",
                "choice3": "Ronald Reagan",
                "choice4": "JFK",
                "rightAnswer": "JFK",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 416,
                "questionText": "Who was William Shatner's best man at his wedding?",
                "choice1": "Brent Spiner",
                "choice2": "DeForest Kelley",
                "choice3": "Leonard Nimoy",
                "choice4": "James Doohan",
                "rightAnswer": "Leonard Nimoy",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 417,
                "questionText": "Which magazine first published photos of a human embryo in 1965?",
                "choice1": "Cosmopolitan\u00a0",
                "choice2": "Life",
                "choice3": "Time",
                "choice4": "Newsweek",
                "rightAnswer": "Life",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 418,
                "questionText": "Which PM played a role in the development of soft ice cream?",
                "choice1": "Margret Thatcher\u00a0",
                "choice2": "Winston Churchill\u00a0",
                "choice3": "William Pitt",
                "choice4": "Tony Blair",
                "rightAnswer": "Margret Thatcher\u00a0",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 419,
                "questionText": "Botany Bay was the first penal colony in which Australian state?",
                "choice1": "Tasmania",
                "choice2": "New South Wales",
                "choice3": "Queensland",
                "choice4": "South Australia",
                "rightAnswer": "New South Wales",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 420,
                "questionText": "Which\u00a0kind of animal\u00a0did Florence Nightingale often carry\u00a0around in her pocket?\u00a0\u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0",
                "choice1": "Snake",
                "choice2": "Owl",
                "choice3": "Kitten",
                "choice4": "Puppy",
                "rightAnswer": "Owl",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 421,
                "questionText": "Which is the oldest airline in the English-speaking world?",
                "choice1": "Air Lingus",
                "choice2": "Quantas",
                "choice3": "American Airlines",
                "choice4": "British Airways",
                "rightAnswer": "Quantas",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 422,
                "questionText": "What kind of animal was the germanic goddess of the spring?",
                "choice1": "wolf",
                "choice2": "fox",
                "choice3": "bluebird",
                "choice4": "rabbit",
                "rightAnswer": "rabbit",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 423,
                "questionText": "Between 1807 and 1821 the capital of Portugal was found in which city?",
                "choice1": "Madrid",
                "choice2": "Goa",
                "choice3": "London",
                "choice4": "Rio de Janeiro",
                "rightAnswer": "Rio de Janeiro",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 424,
                "questionText": "Who was Australia's longest serving Prime Minister?",
                "choice1": "Gough Whitlam",
                "choice2": "Robert Menzies",
                "choice3": "John Howard",
                "choice4": "Bob Hawke",
                "rightAnswer": "Robert Menzies",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 425,
                "questionText": "Who was the first man to claim he\u00a0reach the North Pole in 1909?",
                "choice1": "Robert Scott",
                "choice2": "Robert Peary",
                "choice3": "Roald Amundsen",
                "choice4": "Admiral Halsey",
                "rightAnswer": "Robert Peary",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 426,
                "questionText": "The Roman province Lusitania was found in which modern day country?",
                "choice1": "France",
                "choice2": "Germany",
                "choice3": "Spain",
                "choice4": "Ireland",
                "rightAnswer": "Spain",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 427,
                "questionText": "Which Sunday newspaper, in 1924, published the first crossword to appear in a British Newspaper?",
                "choice1": "Sunday Mirror",
                "choice2": "Sunday Times",
                "choice3": "The Observer",
                "choice4": "Sunday Express",
                "rightAnswer": "Sunday Express",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 428,
                "questionText": "Which Prime Minister helped invent soft ice-cream?",
                "choice1": "Wilson",
                "choice2": "Major",
                "choice3": "Callaghan",
                "choice4": "Thatcher",
                "rightAnswer": "Thatcher",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 429,
                "questionText": "What was TIME magazines man of the year in 1982?",
                "choice1": "The Computer\u00a0",
                "choice2": "The Automobile",
                "choice3": "NASA",
                "choice4": "The Red Cross",
                "rightAnswer": "The Computer\u00a0",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 430,
                "questionText": "Which of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World was found in Halicarnassus?",
                "choice1": "The Lighthouse",
                "choice2": "The Temple of Artemis",
                "choice3": "The Mausoleum",
                "choice4": "The Hanging Gardens",
                "rightAnswer": "The Mausoleum",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 431,
                "questionText": "Off the coast of which country did the USS Arizona sink?",
                "choice1": "USA",
                "choice2": "Australia",
                "choice3": "Canada",
                "choice4": "Ireland",
                "rightAnswer": "USA",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 432,
                "questionText": "What name did the Vikings give to present day Newfoundland?",
                "choice1": "No mans Land",
                "choice2": "Vinland",
                "choice3": "Graceland",
                "choice4": "Ice Land",
                "rightAnswer": "Vinland",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 433,
                "questionText": "Which US state did Sir Walter Raleigh name?",
                "choice1": "Virginia",
                "choice2": "Massachusetts",
                "choice3": "Florida",
                "choice4": "Rhode Island",
                "rightAnswer": "Virginia",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 434,
                "questionText": "Who was Ronald Reagan's best man at his wedding?",
                "choice1": "Cary Grant",
                "choice2": "Charlie Chaplin",
                "choice3": "William Holden",
                "choice4": "Humphrey Bogart",
                "rightAnswer": "William Holden",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 435,
                "questionText": "Which Thomas was executed alongside Guy Fawkes in November 1605?",
                "choice1": "Summer",
                "choice2": "March",
                "choice3": "May",
                "choice4": "Winter",
                "rightAnswer": "Winter",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 436,
                "questionText": "Which general defeated the French in Canada?",
                "choice1": "Hogge",
                "choice2": "Hawke",
                "choice3": "Wolfe",
                "choice4": "Lambe",
                "rightAnswer": "Wolfe",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "History",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 437,
                "questionText": "How many ghosts visit Scrooge in A Christmas Carol?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 4,
                "choice3": 2,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 438,
                "questionText": "Which female novelist wrote the book Black Beauty?",
                "choice1": "Enid Blyton",
                "choice2": "Barbara Cartland",
                "choice3": "Dorothy L Sayers",
                "choice4": "Anna Sewell",
                "rightAnswer": "Anna Sewell",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 439,
                "questionText": "What was the name of Roy Rogers' pet dog?",
                "choice1": "Dog Rogers",
                "choice2": "Bullet",
                "choice3": "Lightening",
                "choice4": "Fido",
                "rightAnswer": "Bullet",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 440,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"Most motorcars are conglomerations....\" ?",
                "choice1": "Mary Poppins",
                "choice2": "The Little Engine That Could",
                "choice3": "War of the Worlds",
                "choice4": "Chitty Chitty Bang Bang",
                "rightAnswer": "Chitty Chitty Bang Bang",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 441,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'a clockwork orange'?",
                "choice1": "Arnold Hopkins",
                "choice2": "Anthony Hopkins",
                "choice3": "Anthony Burgess",
                "choice4": "Arnold Burgess",
                "rightAnswer": "Anthony Burgess",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 442,
                "questionText": "What was Eric Blair\u2019s pen name?",
                "choice1": "John Steinbeck",
                "choice2": "H.G. Wells",
                "choice3": "George Orwell",
                "choice4": "Charles Dickens",
                "rightAnswer": "George Orwell",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 443,
                "questionText": "What was the name of the dog of Dennis the menace?",
                "choice1": "Gnasher",
                "choice2": "Smasher",
                "choice3": "Thrasher",
                "choice4": "Basher",
                "rightAnswer": "Gnasher",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 444,
                "questionText": "Which is the longest of Shakespeare\u2019s plays?",
                "choice1": "Hamlet",
                "choice2": "2 Gentlemen of Verona",
                "choice3": "Romeo and Juliet",
                "choice4": "MacBeth",
                "rightAnswer": "Hamlet",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 445,
                "questionText": "Which of the following is not a Romance author?",
                "choice1": "Harold Robbins",
                "choice2": "Danielle Steel",
                "choice3": "Jackie Collins",
                "choice4": "Barbara Cartland",
                "rightAnswer": "Harold Robbins",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 446,
                "questionText": "What John Spyri story is about a girl who lives in the Alps?",
                "choice1": "Carmen",
                "choice2": "Emily",
                "choice3": "Annie",
                "choice4": "Heidi",
                "rightAnswer": "Heidi",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 447,
                "questionText": "In which month did Samuel Pepys begin his famous diary?",
                "choice1": "July",
                "choice2": "March",
                "choice3": "May",
                "choice4": "January",
                "rightAnswer": "January",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 448,
                "questionText": "At which railway station does one board the 'Hogwarts Express'?",
                "choice1": "Waterloo",
                "choice2": "Kings Cross",
                "choice3": "Victoria",
                "choice4": "Charing Cross",
                "rightAnswer": "Kings Cross",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 449,
                "questionText": "Which of the following is not a childrens author?",
                "choice1": "Enid Blyton",
                "choice2": "Michael Crichton",
                "choice3": "Dr. Seuss",
                "choice4": "Roger Hargreaves",
                "rightAnswer": "Michael Crichton",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 450,
                "questionText": "What was the name of Sherlock Holmes house\u00a0keeper?",
                "choice1": "Mrs Wilson",
                "choice2": "Mrs Hudson",
                "choice3": "Miss Mayweather",
                "choice4": "Mrs Sippi",
                "rightAnswer": "Mrs Hudson",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 451,
                "questionText": "Michael Bond was the creator of which bear?",
                "choice1": "Paddington",
                "choice2": "Pooh",
                "choice3": "Baloo",
                "choice4": "Yogi",
                "rightAnswer": "Paddington",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 452,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"All children except one, grow up....\" ?",
                "choice1": "Mary Poppins",
                "choice2": "The Jungle Book",
                "choice3": "The lion. the witch and the wardrobe",
                "choice4": "Peter Pan",
                "rightAnswer": "Peter Pan",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 453,
                "questionText": "Whose nose grew when he told a lie?",
                "choice1": "Peter Pan",
                "choice2": "Jeffrey Archer",
                "choice3": "Pinocchio",
                "choice4": "Dumbo",
                "rightAnswer": "Pinocchio",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 454,
                "questionText": "Carlo Collodi created which famous children's character?",
                "choice1": "Pinocchio",
                "choice2": "Peter Pan",
                "choice3": "Snow White",
                "choice4": "Dumbo",
                "rightAnswer": "Pinocchio",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 455,
                "questionText": "What is Dick Grayson better known as?",
                "choice1": "Batman",
                "choice2": "Alfred",
                "choice3": "Robin",
                "choice4": "Joker",
                "rightAnswer": "Robin",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 456,
                "questionText": "Where was William Shakespeare born?",
                "choice1": "Kingston Upon Thames",
                "choice2": "Stratford Upon Avon",
                "choice3": "Bath",
                "choice4": "Bradford",
                "rightAnswer": "Stratford Upon Avon",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 457,
                "questionText": "What is the subtitle of Peter Pan?",
                "choice1": "The Boy Who Wouldn\u2019t Grow Up",
                "choice2": "The Puppet That Came Alive",
                "choice3": "The Boy With The Growing Nose",
                "choice4": "The Boy Who Lied",
                "rightAnswer": "The Boy Who Wouldn\u2019t Grow Up",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 458,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"Dorothy lived in the midst....\" ?",
                "choice1": "The Wonderful Wizard of Oz",
                "choice2": "The Thorn Birds",
                "choice3": "Mary Poppins",
                "choice4": "Mists of Avalon",
                "rightAnswer": "The Wonderful Wizard of Oz",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 459,
                "questionText": "Which of the following is the best-selling fiction author of all time?",
                "choice1": "Barbara Cartland",
                "choice2": "Harold Robbins",
                "choice3": "William Shakespeare",
                "choice4": "Agatha Christie",
                "rightAnswer": "William Shakespeare",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 460,
                "questionText": "How many Bronte sisters were there?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 2,
                "choice3": 5,
                "choice4": 4,
                "rightAnswer": 3,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 461,
                "questionText": "How many children were in Enid Blytons the famous five?",
                "choice1": 6,
                "choice2": 4,
                "choice3": 3,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 462,
                "questionText": "Winston Smith is the central character in which book?",
                "choice1": "The Day Of The Triffids",
                "choice2": 1984,
                "choice3": "The Time Machine",
                "choice4": "Dune",
                "rightAnswer": 1984,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 463,
                "questionText": "How many rode into Tennyson's 'valley of death'?",
                "choice1": 6000,
                "choice2": 100,
                "choice3": 1000,
                "choice4": 600,
                "rightAnswer": 600,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 464,
                "questionText": "How old was Adrian Mole?",
                "choice1": "13 and a half",
                "choice2": "13 and 3 quarters",
                "choice3": "13 and 2 thirds",
                "choice4": "13 and 3 fifths",
                "rightAnswer": "13 and 3 quarters",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 465,
                "questionText": "What was the name of inn in Treasure Island?",
                "choice1": "Officer Benbow",
                "choice2": "Corporal Benbow",
                "choice3": "Admiral Benbow",
                "choice4": "Captain Benbow",
                "rightAnswer": "Admiral Benbow",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 466,
                "questionText": "Who wrote \"don't count your chickens before they are hatched\"?",
                "choice1": "Shakespeare",
                "choice2": "Chaucer",
                "choice3": "Aesop",
                "choice4": "Ben \u00a0Franklin",
                "rightAnswer": "Aesop",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 467,
                "questionText": "Which of the following is the second best-selling fiction author of all time?",
                "choice1": "Agatha Christie",
                "choice2": "Harold Robbins",
                "choice3": "Barbara Cartland",
                "choice4": "William Shakespeare",
                "rightAnswer": "Agatha Christie",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 468,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'The Count of Monte Christo'?",
                "choice1": "Alexandre Dumas",
                "choice2": "Herman Melville",
                "choice3": "Nathaniel Hawthorne",
                "choice4": "Victor Hugo",
                "rightAnswer": "Alexandre Dumas",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 469,
                "questionText": "Which\u00a0name is not a Steven King book?",
                "choice1": "Christine",
                "choice2": "Cujo\u00a0",
                "choice3": "Cacy",
                "choice4": "Carrie",
                "rightAnswer": "Cacy",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 470,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"These two very old people are the father and mother of Mr Bucket...\"?",
                "choice1": "Mary Poppins",
                "choice2": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory",
                "choice3": "Peter Pan",
                "choice4": "Treasure Island",
                "rightAnswer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 471,
                "questionText": "Which of the following is not visited by Gulliver in Gulliver's Travels?",
                "choice1": "China",
                "choice2": "Laputa",
                "choice3": "Lilliput",
                "choice4": "Japan",
                "rightAnswer": "China",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 472,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'Moll Flanders'?",
                "choice1": "Johnathan Swift",
                "choice2": "Daniel DeFoe",
                "choice3": "Voltaire",
                "choice4": "Henry Fielding",
                "rightAnswer": "Daniel DeFoe",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 473,
                "questionText": "Who wrote In The Beginning I Used To Be An Animal But I'm Alright Now?",
                "choice1": "Wayne Rooney",
                "choice2": "Scary Spice",
                "choice3": "Vinnie Jones",
                "choice4": "Eric Burdon",
                "rightAnswer": "Eric Burdon",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 474,
                "questionText": "What is the complete title of Mary Shelley's Frankenstein?",
                "choice1": "Frankenstein or The modern satan",
                "choice2": "Frankenstein or The modern Prometheus",
                "choice3": "Frankenstein or The modern phoenix",
                "choice4": "Frankenstein or The modern genesis",
                "rightAnswer": "Frankenstein or The modern Prometheus",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 475,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'Pygmalion'?",
                "choice1": "G B Shaw",
                "choice2": "Tolstoj",
                "choice3": "Mark Twain",
                "choice4": "Emily Bronte",
                "rightAnswer": "G B Shaw",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 476,
                "questionText": "Which of these writers died in 1400?",
                "choice1": "William Shakespeare",
                "choice2": "Samuel Johnson",
                "choice3": "Daniel DeFoe",
                "choice4": "Geoffrey Chaucer",
                "rightAnswer": "Geoffrey Chaucer",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 477,
                "questionText": "What was Mary Ann Evans pen name?",
                "choice1": "George Bernard Shaw",
                "choice2": "George Eliot",
                "choice3": "George Sand",
                "choice4": "George Orwell",
                "rightAnswer": "George Eliot",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 478,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'Tom Jones'?",
                "choice1": "Johnathan Swift",
                "choice2": "Henry Fielding",
                "choice3": "Herman Melville",
                "choice4": "Daniel DeFoe",
                "rightAnswer": "Henry Fielding",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 479,
                "questionText": "Aldous Huxley's book Brave New World was banned in which country?",
                "choice1": "South Africa",
                "choice2": "Canada",
                "choice3": "Ireland",
                "choice4": "USA",
                "rightAnswer": "Ireland",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 480,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'I Robot'?",
                "choice1": "Jules Verne",
                "choice2": "Douglas Adams",
                "choice3": "H G Wells",
                "choice4": "Isaac Asimov",
                "rightAnswer": "Isaac Asimov",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 481,
                "questionText": "Who was Rowena's husband?",
                "choice1": "Macbeth",
                "choice2": "Robin Hood",
                "choice3": "Dick Turpin",
                "choice4": "Ivanhoe",
                "rightAnswer": "Ivanhoe",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 482,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'Peter Pan'?",
                "choice1": "Rudyard Kipling",
                "choice2": "J M Barrie",
                "choice3": "Lewis Carroll",
                "choice4": "Carlo Collodi",
                "rightAnswer": "J M Barrie",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 483,
                "questionText": "Who wrote the book The Last Of The Mohicans?",
                "choice1": "Jules Verne",
                "choice2": "James Fenimore Cooper",
                "choice3": "H.G. Wells",
                "choice4": "Sir Walter Scott",
                "rightAnswer": "James Fenimore Cooper",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 484,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \" The great fish moved silently...\" ?",
                "choice1": "The Old Man and the Sea",
                "choice2": "Jaws",
                "choice3": "Moby Dick",
                "choice4": "The Shipping News",
                "rightAnswer": "Jaws",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 485,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'The Spy Who Came In From The Cold'?",
                "choice1": "John le Carre",
                "choice2": "Ian Fleming",
                "choice3": "Arthur Conan Doyle",
                "choice4": "Henning Mankell",
                "rightAnswer": "John le Carre",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 486,
                "questionText": "Mother Raksha is a character in which childrens book?",
                "choice1": "The Wind in the Willows",
                "choice2": "Jungle Book",
                "choice3": "The Wonderful Wizard Of Oz",
                "choice4": "Peter Pan",
                "rightAnswer": "Jungle Book",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 487,
                "questionText": "Uther Pendragon was which mans father?",
                "choice1": "Robin Hood",
                "choice2": "King Arthur",
                "choice3": "Ivanhoe",
                "choice4": "Dick Turpin",
                "rightAnswer": "King Arthur",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 488,
                "questionText": "Oliver Mellors is a central character in which novel?",
                "choice1": "Animal Farm",
                "choice2": "Lady Chatterley's Lover",
                "choice3": "The Great Gatsby",
                "choice4": "The World According To Garp",
                "rightAnswer": "Lady Chatterley's Lover",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 489,
                "questionText": "Totally Frank is which Frank's autobiography?",
                "choice1": "Howard",
                "choice2": "Lampard",
                "choice3": "Zappa",
                "choice4": "Sinatra",
                "rightAnswer": "Lampard",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 490,
                "questionText": "Who wrote the popular Simon Templar books?",
                "choice1": "Leslie Charteris",
                "choice2": "Raymond Chandler",
                "choice3": "John le Carre",
                "choice4": "Dorothy L Sayers",
                "rightAnswer": "Leslie Charteris",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 491,
                "questionText": "What were the cities in Dickens\u2019s A Tale Of Two Cities?",
                "choice1": "Venice and Rome",
                "choice2": "Rome and Florence",
                "choice3": "London and Paris",
                "choice4": "Paris and Florence",
                "rightAnswer": "London and Paris",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 492,
                "questionText": "Who\u00a0is a bat in Jungle Book?",
                "choice1": "Bang",
                "choice2": "Mang",
                "choice3": "Hang",
                "choice4": "Fang",
                "rightAnswer": "Mang",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 493,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'The Mists of Avalon'?",
                "choice1": "Marion Zimmer Bradley",
                "choice2": "J R R Tolkien",
                "choice3": "Joanne K Rowling",
                "choice4": "Terry Pratchett",
                "rightAnswer": "Marion Zimmer Bradley",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 494,
                "questionText": "What was Samuel Langhorne Clemens pen name?",
                "choice1": "Mark Twain",
                "choice2": "Jack London",
                "choice3": "Novalis",
                "choice4": "Joseph Conrad",
                "rightAnswer": "Mark Twain",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 495,
                "questionText": "What was the name of the paranoid android in Hitch Hikers Guide to the Galaxy?",
                "choice1": "Gort",
                "choice2": "Wayne",
                "choice3": "Robby",
                "choice4": "Marvin",
                "rightAnswer": "Marvin",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 496,
                "questionText": "The Count of Monte Christo was in love with which woman?",
                "choice1": "Porsche",
                "choice2": "Lancia",
                "choice3": "Mercedes",
                "choice4": "Cadillac",
                "rightAnswer": "Mercedes",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 497,
                "questionText": "What are the cannibalistic beasts called in H.G. Wells book The Time Machine?",
                "choice1": "Triffids",
                "choice2": "Morlocks",
                "choice3": "Yahoos",
                "choice4": "Warlocks",
                "rightAnswer": "Morlocks",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 498,
                "questionText": "Whose autobiography was entitled 'The Long Walk To Freedom'?",
                "choice1": "Nelson Mandela",
                "choice2": "Mahatma Gandhi",
                "choice3": "Lenin",
                "choice4": "Martin Luther King",
                "rightAnswer": "Nelson Mandela",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 499,
                "questionText": "Who does Mr Brownlow rescue?",
                "choice1": "Huckleberry Finn",
                "choice2": "Oliver Twist",
                "choice3": "Tom Brown",
                "choice4": "Tom Jones",
                "rightAnswer": "Oliver Twist",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 500,
                "questionText": "Which nationality is best-selling author Paulo Coelho?",
                "choice1": "Portuguese",
                "choice2": "Spanish",
                "choice3": "French",
                "choice4": "Italian",
                "rightAnswer": "Portuguese",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 501,
                "questionText": "What is comic book hero Roy of the Rovers' surname?",
                "choice1": "Run",
                "choice2": "Rover",
                "choice3": "Rave",
                "choice4": "Race",
                "rightAnswer": "Race",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 502,
                "questionText": "Which Adams wrote Watership Down?",
                "choice1": "Morticia",
                "choice2": "Tony",
                "choice3": "Douglas",
                "choice4": "Richard",
                "rightAnswer": "Richard",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 503,
                "questionText": "Which king said \"A horse, a horse! my kingdom for a horse!\"?",
                "choice1": "Wenceslas",
                "choice2": "Arthur",
                "choice3": "Richard III",
                "choice4": "Henry VIII",
                "rightAnswer": "Richard III",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 504,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'Treasure Island'?",
                "choice1": "Robert Louis Stevenson",
                "choice2": "Sir Walter Scott",
                "choice3": "H G Wells",
                "choice4": "Jack London",
                "rightAnswer": "Robert Louis Stevenson",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 505,
                "questionText": "Who wrote the book 'Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde'?",
                "choice1": "Alister Maclean",
                "choice2": "Iian Banks",
                "choice3": "Sir Walter Scott",
                "choice4": "Robert Louis Stevenson",
                "rightAnswer": "Robert Louis Stevenson",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 506,
                "questionText": "What Was the Title Of Alex Haleys Most Famous Work?",
                "choice1": "Roots",
                "choice2": "Toots",
                "choice3": "Coots",
                "choice4": "Boots",
                "rightAnswer": "Roots",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 507,
                "questionText": "Which novel begins with the line \"Early in the spring of 1750....\" ?",
                "choice1": "I, Claudius",
                "choice2": "Tom Jones",
                "choice3": "Roots",
                "choice4": "The Great Gatsby",
                "rightAnswer": "Roots",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 508,
                "questionText": "What school does Tom attend in Tom Brown\u2019s school days?",
                "choice1": "Dulwich",
                "choice2": "Eton",
                "choice3": "Rugby",
                "choice4": "Harrow",
                "rightAnswer": "Rugby",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 509,
                "questionText": "Who wrote the play 'Waiting for Godot'?",
                "choice1": "Vladimir Nabokov",
                "choice2": "Andrew Lloyd Webber",
                "choice3": "Samuel Beckett",
                "choice4": "George Bernard Shaw",
                "rightAnswer": "Samuel Beckett",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 510,
                "questionText": "The jealous Athena turned Arachne into which kind of animal?",
                "choice1": "spider",
                "choice2": "snake",
                "choice3": "rat",
                "choice4": "donkey",
                "rightAnswer": "spider",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 511,
                "questionText": "What was the title of George Bernard Shaw\u2019s play about Joan of Arc?",
                "choice1": "St Joan",
                "choice2": "Our Joan",
                "choice3": "Joan D'arc",
                "choice4": "Joan of Arc",
                "rightAnswer": "St Joan",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 512,
                "questionText": "Which of the following authors are not in the top ten best-selling literature authors of all time?",
                "choice1": "Danielle Steel",
                "choice2": "Stephen King",
                "choice3": "Agatha Christie",
                "choice4": "Gilbert Patten",
                "rightAnswer": "Stephen King",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 513,
                "questionText": "Holden Caulfield is the main character in which book?",
                "choice1": "Catch 22",
                "choice2": 1984,
                "choice3": "The Catcher In The Rye",
                "choice4": "Moby Dick",
                "rightAnswer": "The Catcher In The Rye",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 514,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"Once there were four children whose names were Peter, Susan, Edmond, and Lucy....\"?",
                "choice1": "The Swiss Family Robinson",
                "choice2": "Mary Poppins",
                "choice3": "Peter Pan",
                "choice4": "The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe",
                "rightAnswer": "The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 515,
                "questionText": "Shylock is a character in which Shakespeare play?",
                "choice1": "The Merchant Of Venice",
                "choice2": "Measure For Measure",
                "choice3": "The Comedy Of Errors",
                "choice4": "Othello",
                "rightAnswer": "The Merchant Of Venice",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 516,
                "questionText": "In The Lord of the Rings, what is the name of the inn in Bree?",
                "choice1": "The Merry Mare",
                "choice2": "The Prancing Pony",
                "choice3": "The Spotted Gelding",
                "choice4": "The Red Stallion",
                "rightAnswer": "The Prancing Pony",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 517,
                "questionText": "In which book would one find the childlike human species named\u00a0Elois?",
                "choice1": "Dune",
                "choice2": "The Time Machine",
                "choice3": "Day Of The Triffids",
                "choice4": "Brave New World",
                "rightAnswer": "The Time Machine",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 518,
                "questionText": "In which book would one find the trog like human species named Morlocks?",
                "choice1": "Brave New World",
                "choice2": "The Time Machine",
                "choice3": "Dune",
                "choice4": "The Day Of The Triffids",
                "rightAnswer": "The Time Machine",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 519,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'The Hunchback of Notre Dame'?",
                "choice1": "Voltaire",
                "choice2": "Victor Hugo",
                "choice3": "Alexandre Dumas",
                "choice4": "Gustave Flaubert",
                "rightAnswer": "Victor Hugo",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 520,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'Mrs Dalloway'?",
                "choice1": "Graham Greene",
                "choice2": "Virginia Woolf",
                "choice3": "James Joyce",
                "choice4": "D H Lawrence",
                "rightAnswer": "Virginia Woolf",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 521,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'The Lord of the Flies'?",
                "choice1": "William Golding",
                "choice2": "George Orwell",
                "choice3": "Joseph Conrad",
                "choice4": "Aldous Huxley",
                "rightAnswer": "William Golding",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 522,
                "questionText": "How many tasks did Hercules have to fulfill?",
                "choice1": 6,
                "choice2": 24,
                "choice3": 12,
                "choice4": 8,
                "rightAnswer": 12,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 523,
                "questionText": "How long did Robinson Crusoe spend on the island?",
                "choice1": "28 years, 2 months and 19 days",
                "choice2": "7 years, 9 months and 22 days",
                "choice3": "2 years, 8 months and 12 days",
                "choice4": "55 years, 4 months and 3 days",
                "rightAnswer": "28 years, 2 months and 19 days",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 524,
                "questionText": "Who was 'The Once and Future King'?",
                "choice1": "Arargon",
                "choice2": "Elvis",
                "choice3": "Idi Amin",
                "choice4": "Arthur",
                "rightAnswer": "Arthur",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 525,
                "questionText": "Which sport is referred to in \u2018Antony and Cleopatra\u2019?",
                "choice1": "Snooker",
                "choice2": "Billiards",
                "choice3": "Darts",
                "choice4": "Pool",
                "rightAnswer": "Billiards",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 526,
                "questionText": "Who is not one of King Lears daughters?",
                "choice1": "Celia",
                "choice2": "Regan",
                "choice3": "Cordelia",
                "choice4": "Goneril",
                "rightAnswer": "Celia",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 527,
                "questionText": "Lewis Carroll's book Alice's Adventures in Wonderland was banned in which country?",
                "choice1": "Ireland",
                "choice2": "France",
                "choice3": "USA",
                "choice4": "China",
                "rightAnswer": "China",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 528,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"Not too long ago, a monster came to the small town of Castle Rock...\" ?",
                "choice1": "Cujo",
                "choice2": "Frankenstein's Monster",
                "choice3": "Harry Potter and the Scorcerer's Stone",
                "choice4": "Bram Stoker's Dracula",
                "rightAnswer": "Cujo",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 529,
                "questionText": "In Which Dickens Novel Does Mr Micawber Appear?",
                "choice1": "David Copperfield",
                "choice2": "A Christmas carol",
                "choice3": "Great Expectations",
                "choice4": "Oliver Twist",
                "rightAnswer": "David Copperfield",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 530,
                "questionText": "Who wrote the book The Moons A Balloon?",
                "choice1": "Jules Verne",
                "choice2": "Julie Andrews",
                "choice3": "H.G. Wells",
                "choice4": "David Niven",
                "rightAnswer": "David Niven",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 531,
                "questionText": "What was Casanova's first name?",
                "choice1": "Francesco",
                "choice2": "Alberto",
                "choice3": "Benito",
                "choice4": "Giacoma",
                "rightAnswer": "Giacoma",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 532,
                "questionText": "Which novel begins with the line \"My father's family name being Pirrip....\"?",
                "choice1": "Great Expectations",
                "choice2": "Kidnapped",
                "choice3": "Charlie and the Chocalate Factory",
                "choice4": "Little Women",
                "rightAnswer": "Great Expectations",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 533,
                "questionText": "In which book would one find the character named 'Pip'?",
                "choice1": "Wind in the Willows",
                "choice2": "Great Expectations",
                "choice3": "Rob Roy",
                "choice4": "Jurassic Park",
                "rightAnswer": "Great Expectations",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 534,
                "questionText": "What is the name of the cat in Shakespeare's\u00a0Macbeth?",
                "choice1": "Tao",
                "choice2": "Kitty",
                "choice3": "Greymalkin",
                "choice4": "Tybalt",
                "rightAnswer": "Greymalkin",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 535,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'Finnegan's Wake'?",
                "choice1": "James Joyce",
                "choice2": "Samuel Beckett",
                "choice3": "W B Yeats",
                "choice4": "Bram Stocker",
                "rightAnswer": "James Joyce",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 536,
                "questionText": "What are the names of the two main characters in Diana Gabaldon's highland saga novels?",
                "choice1": "Rab and Elizabeth",
                "choice2": "Hamish and Maggie",
                "choice3": "Jamie and Claire",
                "choice4": "Fergus and Fiona",
                "rightAnswer": "Jamie and Claire",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 537,
                "questionText": "Who wrote The Day of the Triffids?",
                "choice1": "John Wyndam",
                "choice2": "Douglas Adams",
                "choice3": "Stephen King",
                "choice4": "Jules Verne",
                "rightAnswer": "John Wyndam",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 538,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"I will begin the story of my adventures....\" ?",
                "choice1": "Roots",
                "choice2": "Kidnapped",
                "choice3": "Kim",
                "choice4": "Mary Poppins",
                "rightAnswer": "Kidnapped",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 539,
                "questionText": "Dan Brown's book The Da Vinci Code was banned in which country?",
                "choice1": "Poland",
                "choice2": "Lebanon",
                "choice3": "Italy",
                "choice4": "Ireland",
                "rightAnswer": "Lebanon",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 540,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"Even in high summer, Tintagel was a haunted place...\" ?",
                "choice1": "The Wonderful Wizard of Oz",
                "choice2": "Rosemary's Baby",
                "choice3": "The Once and Future King",
                "choice4": "Mists of Avalon",
                "rightAnswer": "Mists of Avalon",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 541,
                "questionText": "Who lives at Number Four Privat Drive?",
                "choice1": "Toad of Toad Hall",
                "choice2": "Mary Poppins",
                "choice3": "Winnie-The-Pooh",
                "choice4": "Mr and Mrs Dursley",
                "rightAnswer": "Mr and Mrs Dursley",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 542,
                "questionText": "What is the name of the man servant in 'Around the world in 80 days'?",
                "choice1": "Giles",
                "choice2": "Pas Partout",
                "choice3": "Machu Picchu",
                "choice4": "Cato",
                "rightAnswer": "Pas Partout",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 543,
                "questionText": "What is the name of the ship in 'Moby Dick'?",
                "choice1": "Surprise",
                "choice2": "Boston",
                "choice3": "Pequod",
                "choice4": "Essex",
                "rightAnswer": "Pequod",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 544,
                "questionText": "Mr Darcy is an arrogant gentleman in which novel?",
                "choice1": "A Passage to India",
                "choice2": "Animal Farm",
                "choice3": "The Great Gatsby",
                "choice4": "Pride and Prejudice",
                "rightAnswer": "Pride and Prejudice",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 545,
                "questionText": "Which novel begins with the line \"Last night I dreamt I went to Manderly again....\" ?",
                "choice1": "Roots",
                "choice2": "Trainspotting",
                "choice3": "Rebecca",
                "choice4": "Little Women",
                "rightAnswer": "Rebecca",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 546,
                "questionText": "Who wrote the poem A Red Red Rose?",
                "choice1": "Dante",
                "choice2": "Shakespeare",
                "choice3": "Stephen King",
                "choice4": "Robert Burns",
                "rightAnswer": "Robert Burns",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 547,
                "questionText": "What is the name of Don Quixote's horse?",
                "choice1": "Theresa",
                "choice2": "Isabella",
                "choice3": "Betty",
                "choice4": "Rosinate",
                "rightAnswer": "Rosinate",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 548,
                "questionText": "Who wrote the poem The Lady of the Lake?",
                "choice1": "King Henry VIII",
                "choice2": "Shakespeare",
                "choice3": "Sir Walter Scott",
                "choice4": "T.S. Eliot",
                "rightAnswer": "Sir Walter Scott",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 549,
                "questionText": "In which town did Tom Sawyer live?",
                "choice1": "Hamburg",
                "choice2": "St Petersburg",
                "choice3": "Bern",
                "choice4": "Rome",
                "rightAnswer": "St Petersburg",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 550,
                "questionText": "Which cartoonist created Spider Man?",
                "choice1": "Steve Ditko",
                "choice2": "Bob Montana",
                "choice3": "Walt Disney",
                "choice4": "Gary Larson",
                "rightAnswer": "Steve Ditko",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 551,
                "questionText": "Which novel begins with the line \"It was the best of times....\" ?",
                "choice1": "Trainspotting",
                "choice2": "Tale of Two Cities",
                "choice3": "Rebecca",
                "choice4": "Chitty Chitty Bang Bang",
                "rightAnswer": "Tale of Two Cities",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 552,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"The summer my father bought the bear...\" ?",
                "choice1": "The\u00a0Jungle Book",
                "choice2": "Trainspotting",
                "choice3": "The Hotel New Hampshire",
                "choice4": "The Godfather",
                "rightAnswer": "The Hotel New Hampshire",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 553,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"Samuel Spade's jaw was long and bony....\" ?",
                "choice1": "The Maltese Falcon",
                "choice2": "Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone",
                "choice3": "The Last of the Mohicans",
                "choice4": "Jaws",
                "rightAnswer": "The Maltese Falcon",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 554,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"The Duchy of Grand Fenwick...\" ?",
                "choice1": "Kim",
                "choice2": "Chitty Chitty Bang Bang",
                "choice3": "The Mouse that Roared",
                "choice4": "Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone",
                "rightAnswer": "The Mouse that Roared",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 555,
                "questionText": "The title of which Pink Floyd album is also a chapter in 'The Wind In The Willows'?",
                "choice1": "Meddle",
                "choice2": "Animals",
                "choice3": "The Piper At The Gates Of Dawn",
                "choice4": "Wish You Were Here",
                "rightAnswer": "The Piper At The Gates Of Dawn",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 556,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \" \"Hello, ship\" Jake Holman said under his breath...\" ?",
                "choice1": "Moby Dick",
                "choice2": "A Night to Remember",
                "choice3": "The Sand Pebbles",
                "choice4": "The Shipping News",
                "rightAnswer": "The Sand Pebbles",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 557,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"The American handed Leamus another cup of coffee....\" ?",
                "choice1": "The Godfather",
                "choice2": "The Spy Who Came In From The Cold",
                "choice3": "The Maltese Falcon",
                "choice4": "The Eye Of The Needle",
                "rightAnswer": "The Spy Who Came In From The Cold",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 558,
                "questionText": "Which book begins with the line \"For many days we had been tempest tossed....\" ?",
                "choice1": "Robinson Crusoe",
                "choice2": "The Swiss Family Robinson",
                "choice3": "Moby Dick",
                "choice4": "The Shipping News",
                "rightAnswer": "The Swiss Family Robinson",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 559,
                "questionText": "Which novel begins with the line \"On December 8th, 1915, Maggie Cleary had her fourth birthday....\" ?",
                "choice1": "The Hotel New Hampshire",
                "choice2": "Little Women",
                "choice3": "Roots",
                "choice4": "The Thorn Birds",
                "rightAnswer": "The Thorn Birds",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 560,
                "questionText": "Who wrote 'Utopia' in 1516?",
                "choice1": "Francis Bacon",
                "choice2": "William Shakespeare",
                "choice3": "Christopher Marlowe",
                "choice4": "Thomas More",
                "rightAnswer": "Thomas More",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 561,
                "questionText": "In which book is there an inn called Admiral Benbow?",
                "choice1": "Lord of the Rings",
                "choice2": "Treasure Island",
                "choice3": "Gullivers Travels",
                "choice4": "Peter Pan",
                "rightAnswer": "Treasure Island",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 562,
                "questionText": "In the book The Last Of The Mohicans what was the name of Chingachgook's only son?",
                "choice1": "Magua",
                "choice2": "Uncas",
                "choice3": "Mingo",
                "choice4": "Lightfoot",
                "rightAnswer": "Uncas",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 563,
                "questionText": "In which Italian city do Romeo and Juliet live?",
                "choice1": "Milano",
                "choice2": "Pisa",
                "choice3": "Naples",
                "choice4": "Verona",
                "rightAnswer": "Verona",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 564,
                "questionText": "Which two men are waiting for Godot?",
                "choice1": "Pumpkin and Honey Bunny",
                "choice2": "Benno and Babe",
                "choice3": "Bob and Ted",
                "choice4": "Vladimir and Estragon",
                "rightAnswer": "Vladimir and Estragon",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 565,
                "questionText": "Which former conservative leader wrote a biography on William Wilberforce in 2007?",
                "choice1": "William Hague",
                "choice2": "John Major",
                "choice3": "Iain Duncan Smith",
                "choice4": "Michael Howard",
                "rightAnswer": "William Hague",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 566,
                "questionText": "Which Prime Minister won a Nobel prize for literature?",
                "choice1": "Tony Blair",
                "choice2": "Winston Churchill",
                "choice3": "William Pitt",
                "choice4": "Margret Thatcher",
                "rightAnswer": "Winston Churchill",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Literature",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 567,
                "questionText": "The jellyfish consists of how much water?",
                "choice1": 0,
                "choice2": 0,
                "choice3": 0,
                "choice4": 0,
                "rightAnswer": 0,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 568,
                "questionText": "How many moons does Earth have?",
                "choice1": 0,
                "choice2": 2,
                "choice3": 8,
                "choice4": 1,
                "rightAnswer": 1,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 569,
                "questionText": "How many atoms are there in a molecule of water?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 1,
                "choice3": 4,
                "choice4": 2,
                "rightAnswer": 3,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 570,
                "questionText": "Cows have how many stomachs?",
                "choice1": 2,
                "choice2": 1,
                "choice3": 4,
                "choice4": 3,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 571,
                "questionText": "How many wisdom teeth does the average adult have?",
                "choice1": 4,
                "choice2": 8,
                "choice3": 6,
                "choice4": 2,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 572,
                "questionText": "The octal numbering system consistes of how many digits?",
                "choice1": 2,
                "choice2": 6,
                "choice3": 4,
                "choice4": 8,
                "rightAnswer": 8,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 573,
                "questionText": "How many legs does a spider have?",
                "choice1": 8,
                "choice2": 6,
                "choice3": 10,
                "choice4": 12,
                "rightAnswer": 8,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 574,
                "questionText": "How many sides does a Nonogon have?",
                "choice1": 99,
                "choice2": 9,
                "choice3": 19,
                "choice4": 0,
                "rightAnswer": 9,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 575,
                "questionText": "In which year did Pfizer Inc introduce it's Viagra drug to the market?",
                "choice1": 1987,
                "choice2": 1977,
                "choice3": 2007,
                "choice4": 1997,
                "rightAnswer": 1997,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 576,
                "questionText": "The binary system of numbers uses which two digits?",
                "choice1": "1 and 10",
                "choice2": "1 and 0",
                "choice3": "1 and 2",
                "choice4": "10 and 100",
                "rightAnswer": "1 and 0",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 577,
                "questionText": "How many millimetres are there in one inch?",
                "choice1": "25.4 mm",
                "choice2": "250.4 mm",
                "choice3": "10.4 mm",
                "choice4": "100.4 mm",
                "rightAnswer": "25.4 mm",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 578,
                "questionText": "Which scientist was born in Germany in 1879, became a Swiss citizen in 1901 and later became a US citizen in 1940?",
                "choice1": "Max Planck",
                "choice2": "Niels Bohr",
                "choice3": "Albert Einstein",
                "choice4": "Ludwig Boltzmann",
                "rightAnswer": "Albert Einstein",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 579,
                "questionText": "What lives in a Formicarium?",
                "choice1": "Apes",
                "choice2": "Ants",
                "choice3": "Turtles",
                "choice4": "Butterflies",
                "rightAnswer": "Ants",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 580,
                "questionText": "What is removed during an appendectomy?",
                "choice1": "Tonsils",
                "choice2": "Kidney",
                "choice3": "Appendix",
                "choice4": "Bone Marrow",
                "rightAnswer": "Appendix",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 581,
                "questionText": "Who first argued that the world was not flat? ",
                "choice1": "Magellan",
                "choice2": "Columbus",
                "choice3": "Aristotle",
                "choice4": "Archimedes",
                "rightAnswer": "Aristotle",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 582,
                "questionText": "Where did the dingo originate?",
                "choice1": "Australia",
                "choice2": "Europe",
                "choice3": "Africa",
                "choice4": "Asia",
                "rightAnswer": "Australia",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 583,
                "questionText": "Which of the following colours would make you appear the slimest?\u00a0",
                "choice1": "White",
                "choice2": "Black",
                "choice3": "Orange",
                "choice4": "Pink",
                "rightAnswer": "Black",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 584,
                "questionText": "What is classified by the A B O system?",
                "choice1": "Genetics",
                "choice2": "Fingerprints",
                "choice3": "Blood",
                "choice4": "Skin Colour",
                "rightAnswer": "Blood",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 585,
                "questionText": "What is the loudest animal on earth?",
                "choice1": "Cricket",
                "choice2": "Human",
                "choice3": "Howler monkey",
                "choice4": "Blue whale",
                "rightAnswer": "Blue whale",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 586,
                "questionText": "What is the name of the small tracking file left by websites on your computer?",
                "choice1": "Spider",
                "choice2": "Cookie",
                "choice3": "Worm",
                "choice4": "Trojan",
                "rightAnswer": "Cookie",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 587,
                "questionText": "What can't a Giraffe do?",
                "choice1": "sleep",
                "choice2": "run",
                "choice3": "hear",
                "choice4": "cough",
                "rightAnswer": "cough",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 588,
                "questionText": "An Aberdeen Angus is a type of what?",
                "choice1": "Plant",
                "choice2": "Pig",
                "choice3": "Cow",
                "choice4": "Dog",
                "rightAnswer": "Cow",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 589,
                "questionText": "What is the chemical symbol for Chromium?",
                "choice1": "Ch",
                "choice2": "Cm",
                "choice3": "Cr",
                "choice4": "Kr",
                "rightAnswer": "Cr",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 590,
                "questionText": "What was the name of the supercomputer that defeated chess master Garri Kasparov in 1997?",
                "choice1": "Deep Blue",
                "choice2": "Deep Waters",
                "choice3": "Deep Thought",
                "choice4": "Deep End",
                "rightAnswer": "Deep Blue",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 591,
                "questionText": "Which of the following animals is believed to be the first to be domesticated?",
                "choice1": "Dog",
                "choice2": "Rabbit",
                "choice3": "Cat",
                "choice4": "Cow",
                "rightAnswer": "Dog",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 592,
                "questionText": "What does a Joule unit measure?",
                "choice1": "Work",
                "choice2": "Light",
                "choice3": "Energy",
                "choice4": "Pressure",
                "rightAnswer": "Energy",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 593,
                "questionText": "A tortoiseshell cat is most likely what?",
                "choice1": "Deaf",
                "choice2": "Male",
                "choice3": "Blind",
                "choice4": "Female",
                "rightAnswer": "Female",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 594,
                "questionText": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?",
                "choice1": "Thunder",
                "choice2": "Skyscrapers",
                "choice3": "Fire",
                "choice4": "Plastic",
                "rightAnswer": "Fire",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 595,
                "questionText": "According to Newton, mass times acceleration is equal to what?",
                "choice1": "Force",
                "choice2": "Torque",
                "choice3": "Power",
                "choice4": "Velocity",
                "rightAnswer": "Force",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 596,
                "questionText": "What does a Hertz unit measure?",
                "choice1": "Frequency",
                "choice2": "Energy",
                "choice3": "Pressure\u00a0",
                "choice4": "Radioactivity",
                "rightAnswer": "Frequency",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 597,
                "questionText": "If you had rubella what would you have caught?",
                "choice1": "Mumps",
                "choice2": "Whooping cough",
                "choice3": "German measles",
                "choice4": "Chicken Pox",
                "rightAnswer": "German measles",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 598,
                "questionText": "Which country introduced the worlds first diesel locomotive in 1912?",
                "choice1": "Germany",
                "choice2": "United Kingdom",
                "choice3": "France",
                "choice4": "Unites States",
                "rightAnswer": "Germany",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 599,
                "questionText": "Which of the following is a metal that will not rust?",
                "choice1": "Silver",
                "choice2": "Nickel",
                "choice3": "Zinc",
                "choice4": "Gold",
                "rightAnswer": "Gold",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 600,
                "questionText": "Alopecia describes a person with a lack of what?",
                "choice1": "Memory",
                "choice2": "Red blood cells",
                "choice3": "Hair",
                "choice4": "teeth",
                "rightAnswer": "Hair",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 601,
                "questionText": "Christopher Cockerel invented what?",
                "choice1": "Catamaran  ",
                "choice2": "Hovercraft",
                "choice3": "Cats Eyes on the road",
                "choice4": "Helecopter",
                "rightAnswer": "Hovercraft",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 602,
                "questionText": "Which is the largest planet in our solar system?",
                "choice1": "Jupiter",
                "choice2": "Earth",
                "choice3": "Saturn",
                "choice4": "Uranus",
                "rightAnswer": "Jupiter",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 603,
                "questionText": "Where in your body is your patella?",
                "choice1": "Elbow",
                "choice2": "Knee",
                "choice3": "Foot",
                "choice4": "Neck",
                "rightAnswer": "Knee",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 604,
                "questionText": "Where in the body is the Patella?",
                "choice1": "Knee",
                "choice2": "Skull",
                "choice3": "Hip",
                "choice4": "Shoulder",
                "rightAnswer": "Knee",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 605,
                "questionText": "Which of the following metals is in a liquid state at room temperature",
                "choice1": "Uranium",
                "choice2": "Sodium",
                "choice3": "Mercury",
                "choice4": "Tungsten",
                "rightAnswer": "Mercury",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 606,
                "questionText": "What is the chemical symbol for Sodium?",
                "choice1": "S",
                "choice2": "Na",
                "choice3": "N",
                "choice4": "So",
                "rightAnswer": "Na",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 607,
                "questionText": "Which is the most common gas in the atmosphere?",
                "choice1": "Nitrogen",
                "choice2": "Oxygen",
                "choice3": "Helium",
                "choice4": "Carbon Dioxide",
                "rightAnswer": "Nitrogen",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 608,
                "questionText": "What is the most common blood type in humans?",
                "choice1": "O",
                "choice2": "A-",
                "choice3": "A",
                "choice4": "A+",
                "rightAnswer": "O",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 609,
                "questionText": "What is not a primary colour?",
                "choice1": "orange",
                "choice2": "yellow",
                "choice3": "blue",
                "choice4": "red",
                "rightAnswer": "orange",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 610,
                "questionText": "What do botanists study?",
                "choice1": "Dentistry",
                "choice2": "Plants",
                "choice3": "Fossils",
                "choice4": "Biology",
                "rightAnswer": "Plants",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 611,
                "questionText": "K is the chemical symbol for which element?",
                "choice1": "Potassium",
                "choice2": "Carbon",
                "choice3": "Chromium",
                "choice4": "Sodium",
                "rightAnswer": "Potassium",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 612,
                "questionText": "What plant does the Colorado beetle attack?",
                "choice1": "Cabbage",
                "choice2": "Potato",
                "choice3": "Lettuce",
                "choice4": "Carrot",
                "rightAnswer": "Potato",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 613,
                "questionText": "Mammals of the Order Marsupialia have what unique feature?",
                "choice1": "Night vision",
                "choice2": "Webbed feet",
                "choice3": "Pouches",
                "choice4": "Powerful legs",
                "rightAnswer": "Pouches",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 614,
                "questionText": "What does a Pascal unit measure?",
                "choice1": "Pressure",
                "choice2": "Radioactivity",
                "choice3": "Light",
                "choice4": "Heat",
                "rightAnswer": "Pressure",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 615,
                "questionText": "Na is the chemical symbol for which element?",
                "choice1": "Neon",
                "choice2": "Potassium",
                "choice3": "Sodium",
                "choice4": "Nitrogen",
                "rightAnswer": "Sodium",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 616,
                "questionText": "With which name do we refer to a male cat?",
                "choice1": "Topcat",
                "choice2": "Tomcat",
                "choice3": "Fleabag",
                "choice4": "Bobcat",
                "rightAnswer": "Tomcat",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 617,
                "questionText": "John Logie Baird is credited with which invention?",
                "choice1": "TV",
                "choice2": "Gramaphone",
                "choice3": "Telephone",
                "choice4": "Radio",
                "rightAnswer": "TV",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 618,
                "questionText": "What is the hottest planet in our solar system?",
                "choice1": "Mercury",
                "choice2": "Venus",
                "choice3": "Mars",
                "choice4": "Earth",
                "rightAnswer": "Venus",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 619,
                "questionText": "Tim Berners-Lee is known as the inventor of what?",
                "choice1": "Email",
                "choice2": "Apple Computers",
                "choice3": "Computer Mouse",
                "choice4": "World Wide Web",
                "rightAnswer": "World Wide Web",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 620,
                "questionText": "Which plant gives absynthe its hallucinogenic properties?",
                "choice1": "mistletoe",
                "choice2": "holly",
                "choice3": "wormwood",
                "choice4": "juniper",
                "rightAnswer": "wormwood",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 621,
                "questionText": "Which temperature has the same value in degrees in both centigrade and Fahrenheit?",
                "choice1": -273,
                "choice2": 0,
                "choice3": 37,
                "choice4": -40,
                "rightAnswer": -40,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 622,
                "questionText": "How many moons does Venus have?",
                "choice1": 0,
                "choice2": 3,
                "choice3": 2,
                "choice4": 1,
                "rightAnswer": 0,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 623,
                "questionText": "What percentage of US dogs are overweight?",
                "choice1": 0,
                "choice2": 0,
                "choice3": 0,
                "choice4": 0,
                "rightAnswer": 0,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 624,
                "questionText": "How many feet in a fathom?",
                "choice1": 36,
                "choice2": 6,
                "choice3": 8,
                "choice4": 12,
                "rightAnswer": 6,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 625,
                "questionText": "In computing how many bits make one byte?",
                "choice1": 16,
                "choice2": 12,
                "choice3": 8,
                "choice4": 4,
                "rightAnswer": 8,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 626,
                "questionText": "How many arms does a squid have?",
                "choice1": 8,
                "choice2": 10,
                "choice3": 12,
                "choice4": 6,
                "rightAnswer": 10,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 627,
                "questionText": "How many sides does a dodecagon have?",
                "choice1": 10,
                "choice2": 22,
                "choice3": 12,
                "choice4": 20,
                "rightAnswer": 12,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 628,
                "questionText": "What was the number of the last Apollo mission?",
                "choice1": 14,
                "choice2": 13,
                "choice3": 29,
                "choice4": 17,
                "rightAnswer": 17,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 629,
                "questionText": "How many moons does Saturn have?",
                "choice1": 18,
                "choice2": 48,
                "choice3": 8,
                "choice4": 28,
                "rightAnswer": 18,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 630,
                "questionText": "On average, how many hours a day does a Koala bear spend sleeping?",
                "choice1": 22,
                "choice2": 8,
                "choice3": 12,
                "choice4": 2,
                "rightAnswer": 22,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 631,
                "questionText": "How many miles must one walk in order to burn off a pound of fat?",
                "choice1": 14,
                "choice2": 4,
                "choice3": 64,
                "choice4": 34,
                "rightAnswer": 34,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 632,
                "questionText": "According to Guinness what is the record number of children borne by one woman?",
                "choice1": 43,
                "choice2": 88,
                "choice3": 69,
                "choice4": 26,
                "rightAnswer": 69,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 633,
                "questionText": "How many nuclear power plants are there in the USA?",
                "choice1": 509,
                "choice2": 109,
                "choice3": 209,
                "choice4": 59,
                "rightAnswer": 109,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 634,
                "questionText": "How many chemical elements are there?",
                "choice1": 412,
                "choice2": 212,
                "choice3": 112,
                "choice4": 312,
                "rightAnswer": 112,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 635,
                "questionText": "How many litres are there in a barrel of oil?",
                "choice1": 59,
                "choice2": 189,
                "choice3": 159,
                "choice4": 29,
                "rightAnswer": 159,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 636,
                "questionText": "The first robot was introduced in which year?",
                "choice1": 1921,
                "choice2": 1941,
                "choice3": 1951,
                "choice4": 1891,
                "rightAnswer": 1921,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 637,
                "questionText": "The Bikini was a concept by Louis R\u00e9ard, but in which year?",
                "choice1": 1946,
                "choice2": 1906,
                "choice3": 1966,
                "choice4": 1926,
                "rightAnswer": 1946,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 638,
                "questionText": "The first working computer mouse was developed by Douglas Engelbart in which year?",
                "choice1": 1983,
                "choice2": 1973,
                "choice3": 1963,
                "choice4": 1993,
                "rightAnswer": 1963,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 639,
                "questionText": "The LCD or Liquid Crystal Display was first developed by James Fergason in which year?",
                "choice1": 1951,
                "choice2": 1971,
                "choice3": 1981,
                "choice4": 1961,
                "rightAnswer": 1971,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 640,
                "questionText": "The world's firsr pocket calculator was invented by the Sharp Corporation in which year?",
                "choice1": 1981,
                "choice2": 1961,
                "choice3": 1991,
                "choice4": 1971,
                "rightAnswer": 1971,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 641,
                "questionText": "In which year did Ern\u0151 Rubik invent the Rubik's cube?",
                "choice1": 1984,
                "choice2": 1964,
                "choice3": 1954,
                "choice4": 1974,
                "rightAnswer": 1974,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 642,
                "questionText": "The first Mobile phone was invented by Bell Labs in which year?",
                "choice1": 1987,
                "choice2": 1982,
                "choice3": 1972,
                "choice4": 1977,
                "rightAnswer": 1977,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 643,
                "questionText": "The Compact Disc was first developed by Philips Electronics and Sony Corp and released in which year?",
                "choice1": 1980,
                "choice2": 1975,
                "choice3": 1985,
                "choice4": 1990,
                "rightAnswer": 1980,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 644,
                "questionText": "DNA fingerprinting was first explained to the world by Alec Jeffreys in which year?",
                "choice1": 1985,
                "choice2": 1965,
                "choice3": 1995,
                "choice4": 1975,
                "rightAnswer": 1985,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 645,
                "questionText": "In which year was the satellite Galileo launched?",
                "choice1": 1969,
                "choice2": 1999,
                "choice3": 1989,
                "choice4": 1979,
                "rightAnswer": 1989,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 646,
                "questionText": "In which year did Tim Berners-Lee introduce the phrase World Wide Web?",
                "choice1": 1990,
                "choice2": 1995,
                "choice3": 1985,
                "choice4": 1980,
                "rightAnswer": 1990,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 647,
                "questionText": "How many muscles are there in an elephants trunk?",
                "choice1": 400,
                "choice2": 4000,
                "choice3": 40,
                "choice4": 40000,
                "rightAnswer": 40000,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 648,
                "questionText": "How many feet long was the largest Blue Whale ever seen?",
                "choice1": "110 ft",
                "choice2": "210 ft",
                "choice3": "55 ft",
                "choice4": "550 ft",
                "rightAnswer": "110 ft",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 649,
                "questionText": "What speed can a human reach in free fall?",
                "choice1": "355 miles per hour",
                "choice2": "155 miles per\u00a0hr",
                "choice3": "55 miles per hour",
                "choice4": "225 miles per\u00a0hr",
                "rightAnswer": "155 miles per\u00a0hr",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 650,
                "questionText": "The first ballpoint pen was invented by Laszlo Biro in which decade?",
                "choice1": "1960s",
                "choice2": "1930s",
                "choice3": "1950s",
                "choice4": "1910s",
                "rightAnswer": "1930s",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 651,
                "questionText": "The world's first microwave oven was built and demonstrated by Percy Spencer in which decade?",
                "choice1": "1960s",
                "choice2": "1940s",
                "choice3": "1970s",
                "choice4": "1980s",
                "rightAnswer": "1940s",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 652,
                "questionText": "In which decade did the World Health Organisation declare Smallpox eradicated?",
                "choice1": "1970s",
                "choice2": "1950s",
                "choice3": "1960s",
                "choice4": "1980s",
                "rightAnswer": "1970s",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 653,
                "questionText": "What generation is the so-called EDGE technology?",
                "choice1": "3G",
                "choice2": "2.5G",
                "choice3": "2.75G",
                "choice4": "2G",
                "rightAnswer": "2.75G",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 654,
                "questionText": "On average, how long does a giraffe sleep each\u00a0day?",
                "choice1": "2 min",
                "choice2": "20 hours",
                "choice3": "20 min",
                "choice4": "2 hours",
                "rightAnswer": "20 min",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 655,
                "questionText": "How much taller is the Eiffel tower in the summertime?",
                "choice1": "0 inches",
                "choice2": "6 inches",
                "choice3": "6 feet",
                "choice4": "6 yards",
                "rightAnswer": "6 inches",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 656,
                "questionText": "What is the sum of the internal angles in a hexagon?",
                "choice1": "1080 degrees",
                "choice2": "360 degrees",
                "choice3": "540 degrees",
                "choice4": "720 degrees",
                "rightAnswer": "720 degrees",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 657,
                "questionText": "For how long is a dog pregnant?",
                "choice1": "9 Fortnights",
                "choice2": "9 Days",
                "choice3": "9 Months",
                "choice4": "9 Weeks",
                "rightAnswer": "9 Weeks",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 658,
                "questionText": "What are Lanthanides?",
                "choice1": "Bacterium",
                "choice2": "Mountains on Earth",
                "choice3": "A block of elements in the periodic table",
                "choice4": "Mountains on the Moon",
                "rightAnswer": "A block of elements in the periodic table",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 659,
                "questionText": "In which continent did the ostrich originate?",
                "choice1": "Asia",
                "choice2": "North America",
                "choice3": "Africa",
                "choice4": "Australia",
                "rightAnswer": "Africa",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 660,
                "questionText": "Which of the following insects requires no sleep?",
                "choice1": "Cockroach",
                "choice2": "Ant",
                "choice3": "Bee",
                "choice4": "Termite",
                "rightAnswer": "Ant",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 661,
                "questionText": "What part of the body does a turtle use to breathe?",
                "choice1": "Shell",
                "choice2": "Belly",
                "choice3": "Mouth",
                "choice4": "Anus",
                "rightAnswer": "Anus",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 662,
                "questionText": "What can you see with Kirlian photography?",
                "choice1": "atoms",
                "choice2": "blood cells",
                "choice3": "aura",
                "choice4": "bones",
                "rightAnswer": "aura",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 663,
                "questionText": "Animals of the Ursidae family are what?",
                "choice1": "Bears",
                "choice2": "Dogs",
                "choice3": "Apes",
                "choice4": "Horses",
                "rightAnswer": "Bears",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 664,
                "questionText": "What colour skin does a polar bear have?",
                "choice1": "White",
                "choice2": "Pink",
                "choice3": "Grey",
                "choice4": "Black",
                "rightAnswer": "Black",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 665,
                "questionText": "What is an Ishihara test used for? ",
                "choice1": "Deafness",
                "choice2": "Diabetes",
                "choice3": "Pregnancy",
                "choice4": "Blindness",
                "rightAnswer": "Blindness",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 666,
                "questionText": "Cats are born with which colour eyes?",
                "choice1": "Grey",
                "choice2": "Blue",
                "choice3": "Brown",
                "choice4": "Red",
                "rightAnswer": "Blue",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 667,
                "questionText": "What colour of tongue does the chow breed of dog have?",
                "choice1": "Blue",
                "choice2": "Black",
                "choice3": "Pink",
                "choice4": "Red",
                "rightAnswer": "Blue",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 668,
                "questionText": "What colour is lobster blood?",
                "choice1": "Red",
                "choice2": "Yellow",
                "choice3": "Clear",
                "choice4": "Blue",
                "rightAnswer": "Blue",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 669,
                "questionText": "What colour is octopus blood?",
                "choice1": "yellow",
                "choice2": "green",
                "choice3": "blue",
                "choice4": "red",
                "rightAnswer": "blue",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 670,
                "questionText": "What are bactrians and dromedaries?",
                "choice1": "Bears",
                "choice2": "Sloths",
                "choice3": "Elephants",
                "choice4": "Camels",
                "rightAnswer": "Camels",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 671,
                "questionText": "Which element is present in all organic compounds?",
                "choice1": "Californium",
                "choice2": "Calcium",
                "choice3": "Copper",
                "choice4": "Carbon",
                "rightAnswer": "Carbon",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 672,
                "questionText": "What type of animal is considered good luck to have living at a theatre?",
                "choice1": "Dog",
                "choice2": "Mouse",
                "choice3": "Bird",
                "choice4": "Cat",
                "rightAnswer": "Cat",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 673,
                "questionText": "A blue Orpington is a breed of which animal?",
                "choice1": "Horse",
                "choice2": "Cow",
                "choice3": "Cat",
                "choice4": "Chicken",
                "rightAnswer": "Chicken",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 674,
                "questionText": "Which of the following animals has the best memory?",
                "choice1": "Chimpanzee",
                "choice2": "Rhino",
                "choice3": "Donkey",
                "choice4": "Elephant",
                "rightAnswer": "Chimpanzee",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 675,
                "questionText": "What did John Harrison invent in 1757?",
                "choice1": "thermometer",
                "choice2": "taxi meter",
                "choice3": "chronometer",
                "choice4": "parking meter",
                "rightAnswer": "chronometer",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 676,
                "questionText": "What was not the name of a US space mission?",
                "choice1": "Magellan",
                "choice2": "Galileo",
                "choice3": "Cassini",
                "choice4": "Colombus",
                "rightAnswer": "Colombus",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 677,
                "questionText": "Which\u00a0beetle loves potatoes?",
                "choice1": "Utah",
                "choice2": "Florida",
                "choice3": "Colorado",
                "choice4": "Oregon",
                "rightAnswer": "Colorado",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 678,
                "questionText": "What did Douglas Engelbart invent in 1963?",
                "choice1": "Mobile Phone",
                "choice2": "Email",
                "choice3": "Pocket Calculator",
                "choice4": "Computer Mouse",
                "rightAnswer": "Computer Mouse",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 679,
                "questionText": "What makes up 99.9% of the universe?",
                "choice1": "dark energy",
                "choice2": "quarks",
                "choice3": "H2O",
                "choice4": "stars",
                "rightAnswer": "dark energy",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 680,
                "questionText": "When cats have blue eyes they are also most likely what?",
                "choice1": "Male",
                "choice2": "Female",
                "choice3": "Blind",
                "choice4": "Deaf",
                "rightAnswer": "Deaf",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 681,
                "questionText": "A wapiti is a what?",
                "choice1": "Bat",
                "choice2": "Monkey",
                "choice3": "Rat",
                "choice4": "Deer",
                "rightAnswer": "Deer",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 682,
                "questionText": "What kind of animal is a Lurcher?",
                "choice1": "Dog",
                "choice2": "Fish",
                "choice3": "Bird",
                "choice4": "Reptile",
                "rightAnswer": "Dog",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 683,
                "questionText": "Cynophobia is the fear of what?",
                "choice1": "Spiders",
                "choice2": "China",
                "choice3": "Dogs",
                "choice4": "The Dark",
                "rightAnswer": "Dogs",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 684,
                "questionText": "Which of the following insects can fly at a speed of around 60 mph?",
                "choice1": "Mosquito",
                "choice2": "Bee",
                "choice3": "Dragonfly",
                "choice4": "Hornet",
                "rightAnswer": "Dragonfly",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 685,
                "questionText": "Which of the following mammals cannot jump?",
                "choice1": "Rhino",
                "choice2": "Giraffe",
                "choice3": "Hippo",
                "choice4": "Elephant",
                "rightAnswer": "Elephant",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 686,
                "questionText": "What was the name of the first digital computer?",
                "choice1": "PONTIAC",
                "choice2": "ENIAC",
                "choice3": "NICKNACK",
                "choice4": "MANIAC",
                "rightAnswer": "ENIAC",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 687,
                "questionText": "Where in your body would you find the rods and cones?",
                "choice1": "Fingers",
                "choice2": "Eyes",
                "choice3": "Lungs",
                "choice4": "Ears",
                "rightAnswer": "Eyes",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 688,
                "questionText": "Which European country has the most nuclear power plants?",
                "choice1": "France",
                "choice2": "GB",
                "choice3": "Germany",
                "choice4": "Russia",
                "rightAnswer": "France",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 689,
                "questionText": "Which type of bomb was invented by Edward Teller and Stanislaw Ulam in 1952?",
                "choice1": "Napalm",
                "choice2": "Bouncing",
                "choice3": "Fusion",
                "choice4": "Fission",
                "rightAnswer": "Fusion",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 690,
                "questionText": "Who said \"nature abhors a vacuum\"?",
                "choice1": "Einstein",
                "choice2": "Aristotle",
                "choice3": "Newton",
                "choice4": "Galileo",
                "rightAnswer": "Galileo",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 691,
                "questionText": "Which European country has sent the most people into space?",
                "choice1": "Germany",
                "choice2": "Italy",
                "choice3": "Bulgaria",
                "choice4": "United Kingdom",
                "rightAnswer": "Germany",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 692,
                "questionText": "Where in Europe is the Barbary ape most likely found?",
                "choice1": "Greece",
                "choice2": "Portugal",
                "choice3": "Gibralta",
                "choice4": "Bulgaria",
                "rightAnswer": "Gibralta",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 693,
                "questionText": "Which of the following animals are not rodents?",
                "choice1": "Rats",
                "choice2": "Hedgehogs",
                "choice3": "Chipmunks",
                "choice4": "Gophers",
                "rightAnswer": "Hedgehogs",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 694,
                "questionText": "What does a 'Hippophagic' eat?",
                "choice1": "cat meat",
                "choice2": "horse meat",
                "choice3": "dog meat",
                "choice4": "whale meat",
                "rightAnswer": "horse meat",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 695,
                "questionText": "Ir is the chemical symbol for which element?",
                "choice1": "Iridium",
                "choice2": "Iron",
                "choice3": "Iodine",
                "choice4": "Iritum",
                "rightAnswer": "Iridium",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 696,
                "questionText": "What is a bird\u2019s \u2018gizzard\u2019?",
                "choice1": "It's distinctive colour",
                "choice2": "It\u2019s second stomach",
                "choice3": "It's tail feather",
                "choice4": "It's beak",
                "rightAnswer": "It\u2019s second stomach",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 697,
                "questionText": "What is the chemical symbol for Potassium?",
                "choice1": "P",
                "choice2": "Ka",
                "choice3": "Po",
                "choice4": "K",
                "rightAnswer": "K",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 698,
                "questionText": "What are young squirrels called?",
                "choice1": "Pups",
                "choice2": "Kids",
                "choice3": "Kittens",
                "choice4": "Ankle biters",
                "rightAnswer": "Kittens",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 699,
                "questionText": "What are baby beavers called?",
                "choice1": "Pups",
                "choice2": "Kittens",
                "choice3": "Cubs",
                "choice4": "Pests",
                "rightAnswer": "Kittens",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 700,
                "questionText": "Mg is the chemical symbol for which element?",
                "choice1": "Tungsten",
                "choice2": "Manganese",
                "choice3": "Magnesium",
                "choice4": "Molybdenum",
                "rightAnswer": "Magnesium",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 701,
                "questionText": "Mn is the chemical symbol for which element?",
                "choice1": "Molybdenum",
                "choice2": "Magnesium",
                "choice3": "Tungsten",
                "choice4": "Manganese",
                "rightAnswer": "Manganese",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 702,
                "questionText": "What is the scientific name for laughing gas?",
                "choice1": "Carbon dioxide",
                "choice2": "Sulphur dioxide",
                "choice3": "Nitrous oxide",
                "choice4": "Nitrous dioxide",
                "rightAnswer": "Nitrous oxide",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 703,
                "questionText": "What colour is an aircraft's black box?",
                "choice1": "Red",
                "choice2": "Black",
                "choice3": "White",
                "choice4": "Orange",
                "rightAnswer": "Orange",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 704,
                "questionText": "With which name do we refer to a female cat?",
                "choice1": "Doe",
                "choice2": "Kitty",
                "choice3": "Queen",
                "choice4": "Bitch",
                "rightAnswer": "Queen",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 705,
                "questionText": "What does a Becquerel unit measure?",
                "choice1": "Radioactivity",
                "choice2": "Energy",
                "choice3": "Frequency",
                "choice4": "Pressure",
                "rightAnswer": "Radioactivity",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 706,
                "questionText": "Which of the following animals can last the longest without water?",
                "choice1": "Human",
                "choice2": "Camel",
                "choice3": "Rat",
                "choice4": "Goat",
                "rightAnswer": "Rat",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 707,
                "questionText": "The common cold is what kind of virus?",
                "choice1": "Avian",
                "choice2": "Rhino",
                "choice3": "Pisces",
                "choice4": "Leo",
                "rightAnswer": "Rhino",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 708,
                "questionText": "What is the chemical symbol for Antimony?",
                "choice1": "Sb",
                "choice2": "Sn",
                "choice3": "Ti",
                "choice4": "T",
                "rightAnswer": "Sb",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 709,
                "questionText": "Which of the following is a theory in physics?",
                "choice1": "Schrodinger's Rat",
                "choice2": "Schrodinger's Bat",
                "choice3": "Schrodinger's Hat",
                "choice4": "Schrodinger's Cat",
                "rightAnswer": "Schrodinger's Cat",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 710,
                "questionText": "What was not the name of a US space mission?",
                "choice1": "Scout",
                "choice2": "Pioneer",
                "choice3": "Mariner",
                "choice4": "Ranger",
                "rightAnswer": "Scout",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 711,
                "questionText": "What did Otto Frederick Rohwedder invent in 1928 that changed the world forever?",
                "choice1": "RADAR",
                "choice2": "The television",
                "choice3": "The refrigerator",
                "choice4": "Sliced bread",
                "rightAnswer": "Sliced bread",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 712,
                "questionText": "What does an OLF unit measure?",
                "choice1": "taste",
                "choice2": "heat",
                "choice3": "light\u00a0",
                "choice4": "smell",
                "rightAnswer": "smell",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 713,
                "questionText": "What is the chemical symbol for Tin?",
                "choice1": "Ti",
                "choice2": "Sb",
                "choice3": "T",
                "choice4": "Sn",
                "rightAnswer": "Sn",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 714,
                "questionText": "On the Mohs scale the hardest substance is diamond - what's the softest?",
                "choice1": "Talcum Powder",
                "choice2": "Wheat Flour",
                "choice3": "Skin dust",
                "choice4": "Sugar",
                "rightAnswer": "Talcum Powder",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 715,
                "questionText": "What is the chemical symbol for Titanium?",
                "choice1": "Sn",
                "choice2": "Sb",
                "choice3": "T",
                "choice4": "Ti",
                "rightAnswer": "Ti",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 716,
                "questionText": "Ti is the chemical symbol for which element?",
                "choice1": "Tin",
                "choice2": "Thorium",
                "choice3": "Thulium",
                "choice4": "Titanium",
                "rightAnswer": "Titanium",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 717,
                "questionText": "Which part of the human body contains the most gold?",
                "choice1": "Hair",
                "choice2": "Toenails",
                "choice3": "Fingernails",
                "choice4": "Skin",
                "rightAnswer": "Toenails",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 718,
                "questionText": "W is the chemical symbol for which element?",
                "choice1": "Tungsten",
                "choice2": "Molybdenum",
                "choice3": "Magnesium",
                "choice4": "Manganese",
                "rightAnswer": "Tungsten",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 719,
                "questionText": "Which planet in the Solar System is closest in size to Earth? ",
                "choice1": "Uranus",
                "choice2": "Mercury",
                "choice3": "Mars",
                "choice4": "Venus",
                "rightAnswer": "Venus",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 720,
                "questionText": "What was the name of Jurij Gagarin's space capsule?",
                "choice1": "MIR",
                "choice2": "Sojus II",
                "choice3": "Vostok I",
                "choice4": "Sputnik I",
                "rightAnswer": "Vostok I",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 721,
                "questionText": "Ergasiophobia is the fear of what?",
                "choice1": "Flatulence",
                "choice2": "Odour",
                "choice3": "Work",
                "choice4": "Belching",
                "rightAnswer": "Work",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 722,
                "questionText": "Which plant gives absinthe its hallucinogenic properties?",
                "choice1": "agara",
                "choice2": "belladonna",
                "choice3": "wormwood",
                "choice4": "mandrake",
                "rightAnswer": "wormwood",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 723,
                "questionText": "What kind of star is our sun?",
                "choice1": "White Dwarf",
                "choice2": "Brown Dwarf",
                "choice3": "Yellow Dwarf",
                "choice4": "Red Giant",
                "rightAnswer": "Yellow Dwarf",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 724,
                "questionText": "How many stomachs does a moth have?",
                "choice1": 32,
                "choice2": 0,
                "choice3": 1,
                "choice4": 102,
                "rightAnswer": 0,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 725,
                "questionText": "Which percentage of the worlds population has an\u00a0I.Q. of 120 or more ?",
                "choice1": 0,
                "choice2": 0,
                "choice3": 0,
                "choice4": 0,
                "rightAnswer": 0,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 726,
                "questionText": "How many hearts does an earthworm have?",
                "choice1": 250,
                "choice2": 1,
                "choice3": 5,
                "choice4": 0,
                "rightAnswer": 5,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 727,
                "questionText": "How many 'arms' does a snowflake have?",
                "choice1": 6,
                "choice2": 9,
                "choice3": 8,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 6,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 728,
                "questionText": "How many minutes does it take rays from the sun to reach the earth",
                "choice1": 10,
                "choice2": 6,
                "choice3": 8,
                "choice4": 12,
                "rightAnswer": 8,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 729,
                "questionText": "How many people have walked on the moon? ",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 9,
                "choice3": 12,
                "choice4": 6,
                "rightAnswer": 12,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 730,
                "questionText": "How many inches to a cubit?",
                "choice1": 12,
                "choice2": 21,
                "choice3": 18,
                "choice4": 16,
                "rightAnswer": 18,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 731,
                "questionText": "How many brains does a leech have?",
                "choice1": 1,
                "choice2": 32,
                "choice3": 102,
                "choice4": 0,
                "rightAnswer": 32,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 732,
                "questionText": "How many gallons of water can a camel drink in 10 minutes?",
                "choice1": 35,
                "choice2": 25,
                "choice3": 5,
                "choice4": 15,
                "rightAnswer": 35,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 733,
                "questionText": "How many muscles does it take to move your hand?",
                "choice1": 15,
                "choice2": 5,
                "choice3": 35,
                "choice4": 65,
                "rightAnswer": 35,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 734,
                "questionText": "How many cubic feet are there in three cubic yards?",
                "choice1": 9,
                "choice2": 27,
                "choice3": 144,
                "choice4": 81,
                "rightAnswer": 81,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 735,
                "questionText": "How many years is 1,000,000 hours?",
                "choice1": 111,
                "choice2": 214,
                "choice3": 211,
                "choice4": 114,
                "rightAnswer": 114,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 736,
                "questionText": "How many sq metres was ENIAC, the worlds first electronic computer?",
                "choice1": 70,
                "choice2": 170,
                "choice3": 7,
                "choice4": 770,
                "rightAnswer": 170,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 737,
                "questionText": "In which year was the ball point pen introduced?",
                "choice1": 1958,
                "choice2": 1888,
                "choice3": 1938,
                "choice4": 1908,
                "rightAnswer": 1938,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 738,
                "questionText": "Ray Tomlinson sent the world's first email in which year?",
                "choice1": 1971,
                "choice2": 1981,
                "choice3": 2001,
                "choice4": 1991,
                "rightAnswer": 1971,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 739,
                "questionText": "In which year was the first black tulip cultivated?",
                "choice1": 2006,
                "choice2": 1896,
                "choice3": 1926,
                "choice4": 1986,
                "rightAnswer": 1986,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 740,
                "questionText": "How many hairs does the average human head have?",
                "choice1": 100000,
                "choice2": 1000,
                "choice3": 10000,
                "choice4": 1000000,
                "rightAnswer": 100000,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 741,
                "questionText": "Roughly how many glasses of milk can one cow produce in one year?",
                "choice1": 20000,
                "choice2": 120000,
                "choice3": 520000,
                "choice4": 720000,
                "rightAnswer": 120000,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 742,
                "questionText": "What was the highest ever\u00a0recorded temperature in the Libyan desert?",
                "choice1": "236 degrees Fahrenheit",
                "choice2": "136 degrees Fahrenheit",
                "choice3": "156 degrees Fahrenheit",
                "choice4": "180 degrees Fahrenheit",
                "rightAnswer": "136 degrees Fahrenheit",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 743,
                "questionText": "What is the speed of light?",
                "choice1": "286,272 miles per second",
                "choice2": "1,188 ,272 miles per second",
                "choice3": "186,272 miles per second",
                "choice4": "84,272 miles per second",
                "rightAnswer": "186,272 miles per second",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 744,
                "questionText": "In 1776 what was the average height of an Englishman?",
                "choice1": "6\u00a0foot",
                "choice2": "5 ft 4 inches",
                "choice3": "5 ft 1 inch",
                "choice4": "5 ft 7 inches",
                "rightAnswer": "5 ft 7 inches",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 745,
                "questionText": "How long does the light from the sun take to reach the earth?",
                "choice1": "8.5 days",
                "choice2": "8.5 min",
                "choice3": "8.5 sec",
                "choice4": "8.5\u00a0hours",
                "rightAnswer": "8.5 min",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 746,
                "questionText": "Bamboo plants can grow how many cm per day?",
                "choice1": "170cm",
                "choice2": "90cm",
                "choice3": "30cm",
                "choice4": "10cm",
                "rightAnswer": "90cm",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 747,
                "questionText": "What is the most common blood group in Europe?",
                "choice1": "A +",
                "choice2": "A -",
                "choice3": "B +",
                "choice4": "O -",
                "rightAnswer": "A +",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 748,
                "questionText": "What does a nidoligist study?",
                "choice1": "Bird Nests",
                "choice2": "Clouds",
                "choice3": "Waves",
                "choice4": "Caves",
                "rightAnswer": "Bird Nests",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 749,
                "questionText": "Which of these elements is the heaviest?",
                "choice1": "Sodium",
                "choice2": "Potassium",
                "choice3": "Rubidium",
                "choice4": "Caesium",
                "rightAnswer": "Caesium",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 750,
                "questionText": "How many earths would fit inside the sun?",
                "choice1": "circa 1,000",
                "choice2": "circa 100,000",
                "choice3": "circa 1,000,000",
                "choice4": "circa 10,000",
                "rightAnswer": "circa 1,000,000",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 751,
                "questionText": "Hypermetropic people are what?",
                "choice1": "moody",
                "choice2": "underfed",
                "choice3": "obese",
                "choice4": "far sighted",
                "rightAnswer": "far sighted",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 752,
                "questionText": "Fredrick Sanger invented which life saver?",
                "choice1": "Aspirin",
                "choice2": "Insulin",
                "choice3": "Safety Pin",
                "choice4": "Inflatable Life Raft",
                "rightAnswer": "Insulin",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 753,
                "questionText": "Which of the following is a bird AND a fruit?",
                "choice1": "Juju",
                "choice2": "Kiwi",
                "choice3": "Pear",
                "choice4": "Mango",
                "rightAnswer": "Kiwi",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 754,
                "questionText": "Which planet has the tallest mountain?",
                "choice1": "Earth",
                "choice2": "Mars",
                "choice3": "Jupiter",
                "choice4": "Venus",
                "rightAnswer": "Mars",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 755,
                "questionText": "What does the medical term dolent mean?",
                "choice1": "internal",
                "choice2": "numb",
                "choice3": "pain",
                "choice4": "fever",
                "rightAnswer": "pain",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 756,
                "questionText": "Which of these is a name of a fish?",
                "choice1": "Boleyn",
                "choice2": "Aragon",
                "choice3": "Seymour",
                "choice4": "Parr",
                "rightAnswer": "Parr",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 757,
                "questionText": "What is the only food a cockroach wont eat?",
                "choice1": "snail",
                "choice2": "porridge",
                "choice3": "pickle",
                "choice4": "marshmellow",
                "rightAnswer": "pickle",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 758,
                "questionText": "What won't a cockroach eat?",
                "choice1": "curry",
                "choice2": "pickles",
                "choice3": "marmite",
                "choice4": "porridge",
                "rightAnswer": "pickles",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 759,
                "questionText": "Which planet has the most eccentric orbit?",
                "choice1": "Venus",
                "choice2": "Pluto",
                "choice3": "Earth",
                "choice4": "Mercury",
                "rightAnswer": "Pluto",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 760,
                "questionText": "What is a Flemish Giant?",
                "choice1": "Rabbit",
                "choice2": "Star",
                "choice3": "Mountain",
                "choice4": "Sprout",
                "rightAnswer": "Rabbit",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 761,
                "questionText": "A 'bind' is a group of what?",
                "choice1": "cobras",
                "choice2": "salmon",
                "choice3": "crows",
                "choice4": "zebras",
                "rightAnswer": "salmon",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 762,
                "questionText": "Which planet has the most moons?",
                "choice1": "Jupiter",
                "choice2": "Neptune",
                "choice3": "Uranus",
                "choice4": "Saturn",
                "rightAnswer": "Saturn",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 763,
                "questionText": "Which bird has a record 25,000 feathers?",
                "choice1": "Stork",
                "choice2": "Swan",
                "choice3": "Albatross",
                "choice4": "Goose",
                "rightAnswer": "Swan",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 764,
                "questionText": "Somatology is the study of what?",
                "choice1": "The Cosmos",
                "choice2": "The Body",
                "choice3": "Somalia",
                "choice4": "Insects",
                "rightAnswer": "The Body",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 765,
                "questionText": "Who invented the sub-machine gun in 1920?",
                "choice1": "Colt",
                "choice2": "Thompson",
                "choice3": "Winchester",
                "choice4": "Gattling",
                "rightAnswer": "Thompson",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 766,
                "questionText": "Brontophobia is the fear of what?",
                "choice1": "Thunder",
                "choice2": "The Dark",
                "choice3": "Elephants",
                "choice4": "Skyscrapers",
                "rightAnswer": "Thunder",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 767,
                "questionText": "Which VW auto was not named after a wind?",
                "choice1": "Bora",
                "choice2": "Touran",
                "choice3": "Passat",
                "choice4": "Scirocco",
                "rightAnswer": "Touran",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 768,
                "questionText": "A Blue Whale has a heart roughly the size of a what?",
                "choice1": "VW Beetle",
                "choice2": "Basketball",
                "choice3": "Peanut",
                "choice4": "Grapefruit",
                "rightAnswer": "VW Beetle",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 769,
                "questionText": "Anemophobia is the fear of what?",
                "choice1": "Fire",
                "choice2": "The Dark",
                "choice3": "Spiders",
                "choice4": "Wind",
                "rightAnswer": "Wind",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 770,
                "questionText": "What is the more usual name for Roentgen Rays?",
                "choice1": "Magnetic Resonance",
                "choice2": "Ultra Violet Rays",
                "choice3": "X Rays",
                "choice4": "Gamma Rays",
                "rightAnswer": "X Rays",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Science",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 771,
                "questionText": "How many holes are there on a ten pin bowling ball?",
                "choice1": 2,
                "choice2": 5,
                "choice3": 4,
                "choice4": 3,
                "rightAnswer": 3,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 772,
                "questionText": "How many rings on the Olympic flag?",
                "choice1": 4,
                "choice2": 6,
                "choice3": 7,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 5,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 773,
                "questionText": "How many Olympic gold medals did mark Spitz win in Munich in 1972?",
                "choice1": 7,
                "choice2": 8,
                "choice3": 6,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 7,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 774,
                "questionText": "How many lanes does an Olympic swimming pool have?",
                "choice1": 10,
                "choice2": 12,
                "choice3": 6,
                "choice4": 8,
                "rightAnswer": 8,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 775,
                "questionText": "How many rounds are there in a professional boxing title contest?",
                "choice1": 8,
                "choice2": 10,
                "choice3": 12,
                "choice4": 20,
                "rightAnswer": 12,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 776,
                "questionText": "In badminton, how many points win a single game?",
                "choice1": 15,
                "choice2": 19,
                "choice3": 20,
                "choice4": 10,
                "rightAnswer": 15,
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 777,
                "questionText": "Which 1982 World Cup team featured the talents of Zico, Socrates and Falcao?",
                "choice1": "Spain",
                "choice2": "Brazil",
                "choice3": "Argentina",
                "choice4": "Italy",
                "rightAnswer": "Brazil",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 778,
                "questionText": "Which swimming stroke was not introduced to the Olympics until 1956?",
                "choice1": "Freestyle",
                "choice2": "Butterfly",
                "choice3": "Breaststroke",
                "choice4": "Doggy Style",
                "rightAnswer": "Butterfly",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 779,
                "questionText": "Which country has Zinedine Zidane played for?",
                "choice1": "France",
                "choice2": "Spain",
                "choice3": "Italy",
                "choice4": "Brazil",
                "rightAnswer": "France",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 780,
                "questionText": "In tennis, what name is given to winning the four major tournaments in a season?",
                "choice1": "Outright",
                "choice2": "Major Slam",
                "choice3": "World Champion",
                "choice4": "Grand Slam",
                "rightAnswer": "Grand Slam",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 781,
                "questionText": "Which of these is another name for a golf course?",
                "choice1": "Pitch",
                "choice2": "Links",
                "choice3": "Steps",
                "choice4": "Suite",
                "rightAnswer": "Links",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 782,
                "questionText": "Which tennis players nickname was 'The Rocket'?",
                "choice1": "Fred Perry",
                "choice2": "John Newcombe",
                "choice3": "Rod Laver",
                "choice4": "Pete Sampras",
                "rightAnswer": "Rod Laver",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 783,
                "questionText": "Which sport is played in Roland Garros?",
                "choice1": "rugby",
                "choice2": "tennis",
                "choice3": "polo",
                "choice4": "football",
                "rightAnswer": "tennis",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 784,
                "questionText": "Which superstar was named 'The Great One'?",
                "choice1": "Rod Laver",
                "choice2": "Dixie Dean",
                "choice3": "Eddie Edwards",
                "choice4": "Wayne Gretsky",
                "rightAnswer": "Wayne Gretsky",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 785,
                "questionText": "What type of sportsman was the toy Stretch Armstrong dressed as?",
                "choice1": "Cricketer",
                "choice2": "Archer",
                "choice3": "Wrestler",
                "choice4": "Boxer",
                "rightAnswer": "Wrestler",
                "difficulty": 1,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 786,
                "questionText": "How many Gold Medals did Jesse Owens win in the 1936 Berlin Olympics? ",
                "choice1": 5,
                "choice2": 4,
                "choice3": 6,
                "choice4": 3,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 787,
                "questionText": "How many hulls are there on a Catamaran?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 4,
                "choice3": 2,
                "choice4": 1,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 788,
                "questionText": "How many balls are used in a game of croquet?",
                "choice1": 2,
                "choice2": 4,
                "choice3": 8,
                "choice4": 1,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 789,
                "questionText": "How many players are there in a polo team?",
                "choice1": 16,
                "choice2": 4,
                "choice3": 2,
                "choice4": 8,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 790,
                "questionText": "How many times did cyclist Miguel Indurain win the Tour de France in the 1990s?",
                "choice1": "None",
                "choice2": 5,
                "choice3": 2,
                "choice4": 9,
                "rightAnswer": 5,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 791,
                "questionText": "How many games make up a match in squash?",
                "choice1": 8,
                "choice2": 12,
                "choice3": 5,
                "choice4": 10,
                "rightAnswer": 5,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 792,
                "questionText": "How many players of an ice hockey team can be on the ice at the same time?",
                "choice1": 6,
                "choice2": 8,
                "choice3": 5,
                "choice4": 7,
                "rightAnswer": 6,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 793,
                "questionText": "How many disciplines make up the men\u2019s gymnastics competition at the Olympics?",
                "choice1": 4,
                "choice2": 6,
                "choice3": 10,
                "choice4": 8,
                "rightAnswer": 6,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 794,
                "questionText": "What is the minimum number of points needed to win a game of squash?",
                "choice1": 10,
                "choice2": 9,
                "choice3": 15,
                "choice4": 20,
                "rightAnswer": 9,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 795,
                "questionText": "How many players in a baseball team?",
                "choice1": 15,
                "choice2": 11,
                "choice3": 7,
                "choice4": 9,
                "rightAnswer": 9,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 796,
                "questionText": "What number shirt did Pele usually wear when playing for Brazil?",
                "choice1": 9,
                "choice2": 10,
                "choice3": 1,
                "choice4": 8,
                "rightAnswer": 10,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 797,
                "questionText": "How many players are there in a Hockey team?",
                "choice1": 11,
                "choice2": 15,
                "choice3": 10,
                "choice4": 9,
                "rightAnswer": 11,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 798,
                "questionText": "In American Football, how many players from one team are allowed on the grid at any one time?",
                "choice1": 12,
                "choice2": 15,
                "choice3": 11,
                "choice4": 10,
                "rightAnswer": 11,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 799,
                "questionText": "How many minutes of play are there in an American football match?",
                "choice1": 150,
                "choice2": 90,
                "choice3": 60,
                "choice4": 120,
                "rightAnswer": 60,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 800,
                "questionText": "In which year did tennis legend\u00a0'Rocket' Rod Laver win his last Grand Slam?",
                "choice1": 1977,
                "choice2": 1981,
                "choice3": 1958,
                "choice4": 1969,
                "rightAnswer": 1969,
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 801,
                "questionText": "Which city hosted the 1992 summer Olympic games?",
                "choice1": "Moscow",
                "choice2": "Barcelona",
                "choice3": "Atlanta",
                "choice4": "Seoul",
                "rightAnswer": "Barcelona",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 802,
                "questionText": "What did the dog named Pickles find?",
                "choice1": "F.A. Cup",
                "choice2": "Federation Cup",
                "choice3": "Davis Cup",
                "choice4": "Coupe Jules Rimet",
                "rightAnswer": "Coupe Jules Rimet",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 803,
                "questionText": "\"The ugliest salad bowl in the world\" is the nickname for which trophy?",
                "choice1": "Football World Cup",
                "choice2": "Davis Cup",
                "choice3": "F.A. Cup",
                "choice4": "Ryder Cup",
                "rightAnswer": "Davis Cup",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 804,
                "questionText": "Wayne Gretzky was a superstar in which sport?",
                "choice1": "golf",
                "choice2": "boxing",
                "choice3": "ice hochey",
                "choice4": "tennis",
                "rightAnswer": "ice hochey",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 805,
                "questionText": "Which tennis player has not lost four Wimbledon singles finals?",
                "choice1": "Boris Becker",
                "choice2": "Ken Rosewall",
                "choice3": "Jimmy Connors",
                "choice4": "Ivan Lendl",
                "rightAnswer": "Ivan Lendl",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 806,
                "questionText": "Who was the only tennis player to have won the US OPEN on three different surfaces?",
                "choice1": "Jimmy Conners\u00a0",
                "choice2": "Big Bill Tilden\u00a0\u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0",
                "choice3": "Roger Federer\u00a0",
                "choice4": "Andre Agassi",
                "rightAnswer": "Jimmy Conners\u00a0",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 807,
                "questionText": "Mika Hakkinen was Formula 1 champion in 1998 and 1999\u00a0in\u00a0which car?",
                "choice1": "Ferrari",
                "choice2": "Benetton Ford",
                "choice3": "Renault",
                "choice4": "McLaren-Mercedes",
                "rightAnswer": "McLaren-Mercedes",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 808,
                "questionText": "'El tri' is the nickname for which\u00a0national football team?\u00a0",
                "choice1": "Spain",
                "choice2": "Brazil",
                "choice3": "Mexico",
                "choice4": "Switzerland",
                "rightAnswer": "Mexico",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 809,
                "questionText": "Which summer Olympic Games were boycotted by most African countries?",
                "choice1": "Moscow 80",
                "choice2": "Munich 72",
                "choice3": "Montreal 76",
                "choice4": "USA 84",
                "rightAnswer": "Montreal 76",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 810,
                "questionText": "Jacky Ickx was a superstar in which sport?",
                "choice1": "motor racing",
                "choice2": "tennis",
                "choice3": "soccer",
                "choice4": "cycling",
                "rightAnswer": "motor racing",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 811,
                "questionText": "Every player\u00a0in the Bulgarian national team at the 1994\u00a0Football World Cup had a name ending in which letters?",
                "choice1": "ov",
                "choice2": "an",
                "choice3": "us",
                "choice4": "ki",
                "rightAnswer": "ov",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 812,
                "questionText": "Which country has won a record four World Championships in mens field hockey?",
                "choice1": "Germany",
                "choice2": "Ireland",
                "choice3": "Holland",
                "choice4": "Pakistan",
                "rightAnswer": "Pakistan",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 813,
                "questionText": "80% of all the footballs in the world are made in which country?",
                "choice1": "Pakistan",
                "choice2": "Australia",
                "choice3": "USA",
                "choice4": "Mexico",
                "rightAnswer": "Pakistan",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 814,
                "questionText": "Who was the last man to win the Grand Slam in tennis?",
                "choice1": "Rod Laver",
                "choice2": "Roger Federer",
                "choice3": "Ivan Lendl",
                "choice4": "Bjorn Borg",
                "rightAnswer": "Rod Laver",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 815,
                "questionText": "Which stadium is named after a WW I flying ace?",
                "choice1": "Bernabeu",
                "choice2": "Fratton Park",
                "choice3": "Roland Garros",
                "choice4": "Giuseppe Meazza",
                "rightAnswer": "Roland Garros",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 816,
                "questionText": "Which city saw Steffi Graf win Olympic gold?",
                "choice1": "Los Angeles",
                "choice2": "Seoul",
                "choice3": "Barcelona",
                "choice4": "Moscow",
                "rightAnswer": "Seoul",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 817,
                "questionText": "'Wedel' is a term in which sport?",
                "choice1": "Skiing",
                "choice2": "Chess",
                "choice3": "Formula One",
                "choice4": "Darts",
                "rightAnswer": "Skiing",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 818,
                "questionText": "In golf what name is given to the No 3 wood?",
                "choice1": "Ladel",
                "choice2": "Spoon",
                "choice3": "Knife",
                "choice4": "Fork",
                "rightAnswer": "Spoon",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 819,
                "questionText": "Which woman thrashed her opponent 6-0 6-0 in the 1988 French Open final?",
                "choice1": "Virginia Wade",
                "choice2": "Stefi Graf",
                "choice3": "Venus Williams",
                "choice4": "Billy Jean King",
                "rightAnswer": "Stefi Graf",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 820,
                "questionText": "What weighs 4lb 6oz at the Olympics?",
                "choice1": "The Olympic Torch",
                "choice2": "The Medals (Gold, Silver, Bronze)",
                "choice3": "The Discuss",
                "choice4": "The Javelin",
                "rightAnswer": "The Discuss",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 821,
                "questionText": "Which football world cup had the highest average attendance figures?",
                "choice1": "Italy 90",
                "choice2": "England 66",
                "choice3": "USA 94",
                "choice4": "Brazil 50",
                "rightAnswer": "USA 94",
                "difficulty": 2,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 822,
                "questionText": "If a golf hole is 130 yards long, what would its par be?",
                "choice1": 3,
                "choice2": 5,
                "choice3": 4,
                "choice4": 2,
                "rightAnswer": 3,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 823,
                "questionText": "How many laps are completed towin a speedway race?",
                "choice1": 6,
                "choice2": 10,
                "choice3": 5,
                "choice4": 4,
                "rightAnswer": 4,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 824,
                "questionText": "How many baseball gloves can be made with the leather from one cow?",
                "choice1": 25,
                "choice2": 1,
                "choice3": 55,
                "choice4": 5,
                "rightAnswer": 5,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 825,
                "questionText": "How old was Boris Becker when he won his first Wimbledon singles title?",
                "choice1": 17,
                "choice2": 16,
                "choice3": 15,
                "choice4": 18,
                "rightAnswer": 17,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 826,
                "questionText": "How many Wimbledon titles did Billie Jean King win?",
                "choice1": 10,
                "choice2": 30,
                "choice3": 5,
                "choice4": 20,
                "rightAnswer": 20,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 827,
                "questionText": "How many laps are run in a 10000-metre track race?",
                "choice1": 20,
                "choice2": 35,
                "choice3": 30,
                "choice4": 25,
                "rightAnswer": 25,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 828,
                "questionText": "In which year were the summer olympic games in Berlin?\u00a0",
                "choice1": 1932,
                "choice2": 1948,
                "choice3": 1942,
                "choice4": 1936,
                "rightAnswer": 1936,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 829,
                "questionText": "In which year were the summer\u00a0olympic games in Montreal?\u00a0",
                "choice1": 1974,
                "choice2": 1978,
                "choice3": 1976,
                "choice4": 1980,
                "rightAnswer": 1976,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 830,
                "questionText": "In which year were the summer olympic games in Moscow?",
                "choice1": 1976,
                "choice2": 1978,
                "choice3": 1982,
                "choice4": 1980,
                "rightAnswer": 1980,
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 831,
                "questionText": "Countries from which continent boycotted the 1976 summer olympics in Montreal?",
                "choice1": "Europe",
                "choice2": "Asia",
                "choice3": "South\u00a0 America",
                "choice4": "Africa",
                "rightAnswer": "Africa",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 832,
                "questionText": "Who was the first black woman to win both the US Open and Wimbledon?",
                "choice1": "Serena Williams",
                "choice2": "Shirley Fry",
                "choice3": "Althea Gibson",
                "choice4": "Venus Williams",
                "rightAnswer": "Althea Gibson",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            },
            {
                "questionId": 833,
                "questionText": "Who is not an accomplished fencer?",
                "choice1": "Arnold Schwarzenegger",
                "choice2": "Antonio Banderas",
                "choice3": "Gene Wilder",
                "choice4": "Elijah Wood",
                "rightAnswer": "Arnold Schwarzenegger",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 834,
                "questionText": "Which sport do the Minnesota Twins play?",
                "choice1": "Basketball",
                "choice2": "Ice Hiockey",
                "choice3": "Football",
                "choice4": "Baseball",
                "rightAnswer": "Baseball",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 835,
                "questionText": "Who was the first american to win the mens singles title at Wimbledon?",
                "choice1": "Bobby Riggs",
                "choice2": "Donald Budge",
                "choice3": "Jack Kramer",
                "choice4": "Big Bill Tilden",
                "rightAnswer": "Big Bill Tilden",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 836,
                "questionText": "Which NHL superstar had the nickname 'The Golden Jet'?",
                "choice1": "Stan Mikita",
                "choice2": "Gordie Howe",
                "choice3": "Bobby Orr",
                "choice4": "Bobby Hull",
                "rightAnswer": "Bobby Hull",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 837,
                "questionText": "Figure skating champion Elvis Stojko was from which country?",
                "choice1": "Canada",
                "choice2": "Bulgaria",
                "choice3": "USA",
                "choice4": "Russia",
                "rightAnswer": "Canada",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 838,
                "questionText": "Who was the captain of Brazil when they won the 1970 football world cup?",
                "choice1": "Socrates",
                "choice2": "Romario",
                "choice3": "Pele",
                "choice4": "Carlos Alberto",
                "rightAnswer": "Carlos Alberto",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 839,
                "questionText": "Eddy Merckx was a superstar in which sport?",
                "choice1": "soccer",
                "choice2": "tennis",
                "choice3": "baseball",
                "choice4": "cycling",
                "rightAnswer": "cycling",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 840,
                "questionText": "Who has a black belt in judo?",
                "choice1": "Bill Gates",
                "choice2": "David Lee Roth",
                "choice3": "Prince Charles",
                "choice4": "David Beckham",
                "rightAnswer": "David Lee Roth",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 841,
                "questionText": "Nine time Olympic gold medal winner Paavo Nurmi was from which country?",
                "choice1": "Finland",
                "choice2": "Hungary",
                "choice3": "India",
                "choice4": "Russia",
                "rightAnswer": "Finland",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 842,
                "questionText": "Juan Manuel Fangio was a superstar in which sport in the 1950s?",
                "choice1": "formula one",
                "choice2": "soccer",
                "choice3": "baseball",
                "choice4": "tennis",
                "rightAnswer": "formula one",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 843,
                "questionText": "In which sport does one compete for the Stanley Cup?",
                "choice1": "polo",
                "choice2": "golf",
                "choice3": "squash",
                "choice4": "ice hockey",
                "rightAnswer": "ice hockey",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 844,
                "questionText": "Which poem greets contestants to centre court Wimbledon?",
                "choice1": "If",
                "choice2": "A dream within a dream",
                "choice3": "All the worlds a stage",
                "choice4": "The road not taken",
                "rightAnswer": "If",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 845,
                "questionText": "Who does not have a black belt in karate?",
                "choice1": "Sharon Stone",
                "choice2": "Guy Ritchie",
                "choice3": "Chuck Norris",
                "choice4": "Jennifer Lopez",
                "rightAnswer": "Jennifer Lopez",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 846,
                "questionText": "What was the name of the mascot bear at the 1980 summer Olympic games in Moscow?",
                "choice1": "Mischa",
                "choice2": "Nikita",
                "choice3": "Igor",
                "choice4": "Olga",
                "rightAnswer": "Mischa",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 847,
                "questionText": "Which NHL hockey team has won the most Stanley Cups?",
                "choice1": "Montreal Canadiens",
                "choice2": "Toronto Maple Leafs",
                "choice3": "New York Rangers",
                "choice4": "Boston Bruins",
                "rightAnswer": "Montreal Canadiens",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 0
            },
            {
                "questionId": 848,
                "questionText": "At which Formula One circuit would one find the 'Lesmo Bend'?",
                "choice1": "Circuit Gilles Villeneuve",
                "choice2": "Monza",
                "choice3": "Silverstone",
                "choice4": "Hockenheimring",
                "rightAnswer": "Monza",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 849,
                "questionText": "Speed skating originated in which country?",
                "choice1": "Norway",
                "choice2": "Canada",
                "choice3": "Russia",
                "choice4": "Netherlands",
                "rightAnswer": "Netherlands",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 850,
                "questionText": "Which\u00a0professional\u00a0sport\u00a0awards the Lady Byng Memorial Trophy each year for the 'Most Gentlemanly Player'?",
                "choice1": "PGA",
                "choice2": "NFL",
                "choice3": "NBA",
                "choice4": "NHL",
                "rightAnswer": "NHL",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 851,
                "questionText": "'Nati' is the nickname for which countrys football team?",
                "choice1": "Mexico",
                "choice2": "Switzerland",
                "choice3": "Holland",
                "choice4": "South Korea",
                "rightAnswer": "Switzerland",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 1
            },
            {
                "questionId": 852,
                "questionText": "Gossima was the original name for which sport?",
                "choice1": "Snooker",
                "choice2": "Badminton",
                "choice3": "Lawn Tennis",
                "choice4": "Table Tennis",
                "rightAnswer": "Table Tennis",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 853,
                "questionText": "Lew Hoad was a superstar in which sport in the 1950s?",
                "choice1": "soccer",
                "choice2": "baseball",
                "choice3": "ice hockey",
                "choice4": "tennis",
                "rightAnswer": "tennis",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 854,
                "questionText": "A 'Miller' is a move in which sport?",
                "choice1": "Ice Hockey",
                "choice2": "Chess",
                "choice3": "Diving",
                "choice4": "Trampolining",
                "rightAnswer": "Trampolining",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 3
            },
            {
                "questionId": 855,
                "questionText": "Which superstar wore the number 99 ?",
                "choice1": "Sebastian Coe",
                "choice2": "Zidane",
                "choice3": "Wayne Gretzky",
                "choice4": "Dixie Dean",
                "rightAnswer": "Wayne Gretzky",
                "difficulty": 3,
                "category": "Sport",
                "rightAnswerIndex": 2
            }
        ]
    }
}